<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<nsx anno="" lt-id="131" min-sys-ver="1" rev="1093" ver="1.0">
	<spc anno="csxad=1&amp;adspace=9,10,11,12,13" id="33537" multi="o" rep="t">
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2026-1-31T12:15:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>qCFW - Arrives to Slim (2500-3000) & SuperSlim (4000-NOR) PlayStation 3 Models</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/qCFW_-_Arrives_to_Slim_(2500-3000)_&_SuperSlim_(4000-NOR)_PlayStation_3_Models.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/qcfw-arrives-to-slim-2500-3000-superslim-4000-nor-playstation-3-models.49533/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/qCFW_-_Arrives_to_Slim_(2500-3000)_&_SuperSlim_(4000-NOR)_PlayStation_3_Models.jpg">UPDATE (Feb. 20) -PS3HEN 3.4.2 Open Beta: Test #1 Released- (Forum Link)UPDATE (Feb. 20) -qCFW updated(forum link)   --qcfw-20260220-release(github link)UPDATE (Feb. 17) -qCFW and Future potential(Forum Thread)by@aomsin2526>here<UPDATE (Feb. 13) -BadWDSD/qCFW + HW Flasher/NoBT(Forum Thread)UPDATE (Feb. 11) -qCFW files have been temporary removed from github by the developer, due to a bug, see@aomsin2526's post >here<  & >also here<UPDATE (Feb. 3)-PS3HEN v3.4.1 (STABLE) has now been releasedby@esc0rtd3w, graduating from the 3.4.1 BETA builds. (Note: v3.4.1+ is required for qCFW)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-8-3T22:44:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>[BD-JB-1250] New Exploit (bluray) for PlayStation 4 supporting upto 12.50 firmware from Gezine</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[BD-JB-1250]_New_Exploit_(bluray)_for_PlayStation_4_supporting_upto_12.50_firmware_from_Gezine.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/bd-jb-1250-new-exploit-bluray-for-playstation-4-supporting-upto-12-50-firmware-from-gezine.48161/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[BD-JB-1250]_New_Exploit_(bluray)_for_PlayStation_4_supporting_upto_12.50_firmware_from_Gezine.jpg">The PlayStation 4 has new BluRay exploit that supports upto 12.50 Firmware. Thanks to the efforts of developerGezine,who has released the source code and helloworld.iso to complete the proof of work of this recent exploit for the PS4.  Below you can see the readme for the project. Also some community reaction and comments about the new exploit for the PS4 from Abkarino & Modded Warefare dives into the exploit in one of his latest video attached​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-6-24T01:48:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>{CFW Release} 4.92.2 Evilnat  Custom Firmware (w/ Cobra v8.5) - Includes: CEX/PEX/D-PEX) + noBD/BT</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{CFW_Release}_4.92.2_Evilnat__Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_-_Includes_CEXPEXD-PEX)_+_noBDBT.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/cfw-release-4-92-2-evilnat-custom-firmware-w-cobra-v8-5-includes-cex-pex-d-pex-nobd-bt.47798/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{CFW_Release}_4.92.2_Evilnat__Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_-_Includes_CEXPEXD-PEX)_+_noBDBT.jpg">After a successful Open Beta for 4.92.2, PlayStation 3 CFW developer@Evilnathas nowOFFICIALLYupdated hisEvilnat Custom Firmware'sfor the PS3 to version4.92.2,A number of new changes and options have been added in this release for your PS3 FAT and Early Slim models capable of installing a CFW PUP.Various patches to the CFW have been made as well as various new additions to theCobra Payload, Also theXAI Pluginwas not left out, as there are some new options one being a newNew Overclock menuhas been introduced to the firmware.  Now we no longer need a dedicated PUP to change overclock settings, it can be done directly on the XMB. All the details and changes can be found in Evilnat's release note's found below and also in the link provided at the bottom.​</description>
			<creators>Evilnat</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-6-14T04:10:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ProtoPwn (Protokernel Exploit by pcm720) -  Now all PS2s are hackable via MemoryCard  (MILESTONE)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ProtoPwn_(Protokernel_Exploit_by_pcm720)_-__Now_all_PS2s_are_hackable_via_MemoryCard__(MILESTONE).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/protopwn-protokernel-exploit-by-pcm720-now-all-ps2s-are-hackable-via-memorycard-milestone.47708/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ProtoPwn_(Protokernel_Exploit_by_pcm720)_-__Now_all_PS2s_are_hackable_via_MemoryCard__(MILESTONE).jpg">Breaking Newsin the PS2 Scene,as a NEW MemoryCard Exploit for Protokernel PS2s (SCPH-10000, SCPH-15000, and DTL-H10000(S)) just got released!!!It took 25 years to reach this point, butNOW ALL PS2s including ALL special models(Arcade, Prototype, Debug, Consumer-model, "special/custom builds")can load Homebrew WITHOUT DISCS!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-5-10T13:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>BadWDSD HW Exploit - With new powerful qCFW for PS3 Slim & SuperSlim NOR models on the horizon</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/BadWDSD_HW_Exploit_-_With_new_powerful_qCFW_for_PS3_Slim_&_SuperSlim_NOR_models_on_the_horizon.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/badwdsd-hw-exploit-with-new-powerful-qcfw-for-ps3-slim-superslim-nor-models-on-the-horizon.47475/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/BadWDSD_HW_Exploit_-_With_new_powerful_qCFW_for_PS3_Slim_&_SuperSlim_NOR_models_on_the_horizon.jpg">Update (Jan. 30) -@esc0rtd3whas releaseda new beta, while not the FINAL (yet) it is the first beta HEN with the qCFW installer.Update (Jan. 29) -@aomsin2526has released thefirst public version of qCFWfor the BadWDSD exploit, now we still needPS3HEN 3.4.1 (FINAL)for the qCFW installer to utilize the qCFW release.Update (Jan. 15)-@aomsin2526has provided a new progress report,qCFWis nearing a public release.>>>LinkUpdate (Dec. 8) -@aomsin2526(aka chattrapat_s / kafuu)has provided an update for the project, in the form of a "To-Do" list for the project, with some reported progress like"qCFW is done"see full post>>> LinkUpdate (Sept. 11) -New video demonstration and details "qCFW will be based on Evilnat PEX from now on. This means both CEX and...​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-31T22:32:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN w/ Linux & Overclocking Support? BadHTAB A hardware-software based hypervisor (lv1) exploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_w_Linux_&_Overclocking_Support_BadHTAB_A_hardware-software_based_hypervisor_(lv1)_exploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-w-linux-overclocking-support-badhtab-a-hardware-software-based-hypervisor-lv1-exploit.47282/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_w_Linux_&_Overclocking_Support_BadHTAB_A_hardware-software_based_hypervisor_(lv1)_exploit.jpg">UPDATE 4 - (May 2 / June 9):@esc0rtd3whas created a fork of the BadHTAB Exploit with some changes such as an "Automatic reboot if glitch crashes ps3" feature among other changes to make it easier for testing the new exploit.(June 9)- ReadMe Updated in link belowUPDATE 2 & 3:Now, not only Linux but also Overclocking on PS3HEN is now possible w/BadHTAB exploit&PS3HEN (beta builds)that are currently supporting the exploit. This is still considered an experimental exploit & features soUse at your Risk.  (See update tabs/links) for additional details and information on these advancements for the PlayStation 3.Original Article: Could Linux Support onPS3HENbe a reality with new exploit? Yes, and also other features but itsnot going to be for everyone. There is a newProof of Conceptreleased for the PS3 that has been implemented byKafuu(@aomsin2526)usingGeohot'soldhtab glitchon PS3HEN.  Developer@zecoxaofirst started posting about this idea and the concept in Jan. of 2023 here inthe forum'sand has shared various thoughts and progress, with the latest progress being Kafuu's implementation.BadHTABis ahardware-softwarebased hypervisor (lv1) exploit,The exploit has a very low success rate of (5-10%)as GameOS has a much smaller "glitch window". As the readme states this not meant "for daily driver, it is for user's withskill and patienceonly.".​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-15T20:55:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PlayStation Home Revived and Enhanced by Home Laboratory!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_Home_Revived_and_Enhanced_by_Home_Laboratory!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/playstation-home-revived-and-enhanced-by-home-laboratory.47120/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_Home_Revived_and_Enhanced_by_Home_Laboratory!.jpg">Home is back on the XMB in 2025! Download and Play just like it was originally!I am pleased to present our extensive work on reviving and enhancingPlayStation Home. Led by AgentDark447, our team has developed an advanced, open-source iteration of this server platform, significantly expanding its capabilities beyond the original. Below, I outline the project’s scope, technical advancements, and access instructions for those interested in exploring or contributing.​</description>
			<creators>DeViL303</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-15T10:34:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Toolset (by bguerville) with 4.92 support has been released.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_(by_bguerville)_with_4.92_support_has_been_released..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-toolset-by-bguerville-with-4-92-support-has-been-released.47135/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_(by_bguerville)_with_4.92_support_has_been_released..jpg">If you have a Custom Firmware compatible PlayStation 3 Model and are running 4.92 Official Firmware and need to Jailbreak for the first time or if you updated your previous CFW installation by mistake to 4.92 OFW. Then the PS3 Toolset will exploit your PS3 via the console's web browser and visitingps3toolset.com website(see tutorial tab), then once the process has completed you will be able to install a Custom Firmware (such as 4.92 Evilnat)  once again or for the first time.Your PlayStation 3 model must be able to install a CFW, these would be all the FAT models PS3 and Early production Slim Models. The easiest and most effective ways to determine if your PS3 can install a cfw​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-9T11:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.92 Littlebalup's DUALBOOT firmware Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Littlebalup's_DUALBOOT_firmware_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-92-littlebalups-dualboot-firmware-released.46963/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Littlebalup's_DUALBOOT_firmware_Released.jpg">Since the4.92 firmware updatethings have been flowing out from the community in response. We have seenPS3HEN (& hfw) releasedfor 4.92 and we have seenEvilnat updateand release his cfw collection on 4.92. Now developer@littlebalupdrops by the forumand release the latestDualBoot (DB) firmwareto support 4.92 firmware.This release for Custom Firmware user's is a very useful firmware, if you use PSN still and do not want to go online with a modded system and risk a potential ban. As it allows you to use an Official firmware that can re-install a CFW without having re-exploiting the console with the toolset or flash writer. See full details in @littlebalups release notes about the Dualboot firmware concept.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-9T11:24:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.92 Evilnat Custom Firmware (w/ Cobra v8.5) Released - CEX,PEX,D-PEX,DEX builds</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Evilnat_Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_Released_-_CEX,PEX,D-PEX,DEX_builds.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-92-evilnat-custom-firmware-w-cobra-v8-5-released-cex-pex-d-pex-dex-builds.46961/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Evilnat_Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_Released_-_CEX,PEX,D-PEX,DEX_builds.jpg">UPDATExai_plugin:New Overclocking Tools (change on the fly) / New ps2netemu improvements added.Following the4.92 firmware updatedeveloper's from around the community have been updating various projects. This time around PS3 CFW developer@Evilnatdrops by the forumand leave's us with a suite of ps3 custom firmware's that support 4.92 firmware.  4 Flavor's (CEX, PEX, D-PEX & DEX) are available for 4.92 Evilnat CFW, depending on your console/taste, all builds are equipped with theCobra v8.5 payloadto provide expanded feature set over Standard CFW's.If you are already on PS3 CFW, updating is a breeze, you just need to install the new CFW PUP file via the official USB Method and you will be on Evilnat's latest release. If you have updated to 4.92 OFW you will have to wait, as you will have re-exploit your ps3 console to allow for a Custom Firmware installation once again. The good news is that developer@bguervilleshould be rolling out a new update soon for the PS3 Toolset that support 4.92 firmware.  The offline tool CFW Flash Writer may take longer for the community to update it, but we hope to see an update for that tool soon as well.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-11-8T00:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>New PS1/PS2 Emulation Features for PS3 CFW user's + Evilnat's 4.91.2-BETA 12</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/New_PS1PS2_Emulation_Features_for_PS3_CFW_user's_+_Evilnat's_4.91.2-BETA_12.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/new-ps1-ps2-emulation-features-for-ps3-cfw-users-evilnats-4-91-2-beta-12.45233/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/New_PS1PS2_Emulation_Features_for_PS3_CFW_user's_+_Evilnat's_4.91.2-BETA_12.jpg">UPDATE: January 2025:ps2gxemu (for CECH-C/E ps3 models) has been updated by@kozarovv+ netemu to gxemu config conversion tool by@Zarhas been released, see details at bottomNov. 2024:  Recently we have had some great news with developments surroundingPS1 & PS2 Emulation on the PS3 for Custom Firmware user'sas the emulator's that reside in the PlayStation 3 Firmware have receivedsome modded tweaksthanks to@kozarovv&@mrjaredbeta, The files can be added manually to many firmware's or you can update to the latest release ofEvilnat's 4.91.2 CFW (BETA 12)that have these newly modded emulator's already installed and ready to go thanks to@Evilnat.The changes and feature's depend on the PS2/PS1 emulator being used and also on which model of the PS3 (with PS2). Below you will find a brief explanation of the emulator, mixed in with the readme details and some added screenshot. Some of the feature's need more testing to see how affective they may be such as the partial antiblur and EE Overclocking/Underclocking patches.  View all the details and related links found below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-7-16T21:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>CFW Flash Writer - Unofficial 4.91 update</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/CFW_Flash_Writer_-_Unofficial_4.91_update.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/cfw-flash-writer-unofficial-4-91-update.44229/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/CFW_Flash_Writer_-_Unofficial_4.91_update.jpg">Developer@aldostoolshas released an unofficial update for theCFW Flash Writerto supportHFW 4.91on the PS3. This can be a secondary candidate for allowing Custom Firmware installations whenbguerville's PS3Toolset (https://www.ps3toolset.com/bgtoolset/)isn't accessible or a self hosting offline option. However, ThePs3toolset is still the preferred  and safest method when available for hacking your capable ps3 model so its ready for PS3 Custom Firmware installations.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-16T23:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Official PS3 Toolset Update (v1.2.007) Release (4.91 Support)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3_Toolset_Update_(v1.2.007)_Release_(4.91_Support).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-ps3-toolset-update-v1-2-007-release-4-91-support.43211/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3_Toolset_Update_(v1.2.007)_Release_(4.91_Support).jpg">FollowingSony firmware update of 4.91for the PS3, developer's across the scene have been updating various exploits and tools. We have seen developer@Evilnatrelease his4.91 PS3 Custom Firmware'searlier in the week. Then we recently just had@esc0rtd3w&@JoonieprovidePS3HEN (& HFW) updated with 4.91 Support. Now we have developer@bguervillewith an update to hisPS3 Toolsetto support the exploiting of 4.91 OFW for custom firmware installation for capable models.​</description>
			<creators>bguerville</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-16T07:42:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Official PS3HEN v3.3.0  + HFW Released for 4.91 Firmware from Team PS3Xploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3HEN_v3.3.0__+_HFW_Released_for_4.91_Firmware_from_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-ps3hen-v3-3-0-hfw-released-for-4-91-firmware-from-team-ps3xploit.43199/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3HEN_v3.3.0__+_HFW_Released_for_4.91_Firmware_from_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg">TheOfficial PS3HENexploit has beenupdated to v3.3.0with some new changes from@esc0rtd3wand@JoonieofTeam PS3Xploitto support 4.91.  Also, developer Joonie has brought back the webkit exploit from 4.82 to 4.91 with the official HFW release(HFW = OFW with old webkit injected). Its best to use the official HFW when using the official PS3HEN release.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-9T19:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update Re-Release] PS3 Custom Firmware - 4.91 Evilnat Cobra (8.4) CFW Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_Re-Release]_PS3_Custom_Firmware_-_4.91_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.4)_CFW_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-re-release-ps3-custom-firmware-4-91-evilnat-cobra-8-4-cfw-released.43110/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_Re-Release]_PS3_Custom_Firmware_-_4.91_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.4)_CFW_Released.jpg">UPDATE -See 1st post for details, Re-Release a few bugs correctedPlayStation 3 CFW developer@Evilnathas just released his much anticipated4.91 Evilnat Custom Firmwarefollowingthe recent routine updatefrom Sony when they dropped firmware 4.91 last week.  If you are on any Custom Firmware currently all you have to do is install this CFW PuP by the USB method. You will not need to wait for an update to bguerville's PS3 Toolset to exploit your system (as its already exploited if you are running CFW).If you had updated to 4.91 OFW or by mistake installed a HFW you will have to wait for the PS3 Toolset to be updated. Developerbguervillewas waiting for the first 4.91 CFW to drop before making his update and that has just occurred with this release, so it should not be to long before we see bguerville provide a 4.91 update to the toolset as the developerdescribed herein the psx-place forums..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-2-27T05:25:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 4.91 Firmware Released - Do Not Update!!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_4.91_Firmware_Released_-_Do_Not_Update!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-4-91-firmware-released-do-not-update.42992/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_4.91_Firmware_Released_-_Do_Not_Update!!!.jpg">UPDATE:its now safe to update to 4.91. PS3HEN (& HFW), CFW & PS3 Toolset have been updated to support 4.91.PS3 Firmware 4.91 is now LiveThe expected once a year firmware update has been executed by Sony, PS3 4.91 Firmware is now Live. While an expected update, could this bring other changes to the firmware? Likely not but its still early to conclude as this update is fresh as of writing .Do not update, various exploits / tools / essential homebrew will need to be updated to support the latest firmware update of 4.91. See below for a short FAQ on 4.91, as there is always some confusions around the update process. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-30T10:41:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Movian M7 (by deank)  - "libav" swapped for "ffmpeg"  & slight name change</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_M7_(by_deank)__-_libav_swapped_for_ffmpeg__&_slight_name_change.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/movian-m7-by-deank-libav-swapped-for-ffmpeg-slight-name-change.42453/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_M7_(by_deank)__-_libav_swapped_for_ffmpeg__&_slight_name_change.jpg">Developer@deankwho has been continuing development of the (modded version) of the original media center that started on the PS3(now runs on Android, Amazon Fire Stick, MacOS ,Windown ,Linux  & Raspberry pi). The media center originally was named "Showtime" on the PS3 but later renamed to "Movian" by the original developerAndreas Omanyears ago.Since that time, we have not seen the official project do much in recent years (currentlyhome siteis down as of writing), but developer deank has been keeping the project alive and evolving (see changelogsover at brewologyfor all archived changes). One of the biggest changes you will see within Movian-M7 compared to older version, is the change from the older (abandoned) "libav" video decoders/parsers to the current "ffmpeg" that was just replaced in the recent M7 update . This should improve compatibility and make for a more up-to date and versatile media player for all supported platforms including the PS3.Also, deank  has made a quick stop in the forum's, then to see a reported issue and provided a fix (seen here) that is now present in v7.0.2​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-4-1T01:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN v3.2.2 - New Additions/ Fixes & Backported Firmware's  Support from Team PS3Xploit.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_v3.2.2_-_New_Additions_Fixes_&_Backported_Firmware's__Support_from_Team_PS3Xploit..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-v3-2-2-new-additions-fixes-backported-firmwares-support-from-team-ps3xploit.40129/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_v3.2.2_-_New_Additions_Fixes_&_Backported_Firmware's__Support_from_Team_PS3Xploit..jpg">Update 4/25/2023: PS3HEN 3.2.2 has been released. Check the changelog for details.We have seen a lot of developer's back in the fold after the4.90 official firmware updatethat hit the PlayStation 3 several weeks ago. We seen a couple weeks ago developer's@Joonieand@esc0rtd3wof thePs3Xploit Teamupdate Ps3HEN to v3.2.0, now we have a new update with the release of v3.2.1..Ps3HENis a Homebrew Enabler that is an alternative exploit to custom firmware (cfw) for models that can not install a CFW. unlikecustom firmwareon the ps3, Ps3HEN has the ability to run on all ps3 model's, while many feature that are in CFW can be found in PS3HEN it does not completely replicate the CFW experience so if your PS3 has the ability to run a CFW that is the better route, but Ps3HEN is a very powerful and capable exploit. See a CFW vs Ps3HEN comparison>here<for a rundown of feature's.In the update v3.2.1, there has been a number of changes and added support to Ps3HEN.@Jooniehas released a backport ofHFW (hybrid firmware) for 4.83, this was done as Ps3HEN has provided support for 4.83 FW, plus 4.84 DEX firmware is also now supported.  There has been a number of other supported firmware and various other changes in the payload and plugin to PS3HEN, Plus this fixes the wMM bug that was creating freezing issue in v3.2.0.  See latest changelogs provided below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-3-23T18:53:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The OFFICIAL bguerville's PS3 Toolset is back online with a new official URL and 4.90 Support !!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_OFFICIAL_bguerville's_PS3_Toolset_is_back_online_with_a_new_official_URL_and_4.90_Support_!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-official-bguervilles-ps3-toolset-is-back-online-with-a-new-official-url-and-4-90-support.40076/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_OFFICIAL_bguerville's_PS3_Toolset_is_back_online_with_a_new_official_URL_and_4.90_Support_!!!.jpg">Last week, we seen developer@bguervillereturn, and he brought theOFFICIAL bguerville PS3 Toolset back onlinewith an new official domain >ps3toolset.com.At first the developer brought back support for 4.80 - 4.89 OFW, but the 4.90 update was not ready quite yet during the relaunch of the website. After testing the 4.90 update, its now ready for a release and has been deployed at the new official URL (ps3toolset.com).PS3 User's should be aware the ps3xploit team lost some of the domain's of their website's late in 2022. Currently the official team website isps3xploit.me. The team lost it's (.com / .net / .org) domains and those are no longer owned by the team (read more here). Also, beware there are unfortunately a number of fraudulent / scammer's posing themselves as the PS3Xploit Team with cloned websites & domain's, .cc / .xyz are some of those fraudulent URL's posing as the team and/orhosting dangerous incomplete software.  Take a look here in>this thread<from@esc0rtd3win the official PS3Xploit Team forums here at psx-place for a listing of all the official domains of the PS3Xploit Team and status, always a good place to check (and spread the word) so you do not get scammed or get fooled into using something dangerous.Now with the official bguerville toolset released and also an update to support4.90...​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-3-4T11:07:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Exploiting 4.90 OFW (Installing CFW & Running PS3HEN) Flash Writer / PS3HEN now supporting 4.90 FW</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Exploiting_4.90_OFW_(Installing_CFW_&_Running_PS3HEN)_Flash_Writer__PS3HEN_now_supporting_4.90_FW.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/exploiting-4-90-ofw-installing-cfw-running-ps3hen-flash-writer-ps3hen-now-supporting-4-90-fw.39772/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Exploiting_4.90_OFW_(Installing_CFW_&_Running_PS3HEN)_Flash_Writer__PS3HEN_now_supporting_4.90_FW.jpg">(Update:PS3HEN 3.2.0w/ 4.90 Support Released)Exploiting a PlayStation 3 console in firmware 4.89 was a bit of a mess to say the least and added alot of confusion that was compounded by bad advice's on various platforms and even the emergence of dangerous software. Withincomplete versionof the closed source PS3 Toolset by bguerville (of PS3Xploit Team) that were being distributed around the net, Causing random bricks to user's as they were not using the true Toolset as it was not the Original Code of the Toolset (just partial code and some bypasses/removal of check's, that are normally designed to make the toolset safe and brick-proof originally in the official. but the incomplete you have to hope everything goes smoothly) .So, many great developer's that are active in the PS3 scene now and whom have return to the scene and a new name have come together with psx-place to bring you the proper exploration of 4.90 on your PS3 Console.  So we do not have the same confusion in the scene that we seen in 4.89 and the unofficial brick-ware floating from unreliable and untrustworthy sources and software..We want to set the stage for the safest methods from the names of developer's you trust that been in the scene for year's and the names who have been advancing the community for a long time.Not having to rely on the untrustworthy sources and services.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-3-1T19:44:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Firmware 4.90 (OFW) is Live - Do Not Update, see full details!!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Firmware_4.90_(OFW)_is_Live_-_Do_Not_Update,_see_full_details!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-firmware-4-90-ofw-is-live-do-not-update-see-full-details.39705/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Firmware_4.90_(OFW)_is_Live_-_Do_Not_Update,_see_full_details!!!.jpg">As Sony tends to do, they like to come with a surprise firmware update when you least expect it and here they are with a surprise4.90 firmware update, now there has been some panic of potential changes and exploits that could be patched in 4.90,  well that is lhe case and not a worry (you shouldn't update yet, but no exploits have been closed), Since firmware 4.80 there has not  been any changes to the kernel, developer@Joonieconfirms in the forumsherethat4.90 use's the 4.80 kernel sourceand since firmware 4.83 we have not seen any counter measure to deter homebrew capabilities on the console for CFW or PS3HEN,Which that attempt (in 4.83) was countered by@Jooniewith the creation of HFW (OFW w/ 4.82 webkit injected). Since that time we have seen the towel thrown in as 4.84 / 4.85 / 4.86 / 4.87 /4.88 / 4.89 and now in 4.90. The update is the usual BluRay update and not much more, but good to see Sony still supporting the BluRay drive (as they should IMO).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-2-1T08:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>CFW RELEASED - 4.89.3 Evilnat (Cobra v8.4) Official debut of PEX (New PS3 CFW type) + Other flavor's</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/CFW_RELEASED_-_4.89.3_Evilnat_(Cobra_v8.4)_Official_debut_of_PEX_(New_PS3_CFW_type)_+_Other_flavor's.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/cfw-released-4-89-3-evilnat-cobra-v8-4-official-debut-of-pex-new-ps3-cfw-type-other-flavors.39315/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/CFW_RELEASED_-_4.89.3_Evilnat_(Cobra_v8.4)_Official_debut_of_PEX_(New_PS3_CFW_type)_+_Other_flavor's.jpg">UPDATE (Re-Download PUP)-via@Evilnat"CFW 4.89.3 updated withCobra 8.4by default andxai_updater updated to v1.2for all versions! It fixes updater package for CEX and DEX."Developer@Evilnathas releasedthe much anticipated updateto his PS3 CFW with the release of4.89.3 Evilnat CFW.This update comes with a variety of PUP to choose from and as we beendetailing overthe pastseveral monthsthere are alot of new features in this custom firmware release from developer@Evilnat,This firmware brings back a lost relic of the scene that was stopped at firmware 4.84 and I am speaking ofRebug REX(the original hybrid of CEX(retail) / DEX (debug) firmware), With no DEX firmware available to the public past 4.84 there was a problem, developer's knew how to create a REX style firmware,they have just been missing the DEX portion since 4.84. Well developer@Evilnatdecided he would try and bring 4.84 DEX to 4.89 by porting the firmware and after some trials and error's the developer was able to achieve that goal and now we haveEvilnat PEX (& D-PEX) CFWwhich is a hybrid like Rebug REX..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-1-14T11:38:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Evilnat 4.89.3 CFW (Official Release - Coming Soon) PEX / OverClocking / Cobra v8.4 / xai_plugin /.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Evilnat_4.89.3_CFW_(Official_Release_-_Coming_Soon)_PEX__OverClocking__Cobra_v8.4__xai_plugin_..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/evilnat-4-89-3-cfw-official-release-coming-soon-pex-overclocking-cobra-v8-4-xai_plugin.39243/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Evilnat_4.89.3_CFW_(Official_Release_-_Coming_Soon)_PEX__OverClocking__Cobra_v8.4__xai_plugin_..jpg">As we have been telling yousince last Octoberdeveloper@Evilnathas been working on an epic PS3 Custom Firmware (CFW) with the upcoming release of4.89.3 Evilnat CFW. Back in October we weredetailing someof the changes coming to the custom xai_plugin that, The custom changes provides many advance features at your fingertips right from the convenience of the XMB,  Since that time the developer has added more feature's to the xai_plugin, a plugin that comes embedded in Evilnat's firmware's. On his personal twitter the developer has detailed some of those new functions also many of those can be seen in the official discussion thread for 4.89 Evilnat CFWhereas well.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-11-14T21:01:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Dynarec support on PicoDrive (Sega 32x & Improved Sega CD) on the horizon from OsirisX</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Dynarec_support_on_PicoDrive_(Sega_32x_&_Improved_Sega_CD)_on_the_horizon_from_OsirisX.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-dynarec-support-on-picodrive-sega-32x-improved-sega-cd-on-the-horizon-from-osirisx.38675/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Dynarec_support_on_PicoDrive_(Sega_32x_&_Improved_Sega_CD)_on_the_horizon_from_OsirisX.jpg">Good news if your a fan of retro emulation and have a jailbroken PS3, as developer@OsirisXhas made a bit of a breakthrough for emulation on the PS3. Following OsirisX other emulation release's / contributions  like theunofficial PS4 port of RetroArchand the progress of theRetroArch Psl1ght PS3 portThe developer is now tackling taking on a new adventure on the PS3.One of the issues on the PS3, has always been the supporting of later generations(the 3d era+)of emulation. While we have seen PS1 / PSP / PS2 emulated  on the PS3, they are using the unlocked  system's firmware emulator's from Sony,. homebrew emulation has not achieved the same success, without support of a dynarec and the emulators re-written to support such a dynarec on the PS3, user's have been stuck side-scrolling in their Retro experiances.  We seen an early example years ago when developer IngPeria released a PoC PS1 emulator (not Sony's firmware one) with dynarec support, but not many other developer's took on the task for any other emulators.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-19T23:57:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PlayStation Home  v0.41 (GDC Demo 2007) playable on HEN & CFW from DeViL303</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_Home__v0.41_(GDC_Demo_2007)_playable_on_HEN_&_CFW_from_DeViL303.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/playstation-home-v0-41-gdc-demo-2007-playable-on-hen-cfw-from-devil303.38492/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_Home__v0.41_(GDC_Demo_2007)_playable_on_HEN_&_CFW_from_DeViL303.jpg">PlayStation 3 developer@DeViL303has been working on a new project of late, taking a break from some of the fantastic XMB work and various firmware hacks and tweaks. The developer has recently set his sights on PlayStation Home and bringing some of the functionality back while preserving some of the history of the project.  DeViL303 has managed to get alot working in the GDC Demo 2007 of Home. There are various notes and details provided below along with a video demonstration of what is working. See full details in the release thread linked​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-19T19:25:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE x5] What is Evilnat brewing up in his next PS3 CFW Release?  4.89.3 in development</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_x5]_What_is_Evilnat_brewing_up_in_his_next_PS3_CFW_Release__4.89.3_in_development.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-x5-what-is-evilnat-brewing-up-in-his-next-ps3-cfw-release-4-89-3-in-development.38489/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_x5]_What_is_Evilnat_brewing_up_in_his_next_PS3_CFW_Release__4.89.3_in_development.jpg">PlayStation 3 developer@Evilnathas been researching and developing some new features for his popularEvilnat's Cobra CFWfor the PS3.  Sony may have dropped official updates, but the development community has not stopped support and continues to pack new features and functionality directly into the firmware. With 4.89.3now confirmedin development by@EvilnatSome of these features are still in the PoC stage and some should be implemented in the next stable release (once fully tested) of the CFW. Currently the community developer's only have access to 4.84 DEX firmware, so the developer is trying to find (if it exist) 4.89 DEX (or a higher then 4.84 DEX) but the developer seems to be experimenting with "porting 4.84 DEX Kernel and required modules to 4.89 (like Rebug REX/D-REX) and is working as expected until now". However the developer warns at this time its still needs alot of testing but its encouraging to see some great development still going into PlayStation 3 CFW and to the Cobra Payload.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-7-7T19:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>OFFICIAL bguerville's PS3 Toolset v1.2.004 Update Now Live - Supporting 4.89 + NEW Features</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OFFICIAL_bguerville's_PS3_Toolset_v1.2.004_Update_Now_Live_-_Supporting_4.89_+_NEW_Features.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-bguervilles-ps3-toolset-v1-2-004-update-now-live-supporting-4-89-new-features.37806/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OFFICIAL_bguerville's_PS3_Toolset_v1.2.004_Update_Now_Live_-_Supporting_4.89_+_NEW_Features.jpg">Notice OFFICIAL PS3 Toolset is not currently online, will be back soon.See Link for more info:https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4...irmware-capable-models-status-warnings.38553/Beware there are some unofficial versions out there in the wild, They are incomplete and have a high brick risk they should not be consider mirror. When official PS3 Toolset is back online we will update you here,.Following the firmware update of 4.89 the scene was awaiting an update tobguerville's PS3 Toolsetso that CFW capable console who may of updated to 4.89 (or jailbreaking for the first time) can run the exploit and once again and be able to install CFW from 4.89.  Now for those experienced CFW user's they knew they should wait and NOT UPDATE when a new firmware update goes live as those user's simply just waited for Evilnat's 4.89 Cobra CFW to be released. .Now back to the official toolset update, behind the scene's prior to the 4.89 update the v1.2 update was near deployment. So instead of making various updates, one to support 4.89 and one for v1.2 new feature's it made sense for the project to have one testing session and release in a single update for 4.89 but that meant it a bit of delay for the deployment since proper testing needed to be conducted with v1.2 features.  However in that time period a Russian Scene site had found someone else's re-implementation(they forget to mention that)and patched worked together a toolset that looked like the real thing but it was hardly bguerville's original toolset nor did it offered the safety/quality or feature set of the real release.There have been various changes in v1.2004 but the much anticipatedFile Manager&xRegistry Editorwill still be rolled out in a future update that will arrive soon after some theming issue's are sorted.  To quote developer@bguervilleabout the new features in this update the developer states  "there is a few new features to play with other than 4.89 support, like some memory patching options including HAN, memory dumping, extended system information details and syscon error logs. Afaik the issue that led to crashes on page load on certain setups should be fixed"  Additional details can be seen in the tabs below .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-6-10T17:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>(UPDATE 2 ) Thefl0w discloses"Blu-ray Disc Java Sandbox Escape" vulnerabilities (PS3, PS4, PS5)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(UPDATE_2_)_Thefl0w_disclosesBlu-ray_Disc_Java_Sandbox_Escape_vulnerabilities_(PS3,_PS4,_PS5).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-2-thefl0w-discloses-blu-ray-disc-java-sandbox-escape-vulnerabilities-ps3-ps4-ps5.37554/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(UPDATE_2_)_Thefl0w_disclosesBlu-ray_Disc_Java_Sandbox_Escape_vulnerabilities_(PS3,_PS4,_PS5).jpg">Update (See Tabs Below PS3 / PS4):Since the disclosure several developer's have went on the hunt and we have seen PoC releases and TEST payload pushed, We have confirmation the PoC is working on 9.00, other have been testing impact on 9.03/.04. See all the details from developer's likesleirsgoevy /@zecoxao/ psxdev(aka bigboss)in the PS4 Tab. Some preliminary discussions about the PS3 impact have been discussed in this thread from various developer's like@bguervilleand@zecoxaoOriginal Article:DeveloperTheFl0wwho is well known in the Homebrew and Hacking in the PlayStation Community, via the hackerone program the hacker has yet again disclosed details on vulnerabilities (5)  "bd-jb Blu-ray Disc Java Sandbox Escape"  is affecting PS3, PS4, PS5.Sony has patched these vulnerabilities in recent firmware updates for the PS5 / PS4 with firmware update's of 5.00 FW for the PS5 and 9.50 FW for the PS4.  These methods are also likely to work on the PS3 according to thefl0w (likely on the latest firmware).thefl0w has detailed some advantages this concept provides over a webkit exploit, you can see that information and various details in the "additional info" tab below, along with some clarification due to over hyping some aspects of this exploit..:​</description>
			<creators>NuthinNew</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-5-24T22:40:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch PS4 (OrbisDev Port) official release on the horizon (PS4 support added to mainline Repo)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_PS4_(OrbisDev_Port)_official_release_on_the_horizon_(PS4_support_added_to_mainline_Repo).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-ps4-orbisdev-port-official-release-on-the-horizon-ps4-support-added-to-mainline-repo.37384/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_PS4_(OrbisDev_Port)_official_release_on_the_horizon_(PS4_support_added_to_mainline_Repo).jpg">If you follow thepsx-place twitter feed, you may of seen aretweet from libretro's officialaccount yesterday, announcing theRetroArch PS4code being merged and adopted into the mainline RetroArch code repo, this mean soon we could see the official release of RetroArch PS4, as the official team has accepted theOrbisdev Portsubmission from scene developer's . For sometime there has been an unofficial port ofRetroArch PS4by developer@OsirisX,who (unrelated to ps4) also shared recently his progress on thepsl1ght port for the PS3 hereforums, to help bring the PS3 back into the mainline RetroArch repo. As the official team removed the old PS3 port in favor of the Open Source psl1ght SDK.The same thing was happening with the PS4, while we had a very functionalunofficial RetroArch PS4 portas seen here in the forums by the dev, it was never adopted in the official project's mainline repo, because the official team preferred aOrbisDev (OpenSource SDK)PS4 port.  Thanks to various ps4 developer's like@fjtrujy/@OsirisX/ @frangar&@psxdev. We now have a build that is close to an official release created with the OpenOrbis SDK.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-5-20T18:49:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN v3.1.1  & HFW Officially updated with 4.89 Support  - (The PS3 Exploit for nonCFW PS3 Models)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_v3.1.1__&_HFW_Officially_updated_with_4.89_Support__-_(The_PS3_Exploit_for_nonCFW_PS3_Models).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-v3-1-1-hfw-officially-updated-with-4-89-support-the-ps3-exploit-for-noncfw-ps3-models.37273/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_v3.1.1__&_HFW_Officially_updated_with_4.89_Support__-_(The_PS3_Exploit_for_nonCFW_PS3_Models).jpg">UPDATE:  v3.1.1 released with HOTFIX see changelog below for v3.1.1Following thefirmware update of 4.89that Sony rolled out last week, the reunion of ps3 developer's was set for the PS3 homebrew / hacking community, First we seen well known Ps3 Homebrew / CFW developer@Evilnatdelivered his4.89 Evilnat (Cobra 8.3)a few days ago for those models that can install a PS3 Custom Firmware, but for those console that can not you can get many CFW features: like the ability to launch homebrew and plugins with the PS3HEN exploit. As@esc0rtd3wof thePS3Xploit Teamhas just released PS3HEN and fellow scene developer@littlebaluphas delivered the special firmware (HFW) that restore the exploits from firmware 4.82 that allows for the execution of PS3HEN.In this official release of PS3HEN v3.1.0(& HFW)for 4.89 firmware, there has been various changes to PS3HEN from developer@esc0rtd3wand various scene developer's like@bucanero,@sandungasand also@xps3rimentshave contributed to as detailed in the changelogs for this latest release of PS3HEN (Official).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-5-17T21:11:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.89 Evilnat CFW w/ Cobra v8.3 (CEX) (+ noBD /noBT builds)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.89_Evilnat_CFW_w_Cobra_v8.3_(CEX)_(+_noBD_noBT_builds).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-89-evilnat-cfw-w-cobra-v8-3-cex-nobd-nobt-builds.37272/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.89_Evilnat_CFW_w_Cobra_v8.3_(CEX)_(+_noBD_noBT_builds).jpg">Following the success of4.88 Evilnat CFW. well known PS3 developer@Evilnatis at it again with a new Custom Firmware Release for 4.89 with the release ofPs3 CFW 4.89 Evilnat Cobra (8.3) (CEX) , following the official firmware update from Sony last week. This CEX based firmware comes packed with the Cobra 8.3 injected into the firmware(making this a Cobra CFW).There is tons of features packed into this firmware that coming from a top tier of developer's who has a strong reputation in the PS3 Homebrew / Hacking scene. The developer did not forget about the damage console with noBD / noBT builds of the Custom firmware also available  Checkout all the details below.PS3HEN, BG Toolset and HFW Official releases are also coming soon from their respective creators , but be patient as important test are being conducted and BEWARE of unofficial releases (of PS3HEN/HFW) there has been some attempts emerging that may encounter issues from improper creations and untested attempts, best to wait for the creator's of these methods to be released with the latest version, Stay tuned for those incoming if you do not have a CFW enabled PS3 model then look out soon for PS3HEN and HFW. But if you have a CFW enabled PS3 and need to jailbreak you will still need to wait for bgtoolset to get an update for 4.89 support. Stay tuned as these release's drop in the coming days..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-5-10T18:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.89 PS3 Firmware is now live. - Does it affect a Jailbroken / Homebrew Enabled  PS3?</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.89_PS3_Firmware_is_now_live._-_Does_it_affect_a_Jailbroken__Homebrew_Enabled__PS3.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-89-ps3-firmware-is-now-live-does-it-affect-a-jailbroken-homebrew-enabled-ps3.37206/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.89_PS3_Firmware_is_now_live._-_Does_it_affect_a_Jailbroken__Homebrew_Enabled__PS3.jpg">Latest Status Update (May 20)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-2-8T22:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch (Community Edition) Beta 4  - Unofficial PS3 Port by Crystal</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(Community_Edition)_Beta_4__-_Unofficial_PS3_Port_by_Crystal.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-community-edition-beta-4-unofficial-ps3-port-by-crystal.36469/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(Community_Edition)_Beta_4__-_Unofficial_PS3_Port_by_Crystal.jpg">RetroArch(CommunityEdition)has reachedBeta 4with a recent update provided by PlayStation 3 Homebrew developer@Crystal,.  RetroArch (CE)  "is a community effort to restore a functional build for the homebrew PS3 Community,". The official port for the PS3 from the libretro team been temporary shelved during a code transition. So, that is whereRetroArch  (CE)has been filling the gap in providing a port that has fixed some longstanding issues on the PS3 with a greater focus on the console itself. The result becomes one of the most stable RetroArch builds on the PS3 with more libretro core's (emulators) then ever to add to the RetroArch (frontend) for your Homebrew enabled PS3 powered by either your favoriteCFWorPS3HEN.,There is alot more information on this unofficial port along with various links and details for instructions to setup many of the libretro cores being used. Checkout the officialthread herein the PSX-Place forumsand join the discussion for this unofficial PS3 Port.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T07:04:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Homebrew Revival PS3.1] Featuring "UFO Racer" by ThatOtherDev</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Homebrew_Revival_PS3.1]_Featuring_UFO_Racer_by_ThatOtherDev.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/homebrew-revival-ps3-1-featuring-ufo-racer-by-thatotherdev.36357/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Homebrew_Revival_PS3.1]_Featuring_UFO_Racer_by_ThatOtherDev.jpg">Homebrew Revialis a new feature at psx-place.com where we explore some great projects of the past to educate new user's on some homebrew they may not of known about and also to perhaps sparks some new development in various projects we spotlight in this series, checkout another exclusive psx-place series withThe Power Supplythat has interviewed various developer's who have powered the community (will continue with a new season of interviews soon).First up, we have a great homebrew game that was developed for the Wii and the PS3 by developerThatOtherDev(aka ThatOtherPerson)calledUFO Racer, it's a game with a great foundation and has alot of potential to be a really great homebrew title, but the original developer has not made an update since 2012, However the source code is available, using an early version of PSL1GHT.. Can this be a project that see's a rival in 2022, 10 years after it was released? Checkout some of the source code and the tutorials this developer wrote for the PS3. Also, take note during the source code release of UFO Racer and many other games created by ThatOtherDev. The developer states the following about using the source code: "Make something. There is an appalling, lack of original games being made in the homebrew community and I implore you to take part in changing this." see full statement in tab below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-25T19:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.88.2 Evilnat Cobra (8.3) Custom FirmWare (CFW-CEX) Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.88.2_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.3)_Custom_FirmWare_(CFW-CEX)_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-88-2-evilnat-cobra-8-3-custom-firmware-cfw-cex-released.32057/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.88.2_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.3)_Custom_FirmWare_(CFW-CEX)_Released.jpg">UPDATE 4.88.2:PS3 Developer@Evilnathas updated and released4.88.2Evilnat (Cobra 8.3) CFW ,there is a number of new options like an added File manager, Option to toggle Cobra version, and various other new options detailed in the changlog provided below. Also the developer has provided a number of  fixes and improvements, View all the details of 4.88.2 release of this latest CFW by@Evilnat​</description>
			<creators>Evilnat</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-17T20:02:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update] Apollo Save Tool v1.8.4 released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.8.4_released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-apollo-save-tool-v1-8-4-released.28124/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.8.4_released.jpg">Update v1.8.4 ReleasedOriginal Introduction:PS3 development has been seeing an upkick lately and developer@bucanerohas been one of the developers playing a part. The developer has recently updatedArtemis with new supportand also releasedPKGi (PS3)but now the developer shares a great utility that involves PS3 Game Saves calledApollo, built utilizing the Artemis GUI this homebrew capable of running on CFW and PS3HEN will allow you to Patch & Resign your Game Saves / Download Game Saves / Unlock Game Saves all from the convenience of your PS3 console and not PC tools are required.  Below you can see the release thread from the developer himself: So i'll let@bucanerotake it from here with another great release:​</description>
			<creators>bucanero</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T21:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[PS3 XMB MOD] Now have Individual Gameboots for each emulator / system / homebrew launched</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[PS3_XMB_MOD]_Now_have_Individual_Gameboots_for_each_emulator__system__homebrew_launched.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-xmb-mod-now-have-individual-gameboots-for-each-emulator-system-homebrew-launched.33240/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[PS3_XMB_MOD]_Now_have_Individual_Gameboots_for_each_emulator__system__homebrew_launched.jpg">If you have an exploited PS3 and have been following some of the progress that@DeViL303has made with XMB modding ,then you already know about some of these great project's the xmb mod developer has been working on lately. For those of you new to his work, some recent mods from DeViL303 includeUltimate ToolboxandPixel Art possibilitiesand many more from the past .  Now the developer has taken on enhancing the Gameboot animation when launching content from the PS3's XMB.  Having the same boring sequence for all your content simply won't cut it anymore. Now withwebMAN MODhelping fuel the concept we now have the abilityto set individual Gameboots per contentsuch as bringing back those iconic start-ups from the PS1 and PS2 or having the system startups for your favorite retro roms. Well now you have that ability and more with the latest release from@DeViL303and the latest update to webMAN MOD from@aldostoolsthat helps power the concept the two have been working on the past several weeks seen here in the psx-place forums (here)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T17:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>IRISMAN v4.87.1:   Adds support for mounting Compressed ISO's ( ZIP, RAR or 7-Zip)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_v4.87.1___Adds_support_for_mounting_Compressed_ISO's_(_ZIP,_RAR_or_7-Zip).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/irisman-v4-87-1-adds-support-for-mounting-compressed-isos-zip-rar-or-7-zip.33210/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_v4.87.1___Adds_support_for_mounting_Compressed_ISO's_(_ZIP,_RAR_or_7-Zip).jpg">Following some of the recent advancements made towebMAN MOD,  PlayStation 3 Homebrew developer@aldostoolshas now looked to incorporate a new feature in the PS3 Homebrew(CFW/PS3HEN) fbackup manager known asIRISMAN. It's currently a new and experimental feature added in the recent release ofv4.87.1that provides the backup manager the ability tomount compressed ISO in .zip / .7z / .rar formats.  This features supports thePS3's Internal HDD or a FAT32 external storage device for PS1 / PSP / PS2 / PS3/ DVD / BluRay ISO's..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-16T19:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>webMAN MOD 1.47.34 - New  XMB / Startup enhancements from Aldostools in this update.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.34_-_New__XMB__Startup_enhancements_from_Aldostools_in_this_update..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/webman-mod-1-47-34-new-xmb-startup-enhancements-from-aldostools-in-this-update.32860/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.34_-_New__XMB__Startup_enhancements_from_Aldostools_in_this_update..jpg">DeveloperAldostools, a great developer in the PS3 Community continues the evolution of a tiny but powerful plugin that runs in the background of your CFW or HEN exploited systems that is capable of running background plugins (sprx).  Of course the plugin of mention iswebMAN MOD. This plugin contains alot of functionality alot and can give your exploited console a variety of new features & abilities (see readme tab)., In the latest updates to webMAN MOD the dev has turned his attention to XMB customization adding some functionality that gives user's some new creativity on your PS3's UI (or better known as its XMB), We recently seen the efforts inPixel Artby Aldostools and developer@DeViL303but now with this latest update to wMM we have some additional features for XMB customization.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-16T10:46:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Pixel Art w/ custom imagefont.bin (By DeViL303) for XMB & Pixel Art Editor (by Aldostools)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Pixel_Art_w_custom_imagefont.bin_(By_DeViL303)_for_XMB_&_Pixel_Art_Editor_(by_Aldostools).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pixel-art-w-custom-imagefont-bin-by-devil303-for-xmb-pixel-art-editor-by-aldostools.32861/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Pixel_Art_w_custom_imagefont.bin_(By_DeViL303)_for_XMB_&_Pixel_Art_Editor_(by_Aldostools).jpg">If you follow thePSX-Place Twitter Feed, you may of seen some tweets last week about this project already. The undisputed king of XMB Modding for the PS3@DeViL303,has been making various discoveries and implementing those various idea's as he investigates the inner workings of the XMB and the PS3's User Interface. Along those adventures the developer has discovered a clever way for displaying lines and shapes around text to highlight(see example below)them then aldostool had the idea forPixel Arton the PS3 XMB,  The idea has progressed as developer@aldostoolshas created a new editor for creation of some pixel-art for the PS3(and progressed the tool already with a few updates).Checkout additional details about this latest discovery and trick for your XMB customization. This should open the door to some new eye candy for the XMB like in the coldboot and other entries on the XMB such as titles and other area's were text is displayed with manipulation of the font files..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-6T19:46:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>OPL (Open PS2 Loader) version 1.0 Released !!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OPL_(Open_PS2_Loader)_version_1.0_Released_!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opl-open-ps2-loader-version-1-0-released.32442/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OPL_(Open_PS2_Loader)_version_1.0_Released_!!!.jpg">It is here! Open PS2 Loader ("OPL") 1.0.0!After more than a decade (November 2008) of continuous development and a bit more than5 years since the last official stable release-build(0.9.3 in December 2015),OPL 1.0.0 has been officially released!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-5T09:29:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3UART Script By Mina Ralwasser: Control your ps3 SYSCON via UART</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3UART_Script_By_Mina_Ralwasser_Control_your_ps3_SYSCON_via_UART.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3uart-script-by-mina-ralwasser-control-your-ps3-syscon-via-uart.32422/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3UART_Script_By_Mina_Ralwasser_Control_your_ps3_SYSCON_via_UART.jpg">After the findings made onCXRSYSCON, ps3 developer@M4j0r,known on twitter handle asMina Ralwasserreleased a script that lets you authenticate overANY PS3 syscon (FAT /,SLIM /,SUPERSLIM)and use the privileged commands to do fun stuff on the system. View the psdevwiki links included to see some of the commands that are now possible with this new script release​</description>
			<creators>zecoxao</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-4T21:54:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Toolset v1.1:  4.80 -4.81 (CEX /DEX) + 4.87 (CEX)  Support Added  + New Improved Performance</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_v1.1__4.80_-4.81_(CEX_DEX)_+_4.87_(CEX)__Support_Added__+_New_Improved_Performance.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-toolset-v1-1-4-80-4-81-cex-dex-4-87-cex-support-added-new-improved-performance.32341/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_v1.1__4.80_-4.81_(CEX_DEX)_+_4.87_(CEX)__Support_Added__+_New_Improved_Performance.jpg">Recently developer@bguervilleupdated thePS3 Toolset tov1.1, theFMM (Flash Memory Manager)utility has been updated to support the recent 4.87 OFW release. So, this means you can now install CFW safety from 4.87 OFW directly. All you need is your PS3 Console and an Internet Connection,  Then when you visit the toolset address on your PS3 browser and follow the instructions you can install CFW on your cfw capable models.With this update of v1.1 there has been some changes to the framework which will be useful for an upcoming update in the coming weeks that should give us a new utility in the toolset and of course I am talking about the File Manager, bguerville has also thought about support of some past firmware and has extended support for 4.80 , 4.81 CEX / DEX firmware's with this v1.1 update.  The full changelog can be seen below​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-15T20:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.87.2: Evilnat's CFW (COBRA v8.20) Released   - First COBRA CFW Appears from known PS3 Dev</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.2_Evilnat's_CFW_(COBRA_v8.20)_Released___-_First_COBRA_CFW_Appears_from_known_PS3_Dev.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-87-2-evilnats-cfw-cobra-v8-20-released-first-cobra-cfw-appears-from-known-ps3-dev.32123/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.2_Evilnat's_CFW_(COBRA_v8.20)_Released___-_First_COBRA_CFW_Appears_from_known_PS3_Dev.jpg">UPDATE- noBD / noBT / noBD-noBT version released (for broken consoles)Following the recent release ofSEN Enablerthe developer behind the homebrew app@Evilnat, has decided to create and release a Custom Firmware (CFW) for 4.87. Now,  we have the first CFW appear from a trusted source for4.87. Evilnat's CFW, the custom firmware is powered by theCOBRA 8.20payload, making it what is known as a "Cobra CFW". Cobra CFW payload comes equipped with additional features and abilities out of the gate like background loading of plugins, ISO Support to name a few, over time a "Standard" type cfw can replicate many Cobra features in Mamba,For additional 4.87 release's for Homebrew & CFW, check outthis post herein the psx-place forums:  Then for more information and to see the release thread and discussion checkout the release thread at the link at bottom of the article.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-3T18:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.87 OFW Released,  Joonie follows with 4.87 HFW Release & Evilnat provides 4.87 Spoof</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87_OFW_Released,__Joonie_follows_with_4.87_HFW_Release_&_Evilnat_provides_4.87_Spoof.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-87-ofw-released-joonie-follows-with-4-87-hfw-release-evilnat-provides-4-87-spoof.31960/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87_OFW_Released,__Joonie_follows_with_4.87_HFW_Release_&_Evilnat_provides_4.87_Spoof.jpg">The PS3 has seen anofficial firmware update (4.87)go live today, it appears that the update is nothing more than a maintenance update which is still common for the PS3. As the console has a BluRay player that still needs updates as time goes on. So firmware updates are not a surprise still at this point on the console, What is a surprise (well not really) has been yet another update that has not seen past hacks and tricks patched,For instance, it did not take our friend developer@Joonielong to create his specialHybrid Firmwarewhich is essentially just an OFW with a few subtle tricks that allows a restore a bug used utilized by various PS3Xploit hacks and tricks and installable on OFW.. . While the bug was patched in 4.83 that PS3Xploit utilized (and discovered), Joonie clever trick restored it in 4.84 /4.85 / 4.86 & now 4.87 after Sony's firmware updates. So, the update is more just a small annoyance and an update to the Blu-Ray player.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-15T09:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE v3]  Barulandia (PS3) - A Painting Game by JMGK</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v3]__Barulandia_(PS3)_-_A_Painting_Game_by_JMGK.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v3-barulandia-ps3-a-painting-game-by-jmgk.31605/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v3]__Barulandia_(PS3)_-_A_Painting_Game_by_JMGK.jpg">Update v3 Released (likely Final Version Released)Here is some new development on the PS3 with a new project by developer@JMGKcalledBarulandia, It's a painting game that has been ported to the PS3 (for use on CFW or PS3HEN). The project is written in C utilizing theOpenSDKon the PS3 known asPSl1ght,+SDL 1.3.the projects source code is hosted at github (seen here).This is a great game for that young members of the household picking up a controller and wanting to allow for some creativity.  This homebrew is like a virtual coloring book, where you can add objects from some imagines provided already and choose your custom color's and simply point to colorize your pics. Might not be the most enjoyable thing but if you need a spare few moments to keep the young ones occupied while they are exercising some creativity Barulandia might be a great game for your PS3.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-9T19:40:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>FB Neo RL Plus v2.12 - Support Added for TurboGrafX 16 / PC-Engine / SuperGrafx / ColecoVision</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FB_Neo_RL_Plus_v2.12_-_Support_Added_for_TurboGrafX_16__PC-Engine__SuperGrafx__ColecoVision.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/fb-neo-rl-plus-v2-12-support-added-for-turbografx-16-pc-engine-supergrafx-colecovision.31719/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FB_Neo_RL_Plus_v2.12_-_Support_Added_for_TurboGrafX_16__PC-Engine__SuperGrafx__ColecoVision.jpg">FB Neo RL Plushas been updated to version 2.12 recently, This fork version of@CaptainCPS-XoriginalFB Alpha Retro Loader (RL)has been progressing in the absence of CPS-X by developer@Crystalwho has forked the project last year withFB Neo RL Plus, now residing at version 2.12 this PS3 emulation project powered byPSL1GHT(PS3's OpenSource SDK)has added various support for new systems making this ps3 homebrew a very appealing emulator and frontend for both PS3 CFW and PS3 HEN user's.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-29T18:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>webMAN MOD 1.47.31 -  Various Improvements & Fixes in new update dedicated to bitsbubba</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.31_-__Various_Improvements_&_Fixes_in_new_update_dedicated_to_bitsbubba.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/webman-mod-1-47-31-various-improvements-fixes-in-new-update-dedicated-to-bitsbubba.31608/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.31_-__Various_Improvements_&_Fixes_in_new_update_dedicated_to_bitsbubba.jpg">A very popular PS3 homebrew plugin has been updated by the talented developer behind the plugin we know as@aldostools, as he releases a new version ofwebMAN MODfor your jailbroken PS3(this plugin CFW & PS3HEN compatible).The developer has dedicated this update in honor of our great friend@bitsbubbawhowe recently learned had lost his lifedue to battle lost to cancer..In this update of the plugin Aldostools has alot of improvements, as the plugin itself has several issues that have been fixed as seen in the changelog included below, plus this update contains various changes to thesuite of toolsthat accompanies the plugin with 73 commits being pushed to those tools​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-7T15:00:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE 2] Super Mario 64 Ported to Vita, PSP, PS2, PS3 and PS4!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_2]_Super_Mario_64_Ported_to_Vita,_PSP,_PS2,_PS3_and_PS4!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-2-super-mario-64-ported-to-vita-psp-ps2-ps3-and-ps4.30923/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_2]_Super_Mario_64_Ported_to_Vita,_PSP,_PS2,_PS3_and_PS4!.jpg">Yes, you read right...Super Mario 64 has been ported to the Vita, PSP, PS2, PS3 and PS4(not to be confused with emulated)! You will need to build your own copy of the game using your own legitimately obtained N64 Rom.DoNOTask for links or pre-complied copies on this site, or you will be banned. And definitely doNOTlink to any pre-complied copies!Super Mario 64is arguably one of the greatest video games of all time, and certainly one of the most significant releases of it's time. Personally, I remember having my parents drop me off atToys 'R' Usfor hours at a time, just so that I could sample a little of this incredible 3D platformer on the demo-kiosk before it was officially released to the public. I will never forget whenBabbage'scalled me three days prior to the release of the Nintendo 64, and said I could come pick up my console and copy of Super Mario 64 that day. I spent countless hours mastering the controls, obtaining all 120 stars, and just enjoying the beautifully created worlds.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-6T13:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: October 06th, '20] HW Acceleration (RSX) Project Update by @ReneRebeTM</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_October_06th,_'20]_HW_Acceleration_(RSX)_Project_Update_by_@ReneRebeTM.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-october-06th-20-hw-acceleration-rsx-project-update-by-renerebetm.21370/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_October_06th,_'20]_HW_Acceleration_(RSX)_Project_Update_by_@ReneRebeTM.jpg">UPDATE(June 28th, '20) - Another New Video Released >>>The next PS3 NVidia RSX accelerated X.org steps(Original Article from Nov. 14) Is the PS3 a bit closer to gainingHardware Acceleration (via RSX) in OtherOS (Linux)with a proper driver to enable the GPU chip? We are not there, but we may be getting closer to a reality. Earlier this year (back in April) we detailed some of the progress that the busy devRenéRebehas made with unlocking the potential of the PlayStation 3's RSX chip and now today we have been greeted with a new video and what we can expect with this project as the developer starts to undertake the challenge of further unlocking one more component of the Ps3 hardware,.The developer has alot of videos on other intresting subjects in his diverse  YouTubechannel >>> (Bits and More) <<<  many very informative video's..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-19T18:10:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>"The next big thing[?]" for PS1&PS2-Hacking? A small dive into a bright future via the MC-port!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_next_big_thing[]_for_PS1&PS2-Hacking_A_small_dive_into_a_bright_future_via_the_MC-port!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-next-big-thing-for-ps1-ps2-hacking-a-small-dive-into-a-bright-future-via-the-mc-port.38484/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_next_big_thing[]_for_PS1&PS2-Hacking_A_small_dive_into_a_bright_future_via_the_MC-port!.jpg">The future of PS1&PS2-Hacking has JUST begun!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-8-30T19:22:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Xplorer v2.0 (by Lapy) - Massive Overhaul of this File Manager with v2.0</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Xplorer_v2.0_(by_Lapy)_-_Massive_Overhaul_of_this_File_Manager_with_v2.0.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-xplorer-v2-0-by-lapy-massive-overhaul-of-this-file-manager-with-v2-0.38237/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Xplorer_v2.0_(by_Lapy)_-_Massive_Overhaul_of_this_File_Manager_with_v2.0.jpg">Homebrew developerLapywho is known for his various releases on the PS4 and PS Vita, ranging from Games likeDuck Hunt Remaketo useful Utility apps like PS4 Xplorer /Ps4 App Lockjust to name some of the developer's many projects. Has now turn his attention to a massive overhaul of that popular utility for the PS4, AsPS4 Xplorerhas been upgraded from v1.37 to v2.0 with lots of improvements for this long overdue update, This feature-rich File Manager does all the basic features of a file manager well with some added features like PKG Installation / FTP Support / Translation support for additional languages and much more.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-8-24T21:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Latest Vita Homebrew by @Rinnegatamante includes Flycast (Dreamcast) / Nanosaur / Wordle / Tomb Rai.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Latest_Vita_Homebrew_by_@Rinnegatamante_includes_Flycast_(Dreamcast)__Nanosaur__Wordle__Tomb_Rai..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/latest-vita-homebrew-by-rinnegatamante-includes-flycast-dreamcast-nanosaur-wordle-tomb-rai.38191/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Latest_Vita_Homebrew_by_@Rinnegatamante_includes_Flycast_(Dreamcast)__Nanosaur__Wordle__Tomb_Rai..jpg">PS Vita Developer@Rinnegatamantehas shared several releases in the psx-place forum's over the past week(s), One of the highlights was released in recent days has been a major update toFlycast Vita-(A Sega Dreamcast emulator)for the PS Vita and PlaStation TV (PSTV) . Updating from the initial release ofv0.1 from Jan. 2021tonow v1.0.2with assistance from developer@Bythosfor the latest update.Earlier in the month of August we seen Rinnegatamante with two other ports released here in the forums with:Nanosaur Vita  (A Port of Nanosaur)&Wordle SDL(A clone of Wordle),which are both welcome additions to the Vita collection. Developer rinnegatamante has been busy with various other release's as well over the past few months.    In case you missed some of the other recent releases from@Rinnegatamantelike theTomb Raider 1 & 2 Classic Collectionsport to the Vita, you can also checkout his...​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-5-11T18:24:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4Load (by bucanero) - Load SELF files over Network</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4Load_(by_bucanero)_-_Load_SELF_files_over_Network.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4load-by-bucanero-load-self-files-over-network.37209/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4Load_(by_bucanero)_-_Load_SELF_files_over_Network.jpg">Developer@bucanerohas another release for the PS4 Community, following the recentPS4 Apollo Save Toolport there is another well known PS3 utility for homebrew development that is making it's way to the PS4. Many have known aboutPS3Load/PS3LoadXbuilt fromPSL1GHT.Now for the PS4 there is a new build using the Open Orbis SDK and now we have PS4Load.With this homebrew utility you can load SELF files over a network, which is a handy utility for developer's testing apps throughout the development process. Any tools making it easier for PS4 Homebrew Development is a step forward in the right direction. If you want to start coding your PS4 project be sure to checkout thePS4 Homebrew Development sub-forumhere at psx-place for additional links and resources for developing your next Homebrew Project.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-13T19:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.86 FERROX COBRA (v8.20) Custom Firmware by Alexander</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86_FERROX_COBRA_(v8.20)_Custom_Firmware_by_Alexander.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-86-ferrox-cobra-v8-20-custom-firmware-by-alexander.29103/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86_FERROX_COBRA_(v8.20)_Custom_Firmware_by_Alexander.jpg">As the4.86 OFW updatehas the PS3 developer cranking out updates, we now have a couple Custom Firmware choices for capable PS3 models (to know if your PS3 model can install a CFW, simply load the exploits page ofbguerville PS3 Toolsetin your PS3 Browser, more infohere) Its good having two well known developer's release CFW's since the 4.86 OFW update .First we had@Joonie(of team rebug & hfw developer)release4.86 REBUG LITE, now we have another known Custom Firmware developer in@Alexanderwith the release of4.86 FERROX COBRA.this cobra cfw comes with v8.20 of the payload and contains the usual tweaks in the FERROX brand . For those of you new to this CFW you can view some of the features listed below, the developer offer's some additional XMB mods that can be found in the source link provided below wi6th instructions in how to install.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T20:33:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Movian (Media Center) v5.0.701 by deank - Improved OSD  / HLS bitrate switching Fixed / ...</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_(Media_Center)_v5.0.701_by_deank_-_Improved_OSD___HLS_bitrate_switching_Fixed__....jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/movian-media-center-v5-0-701-by-deank-improved-osd-hls-bitrate-switching-fixed.29075/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_(Media_Center)_v5.0.701_by_deank_-_Improved_OSD___HLS_bitrate_switching_Fixed__....jpg">Developer @deank(who werecently interviewed) has pushed an unofficial update forMovian, a multi-platform project originally developed byAndreas Smas(available on Android, Linux, OS/X, Raspberry Pi and PS3).For those of your that are new to this longstanding PS3 project, it's a robustmedia centerthat comes equipped with additional support for video and audio codecs then what you would find in the PS3's official media player. Various plugins are also available from within the application such as YouTube plugin giving user's an additional option vs the YouTube app .There are other various plugins you can use that provide ranging functions some include themeing /info / other functionalities. Recently deank has releasedv5.0.701and there has been a few cosmetic changes (listed in the changelogs provide) and a couple of  bug fixes provided (see 2nd tab)..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T17:39:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update 2]  PS3 Simple File Manager (by tps)  v0.5.0  Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_2]__PS3_Simple_File_Manager_(by_tps)__v0.5.0__Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-2-ps3-simple-file-manager-by-tps-v0-5-0-released.29071/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_2]__PS3_Simple_File_Manager_(by_tps)__v0.5.0__Released.jpg">Updated(2) v0.5.0 -Provides External Support for manager's (0.4.0) + NTFS Support (v0.5.0)(original Article v0.3.0)The PS3 has no shortage of File Management solutions and alot of choices via homebrew managers like(multiMAN, IRISMAN, ManaGunZ or webMAN / webMAN MOD/ XMB Mods / Apps like Comgenies File Manager, FTP support), but developer@tps(aka lmirel) has released another choice in file management for the PS3, this is currently in the early stages and in the currently labeled as a test release. The file manager itself contains basic features, though with a name likeSimple File Managerthe developer intentions is more then likely focusing on perfecting the basic functions for a Simple File Manager that is easy to use. The ps3 homebrew utility currently supports exFAT and FAT file systems, view the release notes from the developer below​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T17:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Artemis r6.1 - Ps3 Cheat App updated by bucanero</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Artemis_r6.1_-_Ps3_Cheat_App_updated_by_bucanero.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/artemis-r6-1-ps3-cheat-app-updated-by-bucanero.29070/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Artemis_r6.1_-_Ps3_Cheat_App_updated_by_bucanero.jpg">A new update forArtemis(r6.1)has been been released by the developer@bucanerothat included some handy new enchantments for the Cheat System for both PS3 CFW user's and PS3HEN user's ,The app on startup will now check for a new update and process the update automatically, A new plugin selection system has been added, the reason for the implementation is that different version of the plugin run better depending on your console's exploration path (CFW or PS3HEN). For instances on PS3HEN the r5 plugin has performed much better then the later r6 plugin that is suggested for CFW user's. So the app gives you the ability to choose easily which plugin you would like to use. Several other new enchantments make their way in this latest update from a developer(seen the release notes below)that has been impressing lately with some of his PS3 projects likePS3 Apollo Save ToolandPKGi​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T12:13:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>IRISMAN 4.86 + MAMBA v8.3 update by Aldostools</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_4.86_+_MAMBA_v8.3_update_by_Aldostools.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/irisman-4-86-mamba-v8-3-update-by-aldostools.29059/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_4.86_+_MAMBA_v8.3_update_by_Aldostools.jpg">Update v4.86.1:see below for changesDeveloper@aldostoolswhom we recently interviewed inThe Power Supply Series,if you have not seen that interview yet, it can be seen>here<.Now the developer is back with a new update for the popularIRISMAN(AIO) manager for homebrew enabled PS3 consoles to support thenew 4.86 (firmware) update.The developer has not just added new FW support but has also made an update (v8.3) toMAMBApayload(an alternative for Cobra on non Cobra CFWs).This update to MAMBA(that's injected from IRISMAN)has added support for@DeViL303PoC of loading games from a modified Photo Columnthat appears in "Games". There are some other neat MAMBA features, like when you disable CFW syscalls they can be re enabled without a restart to the PS3 Console, This mamba update also provides some other tweaks and enchantments that the developer has outlined in the changelog below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T11:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>XForge PS QRC Tool -  Modifying aspects of the XMB is now easier then ever.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/XForge_PS_QRC_Tool_-__Modifying_aspects_of_the_XMB_is_now_easier_then_ever..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/xforge-ps-qrc-tool-modifying-aspects-of-the-xmb-is-now-easier-then-ever.28804/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/XForge_PS_QRC_Tool_-__Modifying_aspects_of_the_XMB_is_now_easier_then_ever..jpg">We have seen many XMB visual mods published so far in the lifetime of the PS3 but the QRC format (a type of container) has been always problematic, tricky, and very restricted.XForgeis intended to solve all this problems once for all, it allows full freedom torebuild the QRC filesand modify all his contentsThere are many files inside the QRC containers that are candidates to be modified, XForge is the first tool that allows to modify them in a "noob friendly" way, everything made from a intuitive interface with preview panelsSay goodbye to the previous manual methods that required dealing with zlib compressed files or injecting them with a hex-editor to create a custom wave, to replace XMB main icons, to change background wallpapers, etc... XForge supersedes all that tutorials, manuals methods, and tools, there is a long list of features supported by XForge, for more detailed descriptions see the feature list below​</description>
			<creators>pink1</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-4T15:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE 4] PS3 Toolset by bguerville: A powerful collection of tools fueled by new PS3 exploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_4]_PS3_Toolset_by_bguerville_A_powerful_collection_of_tools_fueled_by_new_PS3_exploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-4-ps3-toolset-by-bguerville-a-powerful-collection-of-tools-fueled-by-new-ps3-exploit.28658/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_4]_PS3_Toolset_by_bguerville_A_powerful_collection_of_tools_fueled_by_new_PS3_exploit.jpg">UPDATE FEB 2023 (The domain's of ** ** www.ps3xploit.net  > Domain no Longer owned by team**  (NEW URL = http://ps3toolset.com)  > Domain no Longer owned by team**  (NEW URL =  http://ps3toolset.com and .com are no longer in poccession of the team, A new address will be posted in future release coverage.Update (4) Now supporting 4.86 Fully  & Issue fixed with NAND console's in raresituationsYou may recall a recentarticlerevealing a few exclusive screenshots of bguerville's latest project, now the time has come to introduce the next evolution in PS3 Jailbreaking solutions. ThePlayStation 3 Toolsetby@bguervilleis a new suite of tools, built upon a new PS3 exploitation framework & fueled bya new exploit discovered on the PS3 by the developer.The new exploit (and the toolset project as a whole)is compatible withall PS3 models running 4.82 - 4.86 OFW/HFW/CFWWhileps3xploitteam member's@habibcontinued research and development ofPS3HENfor nonCFW models with assistance from@esc0rtd3w, @bguervillemeanwhile was working on his own research and developing other tools and exploits as you will see with this new PlayStation 3 Toolset, which thorough testing was conducted by@esc0rtd3w(whom we recently interviewed). All the team of talented devs have done some amazing work in the scene in recent years with all thePS3Xploitprojects and that trend continues with this release.ThePS3 toolsetis a project that@bguervillehas been working on for some time,the developer gave us a brief timeline of events since thePs3XploitTools 2.0 framework(flash writer and dumper(s)) that led to this new release (see the timeline section).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-1T20:48:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.86.1 REBUG LITE EDITION + REBUG TOOLBOX 2.03.04 MULTI RELEASED</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86.1_REBUG_LITE_EDITION_+_REBUG_TOOLBOX_2.03.04_MULTI_RELEASED.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-86-1-rebug-lite-edition-rebug-toolbox-2-03-04-multi-released.28809/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86.1_REBUG_LITE_EDITION_+_REBUG_TOOLBOX_2.03.04_MULTI_RELEASED.jpg">UPDATE - Builds for Broken Console's (NoBD / NoBT / RSOD) - See link at bottom of articleIt has been a busy week and especially for the PS3, First we had introduction ofbguerville PS3 Toolset(which introduce a new ps3 Exploit along with some powerful tools). Then we had4.86 Official Firmwaredropped (no exploits patched)  Then  developer@JoonieofTeam Rebugwas quick to release an updatedHybridFirmWare(forPS3HENuser's when an update toPS3HENarrives for those nonCFW models)and now the developer follows that with the release of4.86.1 REBUG LITE Edition,supplying us with one of the best firmware as the first option for 4.86 Custom FirmwareChoices.This CFW comes equipped Cobra 8.2 payload, this payload provides various features some of those highlights include background running plugins, burnt optical media support as well as ISO Support are a few of the many Cobra features included in v8.2. The release details found below detail the various features & patches found in this CFW release. Also it's worth checking out at the download location (link below) the additional info and ":how to" information pertaining to use of REBUG LITE's CFW functionality.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-3-31T19:49:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.87.1 PS3 HFW (Hybrid Firmware) - HFW is helpful for installing PS3HEN on 4.84/4.85/4.86/4.87 FW</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.1_PS3_HFW_(Hybrid_Firmware)_-_HFW_is_helpful_for_installing_PS3HEN_on_4.844.854.864.87_FW.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-87-1-ps3-hfw-hybrid-firmware-hfw-is-helpful-for-installing-ps3hen-on-4-84-4-85-4-86-4-87-fw.23094/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.1_PS3_HFW_(Hybrid_Firmware)_-_HFW_is_helpful_for_installing_PS3HEN_on_4.844.854.864.87_FW.jpg">UPDATE (May, 2022) 4.89 HFW Releasedsee here.Original Article (4.84 HFW - March 2019): Huge News as the PS3 exploit ladder has taken a step up into 4.84 rung, with a new approach tobring back PS3Xploit functionality on 4.84.With a Hybrid Firmware (NOT A CFW) that can be installed onANY MODEL PS3 over any Official Firmware (OFW) version..The only thing this modified firmware essentially does is bring back the patched webkit from OFW 4.82 that was an entry point forPS3Xploit, if you recall when 4.84 was released developers@bguervilleand@esc0rtd3wstated the exploit was not actually patched but rather only the webkit entry used was removed in 4.83+ which rendered the actual exploit unreachable (not patched and could be restored). Now the webkit is back for 4.84 OFW thanks to this new clever magic that has allowed OFW user's to use and install this slightly modified Firmware.​</description>
			<creators>Joonie</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-3-22T12:07:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 04) - Our Guest Today: "PS3(Xploit) Developer @esc0rtd3w"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._04)_-_Our_Guest_Today_PS3(Xploit)_Developer_@esc0rtd3w.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-04-our-guest-today-ps3-xploit-developer-esc0rtd3w.28157/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._04)_-_Our_Guest_Today_PS3(Xploit)_Developer_@esc0rtd3w.jpg">OurInterview Seriesis a full success. Not only can you get anin-depth look behind all the great projectseach of those developer's have worked on in the past and their plans into the future, but also that you can get auseful overview with all important Homebrew Releasesmade by the developer's which willhelp you if you want to get the "Full Experience" from your hacked Console's and devices. For instance, we learned in ourlast Interviewwithdeveloper@aldostoolsthat he created the "Tools Collection" for the PS3, which containsOVER 50+ TOOLS! But while we had interviewed candidates before, who developed their projects after a Hack/Exploit was released, we thought about introducing you to another side of development, namely those, who make it possible for those previously mentioned developers to create their Homebrew running on your hacked devices. And since this mentioned "Tools Collection" contains mainly Tools for yourhacked PS3, it would be only fair to give you an in-depth look with one of the developers of thePS3Xploit-Team, who helpedreanimating you and your PS3with all those great projects. This developer work includes participation in projects like theFlash Writer'sthat provide theability for CFW Installation, then "PS3HEN" which brought Homebrew Support for "nonCFW Models" and also the variety of tools and dumpers released from thePS3Xploit-Team. So, without further waiting, our Guest Today is no other thanDeveloper and long-time Community Member -@esc0rtd3w!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-2T11:15:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.2]  SATURN-FPKG - Convert Saturn Games into PS4 fPKGs!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.2]__SATURN-FPKG_-_Convert_Saturn_Games_into_PS4_fPKGs!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-2-saturn-fpkg-convert-saturn-games-into-ps4-fpkgs.36031/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.2]__SATURN-FPKG_-_Convert_Saturn_Games_into_PS4_fPKGs!.jpg">Following the recentPS4 9.00 Jailbreak, Ps4 developer@Jabuhas a new tool for 9.00 FW , you may remember this developer's previous release's for the PS4 with theps2-fpkgandpsx-fpkgtools that allowed for Ps2 / Ps1 games into a fpkg's  to install on a homebrew enabled PS4.  Following that same concept of injecting custom roms into an fpkg the developer now has a new tool that convertsSega Saturngames into PS4 fpkgs.  With the release of  "Cotton Guardian Force Saturn Tribute"(a Sega Saturn Game)for the PS4, it has equipped a useful Sega Saturn emulator that is said to be based off theSSF emulator.  (According to ZiL0G80) and performing well. Upon seeing this game release is when developer@Jabuinterest peaked and then decided to develop and release the following tool to make running your Sega Saturn games easily on your homebrew equipped PS4 (9.00 FW).....​</description>
			<creators>Jabu</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-1T13:12:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>TeamFAPS Release CEX2DEX for Vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TeamFAPS_Release_CEX2DEX_for_Vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/teamfaps-release-cex2dex-for-vita.36069/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TeamFAPS_Release_CEX2DEX_for_Vita.jpg">CEX2DEX for the PS VitaBy Team Fapps**PSTV & VitaTV planned for future date**​</description>
			<creators>atreyu187</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-12-12T23:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Firmware 9.00 Jailbreak Update (Released)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Firmware_9.00_Jailbreak_Update_(Released).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-firmware-9-00-jailbreak-update-released.35900/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Firmware_9.00_Jailbreak_Update_(Released).jpg">"In this project you will find an implementation that tries to make use of a filesystem bug for the Playstation 4 on firmware 9.00. The bug was found while diffing the 9.00 and 9.03 kernels. It will require a drive with a modified exfat filesystem. Successfully triggering it will allow you to run arbitrary code as kernel, to allow jailbreaking and kernel-level modifications to the system. will launch the usual payload launcher (on port 9020).- via project's official readme"PS4 Firmware 9.00Jailbreak Released(awesome work bychendochap&@Znullptr)​</description>
			<creators>Death_Dealer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-22T22:52:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch (PS2) Progress : New Cores incoming,  gpSP  (GameBoy Advance @ Full-Speed)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(PS2)_Progress__New_Cores_incoming,__gpSP__(GameBoy_Advance_@_Full-Speed).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-ps2-progress-new-cores-incoming-gpsp-gameboy-advance-full-speed.34680/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(PS2)_Progress__New_Cores_incoming,__gpSP__(GameBoy_Advance_@_Full-Speed).jpg">Emulation on a Homebrew Enabled PS2 Console has some great progress in the past year plus,  thanks to still very much active PS2 development scene.  Developer's like@fjtrujyhasported RetroArchto the PS2 about and since then has been adding more and more support for additional emulation with additional libretro core's., Recently the developer previewed some big things that  have been in the pipeline for the  PlayStation 2 port of RetroArch (a multi-system emulator).The PS2 now has a new full speedGBA (GameBoy Advance) emulatorcoming soon with thegpsplibretro corenow running very well @ full speed with the work of@fjtrujyand@davidgfnetcollaborating to bring dynarec to provide a full speed gba emu on the PS2 Console.  Also, the Lutro Core (Lua) improvements are right around the corner as well with some progress being made (seen here) to the core . See some of the progress that has been made on the PS2 port of RetroArch so far in 2021 below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-22T22:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>jfduke3d-vita + jfsw-vita + vitaRTCW released + Doom3 Port in the works</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/jfduke3d-vita_+_jfsw-vita_+_vitaRTCW_released_+_Doom3_Port_in_the_works.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/jfduke3d-vita-jfsw-vita-vitartcw-released-doom3-port-in-the-works.34648/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/jfduke3d-vita_+_jfsw-vita_+_vitaRTCW_released_+_Doom3_Port_in_the_works.jpg">Following theKYUHEN Homebrew Contest, the PS Vita platform has been getting some new homebrew updates and ports from a familiar developer to all in the PS Vita community. Developer@Rinnegatamanterecently provided updates toVitaQuakeIII (v1.0),re3-gta (v1.4)andVitaVoyager (v0.8)Following those updates another project seen an update with the release ofVitaRTCW (v0.4)here in the psx-place forum's,.Now comes the introduction of a few new projects, some have been released already here in the psx-place.com forums,1st up we havefsw-vita - Port of Shadow Warrior Classicand then today we seen the release ofjfduke3d-vita iport of jfduke3d (JonoF's Duke 3D).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-13T22:34:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>KYUHEN  PS Vita / PSTV  Homebrew Contest Winner's have been announced!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__PS_Vita__PSTV__Homebrew_Contest_Winner's_have_been_announced!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/kyuhen-ps-vita-pstv-homebrew-contest-winners-have-been-announced.34499/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__PS_Vita__PSTV__Homebrew_Contest_Winner's_have_been_announced!!.jpg">After a couple months of development of various homebrew projects for the PS Vita and PlayStation TV, theKYUHEN Contestfor the PS Vita has came to a close recently and now the Winners have been Announced (top 3 from each category). The Full Rankings (& Doiwnloads) can be found on the "Result" Page on the Contest's Official Website.  The Contest yielded36 entries(about the same as GekiHEN Contest (39))that spawned across the following 4 categories:Game 1 , Game 2, Utility, Port. No doubt has been some impressive showing and some great projects that are now available on your Homebrew Enabled PS Vita or PlayStation TV(vita tv).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-12T00:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>re3-Vita (Grand Theft Auto III port) updated to v1.4</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3-Vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_port)_updated_to_v1.4.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/re3-vita-grand-theft-auto-iii-port-updated-to-v1-4.34564/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3-Vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_port)_updated_to_v1.4.jpg">Recently the re3-vita (GTA III Port)is back with a new update with the release of version 1.4, this update provided by developer@Rinnegatamante, who has recently updatedVitaQuakeIII (v1.0)&VitaVoyager (v0.8)Has now updated this amazing vita port of re3 with various fixes for all "game-breaking issues affecting previous release's" and v1.4 also includes some features like the inclusion of a Game Manual.  To round out the update we have support for video playback now in v1.4 and instructions in how to get your Video's converted to work on the PS Vita / PSTV, Checkout all the details below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-6T19:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>VitaQuakeIII  v1.0   +  VitaVoyager v0.8:  New updates to vitaGL provides new performance boost !</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaQuakeIII__v1.0___+__VitaVoyager_v0.8__New_updates_to_vitaGL_provides_new_performance_boost_!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vitaquakeiii-v1-0-vitavoyager-v0-8-new-updates-to-vitagl-provides-new-performance-boost.34500/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaQuakeIII__v1.0___+__VitaVoyager_v0.8__New_updates_to_vitaGL_provides_new_performance_boost_!.jpg">Developer@Rinnegatamantedropped by the forums here at psx-place.com to release a couple of new items for the homebrew community.  First up we have an update toVitaQuakeIIIwith the release of version 1.0. This update has provided the port withMultitexturing supportandTexture CombinerWhat this does, is improves performance on the PS Vita and provides support for features like dynamic light that previously has been disabled prior to this update (see video below for a showcase of examples).  In regards to the recentadvancements to VitaGLthe developer states "Expect a branch of releases for idTech3 derivates plus maybe some new idTech 3 derivates ports in the future" be sure to keep a look out in the future here in thepsx-place forumsand @VitaDBfor when those release appear directly fromRinnegatamante.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-10-27T12:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.85.1 REBUG LITE CFW with new COBRA v8.2 Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.85.1_REBUG_LITE_CFW_with_new_COBRA_v8.2_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-85-1-rebug-lite-cfw-with-new-cobra-v8-2-released.26793/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.85.1_REBUG_LITE_CFW_with_new_COBRA_v8.2_Released.jpg">Developer JoonieofTeam Rebughas announced today the latest cfw release (following 4.84.2 rex) of the REBUG brand. This is not the iconic REX flavor of PS3 Custom Firmware, which is a hybrid of dex/cex, In order for the creation of REX, the team is dependent and still in search for file's needed for the creation of REX (4.85 DEX PUP).However, they have theLITE version(a CEX based Cobra CFW) ready to go for4.85 user's seeking a new 4.85 CFW. This is a welcomed update fromTeam Rebugas the4.85 PS3 CFWlandscape has been a bit light in choices (for 4.85). So having the developer's with one of the best name's in Custom,Firmware development is great to see now as an available option.  Also, they have updated the Cobra payload to now version 8.2 & also the Rebug Toolbox has been updated (toolbox addon requires installation in "install package files" pkg is waiting for you there after installing REBUG)  You can checkout all the feature's/patche's in the provided list below for this PlayStation 3 Custom FirmWare and then checkout full details/documentation of the release at rebug.me the official website (direct link found at bottom of article).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-10-13T22:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update] multiMAN 04.85.01 - Official Update from deank adds 4.83-4.85 CFW Support + PS3HEN Support</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_multiMAN_04.85.01_-_Official_Update_from_deank_adds_4.83-4.85_CFW_Support_+_PS3HEN_Support.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-multiman-04-85-01-official-update-from-deank-adds-4-83-4-85-cfw-support-ps3hen-support.26435/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_multiMAN_04.85.01_-_Official_Update_from_deank_adds_4.83-4.85_CFW_Support_+_PS3HEN_Support.jpg">UPDATE04.85.01- ImprovedPS3HENSupport AddedOriginal:Appears that developer@deankhas pushed an official update for the popular PS3 Homebrew known asmultiMAN(or mM).  We have not seen an official updatesince firmware 4.82(albeit from some unofficial modified version, that were not ideal), there was not much of a need for an update since the previous official update of 4.82 worked fine as is on 4.83 /4.84 / 4.85. In that time Sony's changes in 4.8x era of firmware  were minimal and presented little changes for the PS3. The only thing that was missing was firmware detection of 4.83 and greater, as it was impossible for the application to know the offsets of future firmware's. However, deank quietly pushed an update via the applications online update.  This new update provides official support forCFW 4.83 - 4.85which will recognize and properly fix the cosmetic issue and display the new firmware presents.Other then that its the same old classic multiMAN, which is not a bad thing as this was and still is an iconic applications for the PS3. This powerful Homebrew is packed with tons of functionality for your cfw enabled PS3,Regarding support for PS3HEN user's I am not sure as of writing this if this version supports PS3HEN fully,(see 04.85.01 update) nothing is mentioned so we should not assume. On brewology there is an unofficial multiMAN4.84 PS3HEN version (* in previous releases), but not sure how compatible many of the feature are (maybe we could have user's comment below with some feedback regarding ps3hen) PS3HEN user's in general should also realize that many PS3 Homebrew apps were created with CFW in mind. so there can be compatibility issue with some features..Note that ManaGunZ is supporting PS3HEN w/ a special PS3HEN mode that will disable the CFW features.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-10-3T00:03:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Coming Soon] bguerville 's PS3 Toolset</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Coming_Soon]_bguerville_'s_PS3_Toolset.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/coming-soon-bguerville-s-ps3-toolset.26513/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Coming_Soon]_bguerville_'s_PS3_Toolset.jpg">The evolution of PS3 exploration continues as PSX-Place.com own moderator and one of the lead developer's of thePS3Xploit Team@bguervillehas been working on a new project for the PS3 of late and the developer has given me permission to share some of the exclusive details about this upcoming project to be released in the coming weeks. The developer has provided us with various screenshots with short descriptions of the tools. bguerville has been working to perfect his ROP framework and has created a robust API for future development of exploits and hacks on the PS3 withbguerville's PS3 Toolset(name may change in final release(?)). Essentially the project is anextremelyfeature rich & powerful file management system that runs on the PS3's Internet Browser (that has become a great feature for us on the PS3) and does not need any kernel exploits (such as PS3HEN or a CFW installed), however a userland exploit will be needed, this could be achieved by utilizing 4.85 HFW or could possibly be done by another solution as well without the need of HFW,  so there looks to be possibilities for the dev to choose when that time comes upon the initial release,@bguervilletoolset contains many functions and features (as seen in the screens provided below) that will be outlined more thoroughly in the future release. Until then, we are left with a sampling of screenshots from the project, to show what's around the corner. (Also, note the GUI shown is not the final product and simply just a placeholder currently according to the developer, so the released version should look different in terms of eye-candy ). Stay tuned as we will learn more about this project as we get closer to the release.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-9-13T20:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.85 Flash Writer Released (CFW PS3 Models Only) - Now go from 4.85 OFW to 4.85 HFW to a 4.85 CFW</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.85_Flash_Writer_Released_(CFW_PS3_Models_Only)_-_Now_go_from_4.85_OFW_to_4.85_HFW_to_a_4.85_CFW.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-85-flash-writer-released-cfw-ps3-models-only-now-go-from-4-85-ofw-to-4-85-hfw-to-a-4-85-cfw.26209/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.85_Flash_Writer_Released_(CFW_PS3_Models_Only)_-_Now_go_from_4.85_OFW_to_4.85_HFW_to_a_4.85_CFW.jpg">It looks like the4.85 landscapeis starting to take shape now as developer's around the scene have been updated the homebrew, utilities and tools that require updates(not all things require updates)and now thePS3Xploit Teamreleased one of the missing pieces.  TheFlash Writerfor 4.85 HFW has now arose and now you can make the jump from4.85 OFW >>4.85 HFW>> Execute Flash Writer >>> Install a4.85 CFW.This release (utility) is ONLY for PlayStation 3 models thatcan install a Custom FirmWare, if your model can not install a CFW then look atPS3HENas the next best alternative to cfw, which the team has an update around the corner as well (stay tuned for that soon), but back to the Flash Writer, If your are new to the tool that is executed from the PS3 Internet Browser, it simply provides those cfw capable models with the ability to install a Custom Firmware after the tool has done its magic to your console's internal flash. However, you must follow all instructions for a clean installation to avoid any issues during the process on the fully softmod exploit..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-9-11T18:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ManaGunZ v1.36 & v1.37: NEW PS3HEN Support , New Features & 4.85 (CEX) Support by Zar</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ManaGunZ_v1.36_&_v1.37_NEW_PS3HEN_Support_,_New_Features_&_4.85_(CEX)_Support_by_Zar.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/managunz-v1-36-v1-37-new-ps3hen-support-new-features-4-85-cex-support-by-zar.26161/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ManaGunZ_v1.36_&_v1.37_NEW_PS3HEN_Support_,_New_Features_&_4.85_(CEX)_Support_by_Zar.jpg">Developer@Zarmade an update for4.85 firmware(cex) support for the popular ps3 homebrewManaGunZ,  but also late last month the developer made a huge update, that has added many new features to the popular Game Manager that always comes equipped with plenty of other features for your exploited PS3. Not only is this homebrew for CFW any longer, but  since v1.36 ManaGunZ is now both compatible with PS3CustomFirmWare and alsoPS3HEN, also zar did not stop there as there has been tons of new additions (seen in the changelogs provided below) and various fixes/optimizations have been brought forward as well in these recent updates that have emerged from developer@Zar. Checkout all the latest details below surrounding ManaGunZ for the PS3.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-9-11T18:30:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>IRISMAN + webMAN MOD - Updated with 4.85 CEX Support</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_+_webMAN_MOD_-_Updated_with_4.85_CEX_Support.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/irisman-webman-mod-updated-with-4-85-cex-support.26162/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_+_webMAN_MOD_-_Updated_with_4.85_CEX_Support.jpg">Developer@aldostoolsrecently updated two great projects of his with 4.85 firmware (cex)support. When the releases appeared over atbrewology.comthey were added to the 4.85 Update/CFW thread >here< but i wanted to get something up on the mainpage for the two apps as there are staples in the PS3 library of homebrew fame.  For those whom may be new to PS3 homebrew,IRISMANis a Game Manager (aka Backup Manager) that provides many features, While multiMAN / IRISMAN & ManaGunZ are all excellent Game Manager's they are all unique from each other, while all sharing the essentials. So no choice of the three is a bad one, but all 3 are different, IRISMAN is a fork from an earlier PS3 Homebrew Manager called IRIS Manager by Estwald & D_Skywalk but aldostools has taken the foundation of that project to new levels by adding a TON of functionality,.. Which bring us to Aldostools other project ofwebMAN MODwhich is a fork of deank's original webMAN plugin. deank made a spectacular foundation and down right great plugin, but as the scene advanced developer aldostools stepped in with other devs and formed webMAN MOD fork and since that forked spawned developer aldostools has created one hell of a plugin with tons of functionality and great features. This plugin allow offers more features then all Sony Firmware updates combined and that is even close to being a discussion. These are to great projects to explore if you have not.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-9-11T18:24:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Podcast Enabler v1.00 (XMB MOD) - Support for podcast pkgs on XMB</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Podcast_Enabler_v1.00_(XMB_MOD)_-_Support_for_podcast_pkgs_on_XMB.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-podcast-enabler-v1-00-xmb-mod-support-for-podcast-pkgs-on-xmb.26135/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Podcast_Enabler_v1.00_(XMB_MOD)_-_Support_for_podcast_pkgs_on_XMB.jpg">XMB modding developer(@DeViL303)is at it again with a few new discoveries and creative implementations.This time around a simple XML mod takes the spotlight, as it has spawned a useful utility appearing in the XMB.PS3 Podcast Enablerthe latest XMB Mod from@DeViL303, serves as a Proof-of-Concept and the developer is hoping the community helps create some podcast.pkg's themselves. DeViL303 has provided an example podcast pkg to serve as a template for others to use. Currently the mod allows for upto 16 different channels to be displayed on the PS3 XMB. This mod is compatible both with CFW & PS3HEN.  Additional details and Setup Instructions can be found in the release notes below along with a video demonstration.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-9-10T19:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>SYSCON Firmware key is now public (release by zecoxao) - What does it mean?</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/SYSCON_Firmware_key_is_now_public_(release_by_zecoxao)_-_What_does_it_mean.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/syscon-firmware-key-is-now-public-release-by-zecoxao-what-does-it-mean.26148/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/SYSCON_Firmware_key_is_now_public_(release_by_zecoxao)_-_What_does_it_mean.jpg">Developer@zecoxaohas recently released something that the dev has been working on obtaining for 10 years now and that obstacle that has now been cleared is theSYSCON Firmware Keyand zecoxao has now released it to the public. First off we must erase some misconceptions asthis is notgoing to directly lead us to a CFW on nonCFW PS3's anytime soon. As the devstated on twitter"needless and pointless to say that the confusion being created around these keys that they will be useful for cfw on ps3 3k and superslim is a very farfetched idea. unless we have access to the TSOP 78K0R models, we will not be able to obtain anything else" and then when@kozarovvprovided afollow-up question about 3k models herethe developer responded with "don't expect miracles, is all i'm saying".  Now the question (whichwas askedby@DeViL303) "So what can we do with this as of now, what is possible with just this key alone and current knowledge?Then@zecoxaoprovides an explanation seen inthis post(and also seen below). So this is a great feat that has been made, but its still being investigated and something that will need to be explored in the weeks to come to fully understand what we can be uncovered,. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-9-10T11:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RPCS3 (PS3 Emulator) - July 2019 Progress Report - When PC Gamer Dreams come true!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RPCS3_(PS3_Emulator)_-_July_2019_Progress_Report_-_When_PC_Gamer_Dreams_come_true!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/rpcs3-ps3-emulator-july-2019-progress-report-when-pc-gamer-dreams-come-true.26143/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RPCS3_(PS3_Emulator)_-_July_2019_Progress_Report_-_When_PC_Gamer_Dreams_come_true!.jpg">People who play Videogames are living in a satisfied world.Especially in the newest era of Videogames, you have the will to choose from many Consoles and it's Games on the market. But sometimes,choosing the "right" Console can give you some trouble.You can confirm that we live in a Generation of Consoles now, where one Console getstwo or even three different SKU Launches- promising an even better Gaming Experience -within one or two years,several Game Titles arerunning better on "this" console compared to the comptetitonor a specific Game Titlewon't see a release on your Console,you choosed before,at all.Then you have Gamers, who prefers to play their purchased Game Titles on their PC. Sure there are some benefits like you won't have problems about any Restrictions about the Output Resolution or Gameplay Framerates, mentioned before. But it can't help you when a Game Title sees a"Console-only"-Release.Luckily there is a solution for this problem.As you know, we present you the newest Progress Report from theGreat Team behindRPCS3and this months one shows thatmore and more Game Titles, which never saw a Release for PCs are getting a better compatibility from time and time,including that one Game TItle whereyou have to ride with your horse through the wide steppes of America in it's Western era of time,which many PC Gamers still waits for a PC Release today.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-8-31T11:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>SEN Enabler (v6.2.3 ): 4.85 Spoofing for PSN Access + 4.85 COBRA (cex) CFW Support by Evilnat</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/SEN_Enabler_(v6.2.3_)_4.85_Spoofing_for_PSN_Access_+_4.85_COBRA_(cex)_CFW_Support_by_Evilnat.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/sen-enabler-v6-2-3-4-85-spoofing-for-psn-access-4-85-cobra-cex-cfw-support-by-evilnat.25966/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/SEN_Enabler_(v6.2.3_)_4.85_Spoofing_for_PSN_Access_+_4.85_COBRA_(cex)_CFW_Support_by_Evilnat.jpg">Following the recent4.85 System Updateon the PS3, developer's around the community have been making the rounds for maintenance updates and 4.85 Solutions. Luckily for the community Sonydid not even attempt to patch the exploits(Hybrid Firmware)brought to us in firmware 4.84. However some apps need updates, we have seen developer@Evilnatpush a useful update forSEN Enabler (homebrew app also in plugin form). This update (for cfw users) adds a new Spoofer for 4.84 cfw (& lower) , also4.85 COBRA CFW (cex)support has been added in the v6.2.3 release. The spoofing feature allows your 4.84 Custom Firmware (not ps3hen supported) to connect to PSN, by using a little trickery to fool the PS3 server's to thinking your 4.84 console(or lower)is a 4.85 console.USE AT YOUR RISKas anything related to PSN and exploited system can have a potential risk for a PSN ban, its not a guaranteed ban but likely if your using the console in a way that an official one would not be used, some research and theories suggest that spoofers can raise the potential ban risk on PSN but like anything with PSN and your exploited PS3 nothing is for sure or known. plenty have used them with no issue and many have blamed the spoofers for the ban (no one is certain why a psn ban occurs).. This app will also disable your CFW Syscalls (a temporary disabling of CFW features until the next console boot) which has also theorized to helpprevent banson PSN, so its always a good idea to use an app that has CFW syscall disabling if you do decide to connect to PSN (SEN Enabler,PSNpatch&webMAN MODall have the cfw disabling feature present and can be activated), but using your console the same way as an OFW one is about the best advice and practice to use for not getting a ban, Respect the network!!!!!​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-17T08:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.6] Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas now playable on the PS Vita / PSTV with new port</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.6]_Grand_Theft_Auto_San_Andreas_now_playable_on_the_PS_Vita__PSTV_with_new_port.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-6-grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-now-playable-on-the-ps-vita-pstv-with-new-port.32975/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.6]_Grand_Theft_Auto_San_Andreas_now_playable_on_the_PS_Vita__PSTV_with_new_port.jpg">UPDATE v1.6 Released:Another great release for the PS Vita community arrives today.. As many of you already know in recent daysGrand Theft Auto: III(updated to v1.3)& also just the other dayGrand Theft Auto: Vice Citywas ported by the PS Vita / PS TV from@Rinnegatamante/ @Theflow0,Now these devsTheflow/ Rinnegatamante&aapall had a role in development ofGrand Theft Auto:San Andreasto the PS Vita(& PSTV) ,where theflow states on release"We gave the PS Vita THE game it always deserved. GTA: SA with authentic PS2 atmosphere on-the-go" .Unlike the previous two vita ports in the GTA Series that used a reversed-engineered engine, GTA:SA-Vita is using the mobile version (apk-android)) of the game and adding a "wrapper", like what we saw inMax Paynevita Port recently released utilizing thekubridge.skprx. The wrapper/port contains many custom hooks and patches to get the game running well on the PS Vita. You will need to provide the Game FIles yourself, the game can be purchased on the Play Store.Also developer Rinnegatamante has provided a configuration app to configure various settings, easily.  Also, as usualMVG. has a great video, as the dev/youtuber is covering this release as he was one of the tester's,  that is for sure worth checking out for some additional insight.. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-14T10:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>reVC-vita (GTA: Vice City) port for PS Vita  /  PSTV by @theflow0  & @Rinnegatamante Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/reVC-vita_(GTA_Vice_City)_port_for_PS_Vita____PSTV_by_@theflow0__&_@Rinnegatamante_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/revc-vita-gta-vice-city-port-for-ps-vita-pstv-by-theflow0-rinnegatamante-released.32928/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/reVC-vita_(GTA_Vice_City)_port_for_PS_Vita____PSTV_by_@theflow0__&_@Rinnegatamante_Released.jpg">The PS Vita / PlayStation TV devices are getting another great release for the Vita Homebrew Scene. Iconic developer's in the Vita Community who have done so much for the platform in@Rinnegatamanteand developer@TheFlow, have continued on another great project in a follow-up toreIII-Vita (A port of GTA III to the PS Vita).The devs have now successfully ported anotherGrand Theft Autoclassic in the series & are now ready for release as they dropreVC-Vita - A Port of Grand Theft Auto: Vice Cityto the Vita Community.reVC-Vitais a fully reversed - reimplementation ofGTA: Vice City using thelibrw engine(a full and open source version of RenderWare Graphic Engine),like we seen used inre3-Vita. In order to play this release you need to own a copy of the PC Game (can be purchased on Steam) and move needed game fiies, additional information can be viewed in the installation notes​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-6T10:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 08) - Our Guest Today: "well-known multiconsole Developer @CelesteBlue123"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._08)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well-known_multiconsole_Developer_@CelesteBlue123.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-08-our-guest-today-well-known-multiconsole-developer-celesteblue123.30581/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._08)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well-known_multiconsole_Developer_@CelesteBlue123.jpg">Since you liked ourpast Interviews so farwhere we talk withDevelopers across all PlayStation consoles- and especiallyone of our latest Interviewwhere wetalked with a Developer who tinkers with various consoles simultaneously- we thought about to do this again. Today's Guest is alsowell-known for releasing various Homebrew Applicationsmainly for thePlayStation Vita, but also for thePlayStation 4. In fact in this interview, you will learn not only what he released so far for both consoles, but alsowhat it means to develop for the PS Vita as for the PS4 in terms of "connectivity" for both consoles. But what does this mean exactly? Maybe you can remember back when the PS4 got presented back at E3 2013,Sony itself tried to make it more tasty for you not only to play with their newest Home Console, but also with the previous released PS Vita as well, especially when using the official "Remote Play" Feature. While this didn't worked quite well for Sony to be honest -although even the newest PS4 Games today still supports "Remote Play"- this Developer took a similar approachto understand the "connectivity" between both consoles but in terms of hacking them and to create useful Homebrew for it. And his results are impressive as well. So without further ado,our Guest Today is well-known multiconsole Developer@CelesteBlue.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-29T14:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Max Payne Mobile Ported to PS Vita / PS TV</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Max_Payne_Mobile_Ported_to_PS_Vita__PS_TV.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/max-payne-mobile-ported-to-ps-vita-ps-tv.32752/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Max_Payne_Mobile_Ported_to_PS_Vita__PS_TV.jpg">While the Vita scene patiently awaits the arrival of the nextGrand Theft Autoports rumored to be released soon, we have a surprise release coming fromfgsfdsandTheFloW. Today, the mobile version ofMax Paynehas been ported to the PS Vita / PS TV. Thanks to the recent release of TheFloW'skubridge, developers are able to bypass dynamic recompilation limits that had been previously set in place. You can take a look at the full list of credits in our dedicated resource thread (linked below) to see all the developers who helped in bringing this game to the PS Vita / PS TV.Similar to other ports,in order to enjoy Max Payne Mobile on your PS Vita / PS TV, you will need to obtain the legitimate assets from your own copy of the game. You will find detailed instructions on how​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-23T10:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 07) - Our Guest Today: "well known multi-console Developer @mathieulh"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._07)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well_known_multi-console_Developer_@mathieulh.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-07-our-guest-today-well-known-multi-console-developer-mathieulh.28915/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._07)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well_known_multi-console_Developer_@mathieulh.jpg">OurInterview Seriesconducted various Interviews with Developers, who worked either mainly for the PlayStation 3 or for the PlayStation 4 (andone time for the PlayStation Vita). But sometimes, there are well-known Developers who say to themselves thatworking on one console isn't enough for me. In fact the older readers will probably remember back when the magical 3.55 Firmware got hacked for the PS3 how many useful stuff we saw from the PSP Development for instance,which led into daily new releases and achievements for both consoles. As you can see, working on several consoles within the same "family" can be an advantage. So when we thought about new candidates for this series of interviews, we quickly recognized that if you want to interview a"multi-console" Developer, then there is someone, where his name will come immediately in every mind. In fact ournext candidate worked with so many both home and portable consoles in the past and still in present days, we would probaly need a complete new sub-section inside the forum to list all of his releases and achievements he did for the community.And you can't imagine how difficult it was for us "questioners" how to begin this interview with such a great person or how to find the right words for him. :P But somehow we think we managed it quite good and this time we have even aspecial question for our female readersout there. ^^ This man needs no more introduction.Here is our guest today, Developer@mathieulh!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-7T13:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Dreamcast Emulation Comes to PS Vita and PS TV with flycast-vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dreamcast_Emulation_Comes_to_PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_with_flycast-vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/dreamcast-emulation-comes-to-ps-vita-and-ps-tv-with-flycast-vita.32450/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dreamcast_Emulation_Comes_to_PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_with_flycast-vita.jpg">Earlier this year, there were plans put into motion by@Rinnegatamanteto bringDreamcast emulation to the PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV. Nowadays, the nameRinnegatamanteshould synonymous with Vita ports, as he is responsible for multiple major ports, all which come with a high level of polish. You will have to look no further than the work he andThe FlOwhave performed in bringingGrand Theft Auto IIInatively to the scene, and all the advancements that have been made since the initial release. Or, watch as the continually evolvingDaedalus X64(Nintendo 64 emulator) make leaps and bounds in allowing us to enjoy all of our favorite N64 games once again. Simply put, take a look at ourVita Homebrewsection of the forum to see all the hard work and amazing releasesRinnegatamantehas been providing for us.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-6T17:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita Monthly Release Round Up - December 2020</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Release_Round_Up_-_December_2020.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-monthly-release-round-up-december-2020.32439/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Release_Round_Up_-_December_2020.jpg">We are officially almost one week into the year of 2021, and in this article we are going to look back and see what goodies the month of December brought your PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV. Whether you were naughty or nice, the Vita scene developers still supplied us all with another round of amazing projects and updates. Let us take a glimpse at some of the gifts we received last month.@Rinnegatamantewas Santa's number one helper, with a total of four updates this holiday season, including three homebrew games (SuperMarioWar,mertious, andDstroy) and an update to the super popular Nintendo 64 emulator,Daedalus X64. Another one of Santa's elves, the developer by the name ofisage(a.k.a.sarcasticat), also game us two updates to existing homebrew games (Open Fodder Vita, anddevilutionX) as well as one new one (REminiscence). There were many, many more homebrew games and homebrew applications released this month, so please take a look at the list below for all the details. It is also important to mentiondevnoname120updated hisVitabrightplugin, as well as added a new user application (Vitabright Lut Editior) to allow us to easily adjust the...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
	</spc>
</nsx>