<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<nsx anno="" lt-id="131" min-sys-ver="1" rev="1093" ver="1.0">
	<spc anno="csxad=1&amp;adspace=9,10,11,12,13" id="33537" multi="o" rep="t">
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2026-1-31T12:15:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>qCFW - Arrives to Slim (2500-3000) & SuperSlim (4000-NOR) PlayStation 3 Models</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/qCFW_-_Arrives_to_Slim_(2500-3000)_&_SuperSlim_(4000-NOR)_PlayStation_3_Models.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/qcfw-arrives-to-slim-2500-3000-superslim-4000-nor-playstation-3-models.49533/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/qCFW_-_Arrives_to_Slim_(2500-3000)_&_SuperSlim_(4000-NOR)_PlayStation_3_Models.jpg">UPDATE (Feb. 20) -PS3HEN 3.4.2 Open Beta: Test #1 Released- (Forum Link)UPDATE (Feb. 20) -qCFW updated(forum link)   --qcfw-20260220-release(github link)UPDATE (Feb. 17) -qCFW and Future potential(Forum Thread)by@aomsin2526>here<UPDATE (Feb. 13) -BadWDSD/qCFW + HW Flasher/NoBT(Forum Thread)UPDATE (Feb. 11) -qCFW files have been temporary removed from github by the developer, due to a bug, see@aomsin2526's post >here<  & >also here<UPDATE (Feb. 3)-PS3HEN v3.4.1 (STABLE) has now been releasedby@esc0rtd3w, graduating from the 3.4.1 BETA builds. (Note: v3.4.1+ is required for qCFW)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-8-3T22:44:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>[BD-JB-1250] New Exploit (bluray) for PlayStation 4 supporting upto 12.50 firmware from Gezine</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[BD-JB-1250]_New_Exploit_(bluray)_for_PlayStation_4_supporting_upto_12.50_firmware_from_Gezine.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/bd-jb-1250-new-exploit-bluray-for-playstation-4-supporting-upto-12-50-firmware-from-gezine.48161/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[BD-JB-1250]_New_Exploit_(bluray)_for_PlayStation_4_supporting_upto_12.50_firmware_from_Gezine.jpg">The PlayStation 4 has new BluRay exploit that supports upto 12.50 Firmware. Thanks to the efforts of developerGezine,who has released the source code and helloworld.iso to complete the proof of work of this recent exploit for the PS4.  Below you can see the readme for the project. Also some community reaction and comments about the new exploit for the PS4 from Abkarino & Modded Warefare dives into the exploit in one of his latest video attached​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-6-24T01:48:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>{CFW Release} 4.92.2 Evilnat  Custom Firmware (w/ Cobra v8.5) - Includes: CEX/PEX/D-PEX) + noBD/BT</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{CFW_Release}_4.92.2_Evilnat__Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_-_Includes_CEXPEXD-PEX)_+_noBDBT.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/cfw-release-4-92-2-evilnat-custom-firmware-w-cobra-v8-5-includes-cex-pex-d-pex-nobd-bt.47798/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{CFW_Release}_4.92.2_Evilnat__Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_-_Includes_CEXPEXD-PEX)_+_noBDBT.jpg">After a successful Open Beta for 4.92.2, PlayStation 3 CFW developer@Evilnathas nowOFFICIALLYupdated hisEvilnat Custom Firmware'sfor the PS3 to version4.92.2,A number of new changes and options have been added in this release for your PS3 FAT and Early Slim models capable of installing a CFW PUP.Various patches to the CFW have been made as well as various new additions to theCobra Payload, Also theXAI Pluginwas not left out, as there are some new options one being a newNew Overclock menuhas been introduced to the firmware.  Now we no longer need a dedicated PUP to change overclock settings, it can be done directly on the XMB. All the details and changes can be found in Evilnat's release note's found below and also in the link provided at the bottom.​</description>
			<creators>Evilnat</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-6-14T04:10:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ProtoPwn (Protokernel Exploit by pcm720) -  Now all PS2s are hackable via MemoryCard  (MILESTONE)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ProtoPwn_(Protokernel_Exploit_by_pcm720)_-__Now_all_PS2s_are_hackable_via_MemoryCard__(MILESTONE).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/protopwn-protokernel-exploit-by-pcm720-now-all-ps2s-are-hackable-via-memorycard-milestone.47708/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ProtoPwn_(Protokernel_Exploit_by_pcm720)_-__Now_all_PS2s_are_hackable_via_MemoryCard__(MILESTONE).jpg">Breaking Newsin the PS2 Scene,as a NEW MemoryCard Exploit for Protokernel PS2s (SCPH-10000, SCPH-15000, and DTL-H10000(S)) just got released!!!It took 25 years to reach this point, butNOW ALL PS2s including ALL special models(Arcade, Prototype, Debug, Consumer-model, "special/custom builds")can load Homebrew WITHOUT DISCS!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-5-10T13:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>BadWDSD HW Exploit - With new powerful qCFW for PS3 Slim & SuperSlim NOR models on the horizon</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/BadWDSD_HW_Exploit_-_With_new_powerful_qCFW_for_PS3_Slim_&_SuperSlim_NOR_models_on_the_horizon.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/badwdsd-hw-exploit-with-new-powerful-qcfw-for-ps3-slim-superslim-nor-models-on-the-horizon.47475/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/BadWDSD_HW_Exploit_-_With_new_powerful_qCFW_for_PS3_Slim_&_SuperSlim_NOR_models_on_the_horizon.jpg">Update (Jan. 30) -@esc0rtd3whas releaseda new beta, while not the FINAL (yet) it is the first beta HEN with the qCFW installer.Update (Jan. 29) -@aomsin2526has released thefirst public version of qCFWfor the BadWDSD exploit, now we still needPS3HEN 3.4.1 (FINAL)for the qCFW installer to utilize the qCFW release.Update (Jan. 15)-@aomsin2526has provided a new progress report,qCFWis nearing a public release.>>>LinkUpdate (Dec. 8) -@aomsin2526(aka chattrapat_s / kafuu)has provided an update for the project, in the form of a "To-Do" list for the project, with some reported progress like"qCFW is done"see full post>>> LinkUpdate (Sept. 11) -New video demonstration and details "qCFW will be based on Evilnat PEX from now on. This means both CEX and...​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-31T22:32:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN w/ Linux & Overclocking Support? BadHTAB A hardware-software based hypervisor (lv1) exploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_w_Linux_&_Overclocking_Support_BadHTAB_A_hardware-software_based_hypervisor_(lv1)_exploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-w-linux-overclocking-support-badhtab-a-hardware-software-based-hypervisor-lv1-exploit.47282/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_w_Linux_&_Overclocking_Support_BadHTAB_A_hardware-software_based_hypervisor_(lv1)_exploit.jpg">UPDATE 4 - (May 2 / June 9):@esc0rtd3whas created a fork of the BadHTAB Exploit with some changes such as an "Automatic reboot if glitch crashes ps3" feature among other changes to make it easier for testing the new exploit.(June 9)- ReadMe Updated in link belowUPDATE 2 & 3:Now, not only Linux but also Overclocking on PS3HEN is now possible w/BadHTAB exploit&PS3HEN (beta builds)that are currently supporting the exploit. This is still considered an experimental exploit & features soUse at your Risk.  (See update tabs/links) for additional details and information on these advancements for the PlayStation 3.Original Article: Could Linux Support onPS3HENbe a reality with new exploit? Yes, and also other features but itsnot going to be for everyone. There is a newProof of Conceptreleased for the PS3 that has been implemented byKafuu(@aomsin2526)usingGeohot'soldhtab glitchon PS3HEN.  Developer@zecoxaofirst started posting about this idea and the concept in Jan. of 2023 here inthe forum'sand has shared various thoughts and progress, with the latest progress being Kafuu's implementation.BadHTABis ahardware-softwarebased hypervisor (lv1) exploit,The exploit has a very low success rate of (5-10%)as GameOS has a much smaller "glitch window". As the readme states this not meant "for daily driver, it is for user's withskill and patienceonly.".​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-15T20:55:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PlayStation Home Revived and Enhanced by Home Laboratory!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_Home_Revived_and_Enhanced_by_Home_Laboratory!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/playstation-home-revived-and-enhanced-by-home-laboratory.47120/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_Home_Revived_and_Enhanced_by_Home_Laboratory!.jpg">Home is back on the XMB in 2025! Download and Play just like it was originally!I am pleased to present our extensive work on reviving and enhancingPlayStation Home. Led by AgentDark447, our team has developed an advanced, open-source iteration of this server platform, significantly expanding its capabilities beyond the original. Below, I outline the project’s scope, technical advancements, and access instructions for those interested in exploring or contributing.​</description>
			<creators>DeViL303</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-15T10:34:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Toolset (by bguerville) with 4.92 support has been released.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_(by_bguerville)_with_4.92_support_has_been_released..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-toolset-by-bguerville-with-4-92-support-has-been-released.47135/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_(by_bguerville)_with_4.92_support_has_been_released..jpg">If you have a Custom Firmware compatible PlayStation 3 Model and are running 4.92 Official Firmware and need to Jailbreak for the first time or if you updated your previous CFW installation by mistake to 4.92 OFW. Then the PS3 Toolset will exploit your PS3 via the console's web browser and visitingps3toolset.com website(see tutorial tab), then once the process has completed you will be able to install a Custom Firmware (such as 4.92 Evilnat)  once again or for the first time.Your PlayStation 3 model must be able to install a CFW, these would be all the FAT models PS3 and Early production Slim Models. The easiest and most effective ways to determine if your PS3 can install a cfw​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-9T11:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.92 Littlebalup's DUALBOOT firmware Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Littlebalup's_DUALBOOT_firmware_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-92-littlebalups-dualboot-firmware-released.46963/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Littlebalup's_DUALBOOT_firmware_Released.jpg">Since the4.92 firmware updatethings have been flowing out from the community in response. We have seenPS3HEN (& hfw) releasedfor 4.92 and we have seenEvilnat updateand release his cfw collection on 4.92. Now developer@littlebalupdrops by the forumand release the latestDualBoot (DB) firmwareto support 4.92 firmware.This release for Custom Firmware user's is a very useful firmware, if you use PSN still and do not want to go online with a modded system and risk a potential ban. As it allows you to use an Official firmware that can re-install a CFW without having re-exploiting the console with the toolset or flash writer. See full details in @littlebalups release notes about the Dualboot firmware concept.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-9T11:24:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.92 Evilnat Custom Firmware (w/ Cobra v8.5) Released - CEX,PEX,D-PEX,DEX builds</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Evilnat_Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_Released_-_CEX,PEX,D-PEX,DEX_builds.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-92-evilnat-custom-firmware-w-cobra-v8-5-released-cex-pex-d-pex-dex-builds.46961/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.92_Evilnat_Custom_Firmware_(w_Cobra_v8.5)_Released_-_CEX,PEX,D-PEX,DEX_builds.jpg">UPDATExai_plugin:New Overclocking Tools (change on the fly) / New ps2netemu improvements added.Following the4.92 firmware updatedeveloper's from around the community have been updating various projects. This time around PS3 CFW developer@Evilnatdrops by the forumand leave's us with a suite of ps3 custom firmware's that support 4.92 firmware.  4 Flavor's (CEX, PEX, D-PEX & DEX) are available for 4.92 Evilnat CFW, depending on your console/taste, all builds are equipped with theCobra v8.5 payloadto provide expanded feature set over Standard CFW's.If you are already on PS3 CFW, updating is a breeze, you just need to install the new CFW PUP file via the official USB Method and you will be on Evilnat's latest release. If you have updated to 4.92 OFW you will have to wait, as you will have re-exploit your ps3 console to allow for a Custom Firmware installation once again. The good news is that developer@bguervilleshould be rolling out a new update soon for the PS3 Toolset that support 4.92 firmware.  The offline tool CFW Flash Writer may take longer for the community to update it, but we hope to see an update for that tool soon as well.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-11-29T23:30:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Ben Heck again tinkering with Nintendo PlayStation (SNES-CD)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Ben_Heck_again_tinkering_with_Nintendo_PlayStation_(SNES-CD).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ben-heck-again-tinkering-with-nintendo-playstation-snes-cd.11748/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Ben_Heck_again_tinkering_with_Nintendo_PlayStation_(SNES-CD).jpg">You may recallBen Heck's Nintendo PlayStation Teardownand repairs to the very rareNintendo PlayStation (SNES-CD) Prototype. Now the hardware genius is back at the Retro Gaming Expo in Portland Oregon meeting again the Nintendo PlayStation and attempting to repair the disc drive with hopes to play the homebrew game "Super Boss Gaiden"  for the SNES-CD platform  . The SNES-CD  is a symbol of Nintendo's and Sony's failed partnership back in the early 90's with a product even though never released to the public changed the course of gaming history.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-10-29T11:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>GS/PAR Enhancement CD Track Ripper (TRAXTRACT) by krHACKen</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/GSPAR_Enhancement_CD_Track_Ripper_(TRAXTRACT)_by_krHACKen.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/gs-par-enhancement-cd-track-ripper-traxtract-by-krhacken.11379/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/GSPAR_Enhancement_CD_Track_Ripper_(TRAXTRACT)_by_krHACKen.jpg">We seen several things released bykrHACKenfor thePS2 communitythe past several days ago inID DUMPER&SCEDoormat_NoME Rel.3 Source Code Release, but the developer also has another release useful for the PlayStation 1 Community.TRAXTRACTaGS/PAR Enhancement CD Track Ripperwhich extracts various elements from a unique file system used in  GameShark  & Action Replay CDs .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-7-25T19:11:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Ben Heck's - Nintendo Sony PlayStation (Prototype Teardown & Repair ) Video 2 of 2 Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Ben_Heck's_-_Nintendo_Sony_PlayStation_(Prototype_Teardown_&_Repair_)_Video_2_of_2_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ben-hecks-nintendo-sony-playstation-prototype-teardown-repair-video-2-of-2-released.10046/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Ben_Heck's_-_Nintendo_Sony_PlayStation_(Prototype_Teardown_&_Repair_)_Video_2_of_2_Released.jpg">Last week we showed you a bit ofnews about the rare Nintendo Sony PlayStation (SNES-CD ), as we seen developer's released aa very nice working homebrew gamefor the system and have aworking emulator, but also we told you about a recent Teardown & Repair that Ben Heck was in the process of doing on the Ben Heck Show. At the time there was just the first of the two part edpisode but recentlyBen Heckdives into the repair process of the prototype console that is EXTREMELY rare and is a true symbol of gaming history. As this was the launch that really brought Sony to the forefront of the gaming market as we all know the Nintendo and Sony relationship went Sour and the CD add-on for the SNES was a distant dream, but Sony's work as we know  it as today did not go to waste​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-7-17T02:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>A new Homebrew Game for SNES CD-ROM (Nintendo PlayStation) + Ben Heck's  Prototype Teardown Video</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/A_new_Homebrew_Game_for_SNES_CD-ROM_(Nintendo_PlayStation)_+_Ben_Heck's__Prototype_Teardown_Video.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/a-new-homebrew-game-for-snes-cd-rom-nintendo-playstation-ben-hecks-prototype-teardown-video.10013/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/A_new_Homebrew_Game_for_SNES_CD-ROM_(Nintendo_PlayStation)_+_Ben_Heck's__Prototype_Teardown_Video.jpg">By now most in the community know the history of the Nintendo PlayStation  (the prototype CD Add-on for the SNES) and how the relationship went sour between Sony and Nintendo and thus lead to Sony going on their own and creating the iconic Sony PlayStation we now know as today . This week there has been several unrelated pieces of news for the Nintendo PlayStation  (kind of a big deal as we do not hear much about this system due to its rarity and the fact it was never in production. If it had it might of changed gaming history as we know it today. Would there be a Sony PlayStation 4 now, or would it of been the Nintendo PlayStation 4. What kind of handheld would we of seen if the two stayed together or would they bound to split at some point?​</description>
			<creators>kozarovv</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-3-7T18:43:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PSXNET Library - Connect the PlayStation 1 (w/ Serial Port) to the Internet using a Raspberry Pi</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSXNET_Library_-_Connect_the_PlayStation_1_(w_Serial_Port)_to_the_Internet_using_a_Raspberry_Pi.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/psxnet-library-connect-the-playstation-1-w-serial-port-to-the-internet-using-a-raspberry-pi.9340/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSXNET_Library_-_Connect_the_PlayStation_1_(w_Serial_Port)_to_the_Internet_using_a_Raspberry_Pi.jpg">PlayStation 1 developerLameGuy64who you may recall as the developer of a fantastic PS1 homebrew gameMarilyn in the Magic Worldwhile the developer recently announced the cancellation of that game he did release the source code for anyone willing to continue the project. Now the PS1 developer is back with a new release along with the Source Code provided.PSXNETshows another use to the Serial Port on those early PlayStation 1 models, as PSXNET with help from a Raspberry Pii give the console the ability to connect to the internet​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-2-25T11:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ePSXe Has Been Updated For Windows - Version 2.0 Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ePSXe_Has_Been_Updated_For_Windows_-_Version_2.0_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/epsxe-has-been-updated-for-windows-version-2-0-released.9255/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ePSXe_Has_Been_Updated_For_Windows_-_Version_2.0_Released.jpg">ePSXe has since been updated as far back as January 2015. This update, which is over a year in the making, brings the PlayStation emulator to version 2.0. This version is said to be compatible with newer versions of Microsoft Windows. Those been from Windows Vista and up. The update introduces language support for English, Spanish, Japanese and Italian. Other​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-4T21:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Marilyn in the Magic World: PS1 Homebrew Game Cancelled & Source Code Released)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Marilyn_in_the_Magic_World_PS1_Homebrew_Game_Cancelled_&_Source_Code_Released).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/marilyn-in-the-magic-world-ps1-homebrew-game-cancelled-source-code-released.3838/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Marilyn_in_the_Magic_World_PS1_Homebrew_Game_Cancelled_&_Source_Code_Released).jpg">Marilyn in the Magic Worldis a homebrew game for the PlayStation 1 created by developerLameGuy64,its a rather impressive project that has unfortunately ran its course as the developer months ago(i know a bit late)announcedthat he has decided to stop development of the project, The Game Developer did provide his source code of the project for any participants who would like to continue the project. This quite an impressive PS1 Homebrew Games, if you have not tried it out yet give it a go. Last version i tested did work on the PS3 and various emulators.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-12-2T20:00:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ROLL BOSS RUSH v1.10a: An impressive PS1 Homebrew Game by isufje</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ROLL_BOSS_RUSH_v1.10a_An_impressive_PS1_Homebrew_Game_by_isufje.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/roll-boss-rush-v1-10a-an-impressive-ps1-homebrew-game-by-isufje.3641/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ROLL_BOSS_RUSH_v1.10a_An_impressive_PS1_Homebrew_Game_by_isufje.jpg">PlayStation 1 (PS1) homebrew developerisufjehas updated one of most impressive looking homebrew games created for the PS1(ROLL BOSS RUSH). The graphics and gameplay are very impressive for a homebrew game., This game with each update continuous to add new elements to the game as it evolves. Which that trend has continued, as the release of this update has bumped the project to version 1.10a. The developer has informed me that this update was only tested on the PC using the ePSXe emulator and if anyone can lend a hand to test on real hardware the developer would appreciate those efforts to help identify any issues that may need repair.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-11-25T19:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PSIO - PlayStation 1 Hardware now Available for Limited Pre-Orders</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSIO_-_PlayStation_1_Hardware_now_Available_for_Limited_Pre-Orders.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/psio-playstation-1-hardware-now-available-for-limited-pre-orders.3599/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSIO_-_PlayStation_1_Hardware_now_Available_for_Limited_Pre-Orders.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-9-23T20:30:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PSXclassic's working with decompressed ISOs (w/ Tutorial)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSXclassic's_working_with_decompressed_ISOs_(w_Tutorial).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/psxclassics-working-with-decompressed-isos-w-tutorial.3014/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSXclassic's_working_with_decompressed_ISOs_(w_Tutorial).jpg">Additional Research from PS3 developerzecoxaoas the dev shares some information & findings fromZeroTolerancepertaining toPSXclassics working with decompressed ISOs. Great news coming for the PlayStation 1 gamer on CFW enabled PS3 consoles. See full details and the tutorial in the various quotes from the source (PlayStationHAX) link provided:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-30T10:41:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Movian M7 (by deank)  - "libav" swapped for "ffmpeg"  & slight name change</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_M7_(by_deank)__-_libav_swapped_for_ffmpeg__&_slight_name_change.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/movian-m7-by-deank-libav-swapped-for-ffmpeg-slight-name-change.42453/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_M7_(by_deank)__-_libav_swapped_for_ffmpeg__&_slight_name_change.jpg">Developer@deankwho has been continuing development of the (modded version) of the original media center that started on the PS3(now runs on Android, Amazon Fire Stick, MacOS ,Windown ,Linux  & Raspberry pi). The media center originally was named "Showtime" on the PS3 but later renamed to "Movian" by the original developerAndreas Omanyears ago.Since that time, we have not seen the official project do much in recent years (currentlyhome siteis down as of writing), but developer deank has been keeping the project alive and evolving (see changelogsover at brewologyfor all archived changes). One of the biggest changes you will see within Movian-M7 compared to older version, is the change from the older (abandoned) "libav" video decoders/parsers to the current "ffmpeg" that was just replaced in the recent M7 update . This should improve compatibility and make for a more up-to date and versatile media player for all supported platforms including the PS3.Also, deank  has made a quick stop in the forum's, then to see a reported issue and provided a fix (seen here) that is now present in v7.0.2​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-27T22:41:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.06] Itemzflow (PS5) -  Homebrew & Game Manager with PS5 game Support</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.06]_Itemzflow_(PS5)_-__Homebrew_&_Game_Manager_with_PS5_game_Support.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-06-itemzflow-ps5-homebrew-game-manager-with-ps5-game-support.42429/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.06]_Itemzflow_(PS5)_-__Homebrew_&_Game_Manager_with_PS5_game_Support.jpg">Following the release ofetaHEN(AIO Homebrew Enabler for the PS5)last month from@lightingModz.Now, the release ofItemzFlowhas arrived for the PlayStation 5 from developer @ligthingmodz. Originally thisHomebrew & Game Managerwas released on the PS4, but the developer has made a special Christmas Release now bringing the homebrew app for the PS5 that is handy for managing and preserving your personal backups.(JUN 27, 2024) Update: v1.06has been released with new improvements and features.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-19T21:10:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Alien Resurrection - (A cheat code to unlock boot disc feature for backups)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Alien_Resurrection_-_(A_cheat_code_to_unlock_boot_disc_feature_for_backups).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/alien-resurrection-a-cheat-code-to-unlock-boot-disc-feature-for-backups.42354/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Alien_Resurrection_-_(A_cheat_code_to_unlock_boot_disc_feature_for_backups).jpg">This is a very interesting discovery or rather disclosure from one of the developer's of the PlayStation 1 (PS1) gameAlien Resurrection(Martin Piper) who had reached out to YouTuberMVGwho has been given permission to disclose something that has always been there all this time in the game, but needed a cheat code to unlock the ability to run backups on a stock retail PS1, acting as a boot disc for the swap method.  MVG details the process here in this video:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-11-5T08:21:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.8B] etaHEN - AIO Homebrew enabler for the PS5</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.8B]_etaHEN_-_AIO_Homebrew_enabler_for_the_PS5.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-8b-etahen-aio-homebrew-enabler-for-the-ps5.42050/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.8B]_etaHEN_-_AIO_Homebrew_enabler_for_the_PS5.jpg">The PlayStation 5 has an early Christmas gift this year as developerLighting Modshas releasedetaHEN - AIO Homebrew Enabler for the PlayStation 5 (PS5), Currently there is not much homebrew to launch for the PS5, but the developer hasported his PS4 HB Store to the PlayStation 5and thanks to theability to run PS4 fpkgs on the PS5, there is various PS4 homebrew that can run such as some of Lapy's homebrew games.Update (Aug. 12):New update has been released by @ligthingmods, now bringing etaHEN to v1.8B, See changelog tab below or guthub links for latest changes and features incorporated in this update and other updates since its release that has jump started the PS5 community. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-10-14T10:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Celebrating Nine Year's of PSX-Place.com</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Celebrating_Nine_Year's_of_PSX-Place.com.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/celebrating-nine-years-of-psx-place-com.41855/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Celebrating_Nine_Year's_of_PSX-Place.com.jpg">The psx-place.com website celebrates its 9th birthday on this day, originally opening in2014onOctober 14to the public. The site remains a pillar in the PlayStation Homebrew / Hacking community, thanks to the tremendous developer & user support that has blessed our forums. The past 9 years we have witnessed some amazing things in these forums, we have seen idea's and theories mature into full blown exploits and projects, we have seen developer's share and bounce idea to each other and even teamed up, which have spawned and improved many projects/aspects in the community. We have seen many developer's choose the psx-place forum to host their Release/Support threads for their projects. It has been a destination for developer's and user's to learn more about the community and even take part in it. Truly a place where people can come together for a common goal and that goal has been getting the most out of our beloved PlayStation devices.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-8-12T07:19:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Athena - A performant JavaScript Runtime Environment for the PS2</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Athena_-_A_performant_JavaScript_Runtime_Environment_for_the_PS2.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/athena-a-performant-javascript-runtime-environment-for-the-ps2.41393/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Athena_-_A_performant_JavaScript_Runtime_Environment_for_the_PS2.jpg">AthenaEnv (JavaScript-Runtime) and the bright future of development on the PS2!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-8-1T20:30:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>FuHEN Contest Submissions - The Four of Us Are Dying / Beat2x / Zik-Zak Vita / Sonic SMS 3 Timelines</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FuHEN_Contest_Submissions_-_The_Four_of_Us_Are_Dying__Beat2x__Zik-Zak_Vita__Sonic_SMS_3_Timelines.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/fuhen-contest-submissions-the-four-of-us-are-dying-beat2x-zik-zak-vita-sonic-sms-3-timelines.41305/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FuHEN_Contest_Submissions_-_The_Four_of_Us_Are_Dying__Beat2x__Zik-Zak_Vita__Sonic_SMS_3_Timelines.jpg">The FuHEN - PS Vita Contest is underway and we have already 4 submissions that have been approved for entry: We have seen 3 Game Ports submitted and also a new Original Game for the PS Vita.  If you have not heard yet, there is a a PS Vita Contest that is currently on going and the submission period for projects is fromJuly 22nd, 2023  September 22nd, 2023You can learn more about the contest prizes, rules and the submissions process at the official website.We have an ambitious Original Game that has been in the making for awhile and aims to provide AAA graphics and effects. The gameplay is still early but the developer has big plans for the game called "The Four of us are Dying".byJosh Allen / noradninja.this game is a Silent Hill 2/Alan Wake style survival horror game.In the Game Port category we have seen 3 entries approved we have seen PS Vita legendary developer@Rinnegatamanteprovide three projects the first being"Beat2k" (A Dance Dance Revolution Clone)and also the developer has entered"Zik-Zak Vita"which is a great game that testes your reaction time getting through each level , Then@Rinnegatamantealso submitted "Eldritch" is a first person shooter inspired by games like roguelikes, immersive sims, and H. P. Lovecraft.  Then tou round out the first wave of entries we have seen developer@MDashKenter"Sonic SMS 3 Timelines"which is port of a fan made Sonic game that takes Sonic on a new adventure.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-6-21T17:22:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Future of the PlayStation 2 Internal Hard Drive by Berion</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Future_of_the_PlayStation_2_Internal_Hard_Drive_by_Berion.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-future-of-the-playstation-2-internal-hard-drive-by-berion.40924/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Future_of_the_PlayStation_2_Internal_Hard_Drive_by_Berion.jpg">The Future of the PlayStation 2 Internal Hard DriveWe have recently started 2023, and the so-called PlayStation 2 console scene is surprisingly still doing well, yes, even better than ever before and better than on not one newer platform! And one of the leading projects that anyone interested can mention without a long moment's hesitation isOpen PS2 Loader- the successor to HDLoader and USB Advance, a program used to run games from USB, i.Link (FireWire), MX4SIO (a reader for e.g. SDXC in the Memory Card slot), the local network and the internal hard drive, whose operation is still stuck in the darkness of the Middle Ages.Before I get into specifics, it's worth recalling what the current, extremely exotic logical disk structure that Sony designed looks like, and which is supported by every software written to date that supports theinternalhard drive. Without understanding the APA, you won't understand the idea of a hybrid drive. It is only later that I will discuss the concept of building a Frankenstein with something modern, familiar, while providing a full or residual layer of compatibility.​</description>
			<creators>Berion</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-5-4T20:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>(Update) Baryon Sweeper: Unbrick PSP 1000, 2000, 3000 /PSP Slim 04g, 07g, 09g/ PSP Street 11g  model</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(Update)_Baryon_Sweeper_Unbrick_PSP_1000,_2000,_3000_PSP_Slim_04g,_07g,_09g_PSP_Street_11g__model.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-baryon-sweeper-unbrick-psp-1000-2000-3000-psp-slim-04g-07g-09g-psp-street-11g-model.32503/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(Update)_Baryon_Sweeper_Unbrick_PSP_1000,_2000,_3000_PSP_Slim_04g,_07g,_09g_PSP_Street_11g__model.jpg">Update (May - 2023):Now PSP models Slim 04g, 07g, 09g models, & the PSP Street 11g model are now supported >> See Details from@zecoxaoin the post via>>this link<<Original Article (Jan 2021): For more than ten years PSP-3000 owner's have been used to the fact that their device couldn't be restored (unbricked) at home. Many fear the brick as if it's the worst nightmare that could ever happen when experimenting with your device.  Even worse in 2021, now because warranty for all PSPs are over, so bricked later (psp) models go either for parts or are doomed to dust in boxes and drawers they'd never return from... that is, if this thread didn't appear with the release ofBaryon Sweeper R1:^)​</description>
			<creators>zecoxao</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-4-1T01:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN v3.2.2 - New Additions/ Fixes & Backported Firmware's  Support from Team PS3Xploit.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_v3.2.2_-_New_Additions_Fixes_&_Backported_Firmware's__Support_from_Team_PS3Xploit..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-v3-2-2-new-additions-fixes-backported-firmwares-support-from-team-ps3xploit.40129/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_v3.2.2_-_New_Additions_Fixes_&_Backported_Firmware's__Support_from_Team_PS3Xploit..jpg">Update 4/25/2023: PS3HEN 3.2.2 has been released. Check the changelog for details.We have seen a lot of developer's back in the fold after the4.90 official firmware updatethat hit the PlayStation 3 several weeks ago. We seen a couple weeks ago developer's@Joonieand@esc0rtd3wof thePs3Xploit Teamupdate Ps3HEN to v3.2.0, now we have a new update with the release of v3.2.1..Ps3HENis a Homebrew Enabler that is an alternative exploit to custom firmware (cfw) for models that can not install a CFW. unlikecustom firmwareon the ps3, Ps3HEN has the ability to run on all ps3 model's, while many feature that are in CFW can be found in PS3HEN it does not completely replicate the CFW experience so if your PS3 has the ability to run a CFW that is the better route, but Ps3HEN is a very powerful and capable exploit. See a CFW vs Ps3HEN comparison>here<for a rundown of feature's.In the update v3.2.1, there has been a number of changes and added support to Ps3HEN.@Jooniehas released a backport ofHFW (hybrid firmware) for 4.83, this was done as Ps3HEN has provided support for 4.83 FW, plus 4.84 DEX firmware is also now supported.  There has been a number of other supported firmware and various other changes in the payload and plugin to PS3HEN, Plus this fixes the wMM bug that was creating freezing issue in v3.2.0.  See latest changelogs provided below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-11T09:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: Version 1.13] Autoplugin 2 released by @TheheroGAC & ONElua Team!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_Version_1.13]_Autoplugin_2_released_by_@TheheroGAC_&_ONElua_Team!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-version-1-13-autoplugin-2-released-by-theherogac-onelua-team.28370/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_Version_1.13]_Autoplugin_2_released_by_@TheheroGAC_&_ONElua_Team!.jpg">Unlike the PlayStation 4 with it's slow Homebrew Content, thePlayStation Vitaalways saw a strong Content of Homebrew and other useful Plugins, which makes your life easier with a hacked PS Vita.In fact, we still see today new plugins released for this Handheld Console, no matter if you want toOverclock your PS Vitato make your favourite Games even better performing or if you just need some handy tools like analways running FTP Server, where you can transfer your favourite Games and other Homebrew Releases on-the-fly. But installing them wasn't always a easy task and there was even a risk when adding them manually, which could harm your complete System when pressing a wrong button. In short, it was always elaborate to install all those wonderful Plugins bit by bit. But luckily we hadAutopluginfor this in the past and today, well-known Developer@thehero_together with theONElua Teamare releasingVersion 2, where not only you can now seewhich Plugins you have already installed on your PS Vita, but also that you can nowdirectly download all translations inside of Autoplugin without any need to quit the Appas it was necessary before. Together with more new Features you can see down below and with a new Design,Autoplugin 2will make your life even more easier now for both you and your PS Vita!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-4T14:00:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: v0.19.1] GE Patch - PSP Native Resolution on the PS Vita for Some Games</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v0.19.1]_GE_Patch_-_PSP_Native_Resolution_on_the_PS_Vita_for_Some_Games.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v0-19-1-ge-patch-psp-native-resolution-on-the-ps-vita-for-some-games.31106/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v0.19.1]_GE_Patch_-_PSP_Native_Resolution_on_the_PS_Vita_for_Some_Games.jpg">Last time we reported news aboutThefl0w(a.k.a. TheFloW, a.k.a. TheOfficialFloW, a.k.a. Flow The Bounty Hunter), he had disclosed hisPS4 Kernal Exploit for OFW 7.02. Today, we now are receiving news that he may be on the bounty chase again, this time going after PSP native resolution on the PS Vita and PS TV. Thecurrent bounty for bringing native resolution to PSP games on the PS Vita is at $1,535.00.GE Patch Pluginmay just be the start of that, which was released asversion 0.1just earlier today (andversion 0.11was just released hours ago)Currently, PSP games being ran on the Vita are actually being run through an ME (media engine) which is emulated by the Vita's CPU. As it stands, most games only run at half the resolution of actual PS Vita games, with the exception of a couple of GTA titles where full resolution has been achieved (from none other than TheFloW himself:see here). The end goal is for the PS Vita to to emulate the GE GPU and redirect the drawing to the Vita's GPU, allowing for full native resolution.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-28T17:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Get Your ADRENALINE Pumping with TheFloW - eCFW Updates</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Get_Your_ADRENALINE_Pumping_with_TheFloW_-_eCFW_Updates.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/get-your-adrenaline-pumping-with-theflow-ecfw-updates.31292/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Get_Your_ADRENALINE_Pumping_with_TheFloW_-_eCFW_Updates.jpg">There has been a lot of commotion going on in the Vita scene regardingplaying PSP games at native resolution on your PS Vita and PS TVs. We first saw the release ofTheFloW'sGePatch, which essentially isa plugin that would allow for some PSP games to utilize the Vita's hardware to run at a much better resolution. Since the initial release, we have already seen11 updatesin less than half a month; with each new releaseadding more support and bringing us closer to the dream of playing all of our PSP games at full native resolution.Along with the updates of GePatch,TheFloWalso released an updated version of the custom PSP firmwareAdrenalinefor end-user consumption,bringing even more compatibility to his incredible plugin. Following close behind this release,there has been a flood of updated Adrenaline related applications, plugins and tools,​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-16T17:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Vita Release Round-up for August & September</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Vita_Release_Round-up_for_August_&_September.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vita-release-round-up-for-august-september.31162/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Vita_Release_Round-up_for_August_&_September.jpg">Well, it has been a month since our lastPS Vita and PS TV Mid-Month Release Roundup, and the Vita Scene shows no signs to slowing down anytime soon (just take a look at our ever-growingPS Vita Resource Section). Another 30 days has brought us many, many more releases for end-users and developers alike. Just in these past several weeks we have seen many amazing releases for the Vita, including: the long awaited release of a plugin (GePatch) thatallows for some PSP games to run in full resolutionon the PS Vita, aport of Super Mario 64that is not to be confused with an emulator, and speaking of emulators we saw somemajor updates and improvements to the Nintendo64 emulator(Daedalus X64), and the list continues on and on.This month I decided to do a little something different, and I have created a couple of great looking lists for our members and readers. If you take a look below, you will see I have put together a collection ofAugustandSeptemberreleases inchronological order. Next to the name of each release, you will find abrief descriptionof what the release is or does. And if you click theNAMEof the release, you will be taken to a page that includes more information and downloads about that specific homebew. Also, be sure to flip...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-15T15:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>GrapheneCt's Recent PS Vita / PS TV Releases</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/GrapheneCt's_Recent_PS_Vita__PS_TV_Releases.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/graphenects-recent-ps-vita-ps-tv-releases.31138/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/GrapheneCt's_Recent_PS_Vita__PS_TV_Releases.jpg">After creating last month'sPS Vita and PS TV Mid-Month Release Roundup, I noticed another developer had been hard at work releasing several PS Vita and PS TV projects. I figured I should spotlight all the tremendous applications and pluginsGrapheneCthad been producing last month, both for end-users and developers.Let's take a look at his releases, starting with the beginning of August. TheHonRipper v1.0plugin was released August 1st, and itallows users to extract data from .MNH (Marlin-Hon format) booksthrough the PS Vita Sony Reader application; and on the same day,libShellAudiov1.1 was released for developers, which is aPS Vita library that can be used in system and music applications to play audio files using SceShell resources. On August 2nd, we saw two releases:MARISA Highlow PS Vita v2.1, aport of a homebrew highlow card game; andBGFTP v3.1, an application that allows forBackground FTP transferto and from your PS Vita and PS TV. Seven days later on August 9th, we saw two releases for developers:libvitaSASv1.01, aSceSas and libaudiodec library wrapperthat supports system mode applications; andlibvita2d_sysv1.22, a2D library for the PS Vitathat​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-6T11:33:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Daedalus X64 (N64 Emulator) v0.5:  Adds Network Loading of Roms / Shaders / Overlay / Playtime count</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Daedalus_X64_(N64_Emulator)_v0.5__Adds_Network_Loading_of_Roms__Shaders__Overlay__Playtime_count.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/daedalus-x64-n64-emulator-v0-5-adds-network-loading-of-roms-shaders-overlay-playtime-count.31044/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Daedalus_X64_(N64_Emulator)_v0.5__Adds_Network_Loading_of_Roms__Shaders__Overlay__Playtime_count.jpg">Following theprevious update(v0.4),developer@Rinnegatamantehas unleashed a massive update to theDaedalus x64 (Nintendo 64) emulatortoday for the PS Vita / PlayStation TV  With the project now maturing toversion 0.5with this latest update the dev has provided various fixes and new implementation of featuresas well (some seen already if you keep up with the nightly builds.).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-8-16T12:52:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita and PS TV Mid-Month Release Roundup</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_Mid-Month_Release_Roundup.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-and-ps-tv-mid-month-release-roundup.30809/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_Mid-Month_Release_Roundup.jpg">It has been a busy month for the Vita scene with several homebrew game releases, a couple of ports, a few of updates to some handy utilities, and even a new version of everyone's favorite GBA emulator. To start off, on the last day of July, we saw an update toJoel16'sVITAlbum, bringing the multi-format picture viewer up to version 1.10; and we also saw the much anticipated release ofVitaHEX Games'The Hallway v1.0, the P.T. clone that now features a puzzle that allows you to escape the house. In the first few days of August, endrift releasedmGBA v0.8.3, which brought many bugfixes and stability improvements to this Gameboy Advance emulator. That same weekNorthfearreleasedGemRB Port for PS Vita, which allows users to play several games designed for Bioware's Infinity Engine. The following daySKGlebareleasedYAMT v4.0. a great tool for SD2VITA users that now supports PSVSD and USB, plus allows you to format your SD/USB to TexFAT directly from your Vita.  Just in this last week alone, we saw four releases: a port ofBaldi's Basics Classicby hat,Crekeryopreleased v0.65 of his manga/comic reader...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-6-28T17:33:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE-4] Daedalus X64 v.0.4 by @Rinnegatamante ---  N64 emulation is progressing on the PS Vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE-4]_Daedalus_X64_v.0.4_by_@Rinnegatamante_---__N64_emulation_is_progressing_on_the_PS_Vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-4-daedalus-x64-v-0-4-by-rinnegatamante-n64-emulation-is-progressing-on-the-ps-vita.29064/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE-4]_Daedalus_X64_v.0.4_by_@Rinnegatamante_---__N64_emulation_is_progressing_on_the_PS_Vita.jpg">UPDATE4- v0.4 Released -SeeCHANGELOGtab for latest changesDaedalusX64 (n64 emulator for the PS Vita / PSTV powered by VitaGL)has recently been updated to version 0.4 by port developer@Rinnegatamantethis update was a jam-packed update, that includes various improvements to the overall experience. The project has been incorporating news features to the emulator and also improving emuation performance as more games issue are being resolves. The emulator still has more work but with that said there is many games that are working very well and provide a great gameplay experience. The emulator contains an internal compatibility list that seeks online updates and plus there is a web-based page for this port's compatibility also.  Also,  developer@Rinnegatamantehas recently decided to move his release's thread here in the psx-place forums. So we would like to welcome another great developer in the scene to our community and hope to continue to see this progress of this port and other projects by the developer in the future, Now there are many changes in v0.4 and your just going to have to checkout the v0.4 changelog provided to get a grasp on al the work being done on this project.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-6-3T22:22:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update(3) - New Plans (flycast)] ReDream (DreamCast Emulator)  porting to VITA from Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update(3)_-_New_Plans_(flycast)]_ReDream_(DreamCast_Emulator)__porting_to_VITA_from_Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-3-new-plans-flycast-redream-dreamcast-emulator-porting-to-vita-from-rinnegatamante.29914/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update(3)_-_New_Plans_(flycast)]_ReDream_(DreamCast_Emulator)__porting_to_VITA_from_Rinnegatamante.jpg">Update (3) See latest progress of this port in development for the PS Vita and PlayStation TVUPDATE(1):Change in port plans, view new details listed bellow in marked updateDeveloperRinnegatamantewhomwe recently interviewedin thePower Supply Seriesand who has ported a Nintendo 64 emulator to the PS Vita / PS TV recently with the release ofDeadalus x64.Has another emulation project that many will be excited for as this shapes up, especially after seeing the great progress of d x64's n64 emulation so far to this point. NowReDream(A Sega Dreamcast Emulator) is being ported to the PS Vita as a libretro core running onRetroArch (Vita),so far its early progress, However, it looks like potential could be untapped from a developer who has some experience with the platform and emulation porting.. So far its rendering of graphics are in the early stages, so stay tuned for more progress reports from the developer..Until then tell us in the comments below what is your favorite Dreamcast Game or memories from SEGA last hardware adventure.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-1-20T08:29:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Universal Media Server v9.2.0 Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Universal_Media_Server_v9.2.0_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/universal-media-server-v9-2-0-released.27904/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Universal_Media_Server_v9.2.0_Released.jpg">Universal Media Serverhas now been updated and matured tov9.2.0by theUMS team, lead by developerSubunk.TheUPnP / DLNA&HTTP/S Media serverworks on yourPS Vita / PlayStation TV,  PlayStation 3 (PS3)andPlayStation 4 (PS4)and a tons of other devices you may own(see tab below for all devices supported)This is an extremely well built project that has been in development for years now and continues to evolve and grow with the dedication from the UMS development team. This utility will run on many operating systems and will connect to your supported devices to stream your personal collections of media (audio/video)  via your locally connected network. See many details included below and also at the UMS official website we have linked below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-6T19:46:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>OPL (Open PS2 Loader) version 1.0 Released !!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OPL_(Open_PS2_Loader)_version_1.0_Released_!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opl-open-ps2-loader-version-1-0-released.32442/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OPL_(Open_PS2_Loader)_version_1.0_Released_!!!.jpg">It is here! Open PS2 Loader ("OPL") 1.0.0!After more than a decade (November 2008) of continuous development and a bit more than5 years since the last official stable release-build(0.9.3 in December 2015),OPL 1.0.0 has been officially released!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-5T09:29:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3UART Script By Mina Ralwasser: Control your ps3 SYSCON via UART</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3UART_Script_By_Mina_Ralwasser_Control_your_ps3_SYSCON_via_UART.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3uart-script-by-mina-ralwasser-control-your-ps3-syscon-via-uart.32422/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3UART_Script_By_Mina_Ralwasser_Control_your_ps3_SYSCON_via_UART.jpg">After the findings made onCXRSYSCON, ps3 developer@M4j0r,known on twitter handle asMina Ralwasserreleased a script that lets you authenticate overANY PS3 syscon (FAT /,SLIM /,SUPERSLIM)and use the privileged commands to do fun stuff on the system. View the psdevwiki links included to see some of the commands that are now possible with this new script release​</description>
			<creators>zecoxao</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-4T21:54:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 Toolset v1.1:  4.80 -4.81 (CEX /DEX) + 4.87 (CEX)  Support Added  + New Improved Performance</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_v1.1__4.80_-4.81_(CEX_DEX)_+_4.87_(CEX)__Support_Added__+_New_Improved_Performance.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-toolset-v1-1-4-80-4-81-cex-dex-4-87-cex-support-added-new-improved-performance.32341/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_Toolset_v1.1__4.80_-4.81_(CEX_DEX)_+_4.87_(CEX)__Support_Added__+_New_Improved_Performance.jpg">Recently developer@bguervilleupdated thePS3 Toolset tov1.1, theFMM (Flash Memory Manager)utility has been updated to support the recent 4.87 OFW release. So, this means you can now install CFW safety from 4.87 OFW directly. All you need is your PS3 Console and an Internet Connection,  Then when you visit the toolset address on your PS3 browser and follow the instructions you can install CFW on your cfw capable models.With this update of v1.1 there has been some changes to the framework which will be useful for an upcoming update in the coming weeks that should give us a new utility in the toolset and of course I am talking about the File Manager, bguerville has also thought about support of some past firmware and has extended support for 4.80 , 4.81 CEX / DEX firmware's with this v1.1 update.  The full changelog can be seen below​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-15T20:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.87.2: Evilnat's CFW (COBRA v8.20) Released   - First COBRA CFW Appears from known PS3 Dev</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.2_Evilnat's_CFW_(COBRA_v8.20)_Released___-_First_COBRA_CFW_Appears_from_known_PS3_Dev.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-87-2-evilnats-cfw-cobra-v8-20-released-first-cobra-cfw-appears-from-known-ps3-dev.32123/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.2_Evilnat's_CFW_(COBRA_v8.20)_Released___-_First_COBRA_CFW_Appears_from_known_PS3_Dev.jpg">UPDATE- noBD / noBT / noBD-noBT version released (for broken consoles)Following the recent release ofSEN Enablerthe developer behind the homebrew app@Evilnat, has decided to create and release a Custom Firmware (CFW) for 4.87. Now,  we have the first CFW appear from a trusted source for4.87. Evilnat's CFW, the custom firmware is powered by theCOBRA 8.20payload, making it what is known as a "Cobra CFW". Cobra CFW payload comes equipped with additional features and abilities out of the gate like background loading of plugins, ISO Support to name a few, over time a "Standard" type cfw can replicate many Cobra features in Mamba,For additional 4.87 release's for Homebrew & CFW, check outthis post herein the psx-place forums:  Then for more information and to see the release thread and discussion checkout the release thread at the link at bottom of the article.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-3T18:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.87 OFW Released,  Joonie follows with 4.87 HFW Release & Evilnat provides 4.87 Spoof</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87_OFW_Released,__Joonie_follows_with_4.87_HFW_Release_&_Evilnat_provides_4.87_Spoof.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-87-ofw-released-joonie-follows-with-4-87-hfw-release-evilnat-provides-4-87-spoof.31960/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87_OFW_Released,__Joonie_follows_with_4.87_HFW_Release_&_Evilnat_provides_4.87_Spoof.jpg">The PS3 has seen anofficial firmware update (4.87)go live today, it appears that the update is nothing more than a maintenance update which is still common for the PS3. As the console has a BluRay player that still needs updates as time goes on. So firmware updates are not a surprise still at this point on the console, What is a surprise (well not really) has been yet another update that has not seen past hacks and tricks patched,For instance, it did not take our friend developer@Joonielong to create his specialHybrid Firmwarewhich is essentially just an OFW with a few subtle tricks that allows a restore a bug used utilized by various PS3Xploit hacks and tricks and installable on OFW.. . While the bug was patched in 4.83 that PS3Xploit utilized (and discovered), Joonie clever trick restored it in 4.84 /4.85 / 4.86 & now 4.87 after Sony's firmware updates. So, the update is more just a small annoyance and an update to the Blu-Ray player.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-15T09:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE v3]  Barulandia (PS3) - A Painting Game by JMGK</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v3]__Barulandia_(PS3)_-_A_Painting_Game_by_JMGK.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v3-barulandia-ps3-a-painting-game-by-jmgk.31605/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v3]__Barulandia_(PS3)_-_A_Painting_Game_by_JMGK.jpg">Update v3 Released (likely Final Version Released)Here is some new development on the PS3 with a new project by developer@JMGKcalledBarulandia, It's a painting game that has been ported to the PS3 (for use on CFW or PS3HEN). The project is written in C utilizing theOpenSDKon the PS3 known asPSl1ght,+SDL 1.3.the projects source code is hosted at github (seen here).This is a great game for that young members of the household picking up a controller and wanting to allow for some creativity.  This homebrew is like a virtual coloring book, where you can add objects from some imagines provided already and choose your custom color's and simply point to colorize your pics. Might not be the most enjoyable thing but if you need a spare few moments to keep the young ones occupied while they are exercising some creativity Barulandia might be a great game for your PS3.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-9T19:40:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>FB Neo RL Plus v2.12 - Support Added for TurboGrafX 16 / PC-Engine / SuperGrafx / ColecoVision</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FB_Neo_RL_Plus_v2.12_-_Support_Added_for_TurboGrafX_16__PC-Engine__SuperGrafx__ColecoVision.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/fb-neo-rl-plus-v2-12-support-added-for-turbografx-16-pc-engine-supergrafx-colecovision.31719/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FB_Neo_RL_Plus_v2.12_-_Support_Added_for_TurboGrafX_16__PC-Engine__SuperGrafx__ColecoVision.jpg">FB Neo RL Plushas been updated to version 2.12 recently, This fork version of@CaptainCPS-XoriginalFB Alpha Retro Loader (RL)has been progressing in the absence of CPS-X by developer@Crystalwho has forked the project last year withFB Neo RL Plus, now residing at version 2.12 this PS3 emulation project powered byPSL1GHT(PS3's OpenSource SDK)has added various support for new systems making this ps3 homebrew a very appealing emulator and frontend for both PS3 CFW and PS3 HEN user's.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-29T18:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>webMAN MOD 1.47.31 -  Various Improvements & Fixes in new update dedicated to bitsbubba</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.31_-__Various_Improvements_&_Fixes_in_new_update_dedicated_to_bitsbubba.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/webman-mod-1-47-31-various-improvements-fixes-in-new-update-dedicated-to-bitsbubba.31608/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.31_-__Various_Improvements_&_Fixes_in_new_update_dedicated_to_bitsbubba.jpg">A very popular PS3 homebrew plugin has been updated by the talented developer behind the plugin we know as@aldostools, as he releases a new version ofwebMAN MODfor your jailbroken PS3(this plugin CFW & PS3HEN compatible).The developer has dedicated this update in honor of our great friend@bitsbubbawhowe recently learned had lost his lifedue to battle lost to cancer..In this update of the plugin Aldostools has alot of improvements, as the plugin itself has several issues that have been fixed as seen in the changelog included below, plus this update contains various changes to thesuite of toolsthat accompanies the plugin with 73 commits being pushed to those tools​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-7T15:00:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE 2] Super Mario 64 Ported to Vita, PSP, PS2, PS3 and PS4!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_2]_Super_Mario_64_Ported_to_Vita,_PSP,_PS2,_PS3_and_PS4!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-2-super-mario-64-ported-to-vita-psp-ps2-ps3-and-ps4.30923/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_2]_Super_Mario_64_Ported_to_Vita,_PSP,_PS2,_PS3_and_PS4!.jpg">Yes, you read right...Super Mario 64 has been ported to the Vita, PSP, PS2, PS3 and PS4(not to be confused with emulated)! You will need to build your own copy of the game using your own legitimately obtained N64 Rom.DoNOTask for links or pre-complied copies on this site, or you will be banned. And definitely doNOTlink to any pre-complied copies!Super Mario 64is arguably one of the greatest video games of all time, and certainly one of the most significant releases of it's time. Personally, I remember having my parents drop me off atToys 'R' Usfor hours at a time, just so that I could sample a little of this incredible 3D platformer on the demo-kiosk before it was officially released to the public. I will never forget whenBabbage'scalled me three days prior to the release of the Nintendo 64, and said I could come pick up my console and copy of Super Mario 64 that day. I spent countless hours mastering the controls, obtaining all 120 stars, and just enjoying the beautifully created worlds.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-6T13:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: October 06th, '20] HW Acceleration (RSX) Project Update by @ReneRebeTM</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_October_06th,_'20]_HW_Acceleration_(RSX)_Project_Update_by_@ReneRebeTM.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-october-06th-20-hw-acceleration-rsx-project-update-by-renerebetm.21370/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_October_06th,_'20]_HW_Acceleration_(RSX)_Project_Update_by_@ReneRebeTM.jpg">UPDATE(June 28th, '20) - Another New Video Released >>>The next PS3 NVidia RSX accelerated X.org steps(Original Article from Nov. 14) Is the PS3 a bit closer to gainingHardware Acceleration (via RSX) in OtherOS (Linux)with a proper driver to enable the GPU chip? We are not there, but we may be getting closer to a reality. Earlier this year (back in April) we detailed some of the progress that the busy devRenéRebehas made with unlocking the potential of the PlayStation 3's RSX chip and now today we have been greeted with a new video and what we can expect with this project as the developer starts to undertake the challenge of further unlocking one more component of the Ps3 hardware,.The developer has alot of videos on other intresting subjects in his diverse  YouTubechannel >>> (Bits and More) <<<  many very informative video's..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-23T06:52:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Mortal Kombat Komplete Edition Mod Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Mortal_Kombat_Komplete_Edition_Mod_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/mortal-kombat-komplete-edition-mod-released.8916/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Mortal_Kombat_Komplete_Edition_Mod_Released.jpg">Mortal Kombat modderfuturetime23dropped by PSX-Place with a treat for MK fans. He released version one of his mod calledMK9 Trilogy Edition.This mod aims at balancing the games characters and at a later stage will introduce further mods that will add more to the game. While this is</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-14T11:31:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PSP Chronoswitch Downgrader Update Released - Version 7.0</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSP_Chronoswitch_Downgrader_Update_Released_-_Version_7.0.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/psp-chronoswitch-downgrader-update-released-version-7-0.4213/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PSP_Chronoswitch_Downgrader_Update_Released_-_Version_7.0.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-13T08:54:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PlayStation 4 Firmware Update 3.15</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_4_Firmware_Update_3.15.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/playstation-4-firmware-update-3-15.3929/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PlayStation_4_Firmware_Update_3.15.jpg">An update to the system software for PlayStation 4 systems was released on 13 January 2016. You can use this to update your system software to version 3.15.Main features in system software update 3.15:This system software update improves the quality of the system performance.Click to expand...Click to expand...Source:PlayStationEUYou can view our PlayStation 4 firmware update thread here.​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-6T11:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>HDDChecker Updated - Diagnostic Harddrive Tool For Your PS2</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/HDDChecker_Updated_-_Diagnostic_Harddrive_Tool_For_Your_PS2.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/hddchecker-updated-diagnostic-harddrive-tool-for-your-ps2.3858/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/HDDChecker_Updated_-_Diagnostic_Harddrive_Tool_For_Your_PS2.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-4T11:48:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>BigBoss Back With More Goodies For The PS4</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/BigBoss_Back_With_More_Goodies_For_The_PS4.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/bigboss-back-with-more-goodies-for-the-ps4.3842/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/BigBoss_Back_With_More_Goodies_For_The_PS4.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2016-1-2T10:05:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Rudi Rastelli Brings Another Update To His PKG Extracting Tool</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Rudi_Rastelli_Brings_Another_Update_To_His_PKG_Extracting_Tool.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/rudi-rastelli-brings-another-update-to-his-pkg-extracting-tool.3808/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Rudi_Rastelli_Brings_Another_Update_To_His_PKG_Extracting_Tool.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-12-29T09:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Universal Media Server Updates Out - The Latter Been A Beta</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Universal_Media_Server_Updates_Out_-_The_Latter_Been_A_Beta.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/universal-media-server-updates-out-the-latter-been-a-beta.3776/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Universal_Media_Server_Updates_Out_-_The_Latter_Been_A_Beta.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-11-25T10:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>TrueAncestor PKG Repacker With New Unpack Engine - Version 2.20</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TrueAncestor_PKG_Repacker_With_New_Unpack_Engine_-_Version_2.20.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/trueancestor-pkg-repacker-with-new-unpack-engine-version-2-20.3595/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TrueAncestor_PKG_Repacker_With_New_Unpack_Engine_-_Version_2.20.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-11-23T11:16:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Wborland Releases Updated PS3 Game List App For Windows</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Wborland_Releases_Updated_PS3_Game_List_App_For_Windows.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/wborland-releases-updated-ps3-game-list-app-for-windows.3579/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Wborland_Releases_Updated_PS3_Game_List_App_For_Windows.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2015-11-18T11:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>VitaShell Version 0.2 Out - Sign PSP Homebrew & More</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaShell_Version_0.2_Out_-_Sign_PSP_Homebrew_&_More.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vitashell-version-0-2-out-sign-psp-homebrew-more.3536/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaShell_Version_0.2_Out_-_Sign_PSP_Homebrew_&_More.jpg">​</description>
			<creators>Tranced</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-13T19:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.86 FERROX COBRA (v8.20) Custom Firmware by Alexander</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86_FERROX_COBRA_(v8.20)_Custom_Firmware_by_Alexander.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-86-ferrox-cobra-v8-20-custom-firmware-by-alexander.29103/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86_FERROX_COBRA_(v8.20)_Custom_Firmware_by_Alexander.jpg">As the4.86 OFW updatehas the PS3 developer cranking out updates, we now have a couple Custom Firmware choices for capable PS3 models (to know if your PS3 model can install a CFW, simply load the exploits page ofbguerville PS3 Toolsetin your PS3 Browser, more infohere) Its good having two well known developer's release CFW's since the 4.86 OFW update .First we had@Joonie(of team rebug & hfw developer)release4.86 REBUG LITE, now we have another known Custom Firmware developer in@Alexanderwith the release of4.86 FERROX COBRA.this cobra cfw comes with v8.20 of the payload and contains the usual tweaks in the FERROX brand . For those of you new to this CFW you can view some of the features listed below, the developer offer's some additional XMB mods that can be found in the source link provided below wi6th instructions in how to install.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T20:33:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Movian (Media Center) v5.0.701 by deank - Improved OSD  / HLS bitrate switching Fixed / ...</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_(Media_Center)_v5.0.701_by_deank_-_Improved_OSD___HLS_bitrate_switching_Fixed__....jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/movian-media-center-v5-0-701-by-deank-improved-osd-hls-bitrate-switching-fixed.29075/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Movian_(Media_Center)_v5.0.701_by_deank_-_Improved_OSD___HLS_bitrate_switching_Fixed__....jpg">Developer @deank(who werecently interviewed) has pushed an unofficial update forMovian, a multi-platform project originally developed byAndreas Smas(available on Android, Linux, OS/X, Raspberry Pi and PS3).For those of your that are new to this longstanding PS3 project, it's a robustmedia centerthat comes equipped with additional support for video and audio codecs then what you would find in the PS3's official media player. Various plugins are also available from within the application such as YouTube plugin giving user's an additional option vs the YouTube app .There are other various plugins you can use that provide ranging functions some include themeing /info / other functionalities. Recently deank has releasedv5.0.701and there has been a few cosmetic changes (listed in the changelogs provide) and a couple of  bug fixes provided (see 2nd tab)..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T17:39:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update 2]  PS3 Simple File Manager (by tps)  v0.5.0  Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_2]__PS3_Simple_File_Manager_(by_tps)__v0.5.0__Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-2-ps3-simple-file-manager-by-tps-v0-5-0-released.29071/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_2]__PS3_Simple_File_Manager_(by_tps)__v0.5.0__Released.jpg">Updated(2) v0.5.0 -Provides External Support for manager's (0.4.0) + NTFS Support (v0.5.0)(original Article v0.3.0)The PS3 has no shortage of File Management solutions and alot of choices via homebrew managers like(multiMAN, IRISMAN, ManaGunZ or webMAN / webMAN MOD/ XMB Mods / Apps like Comgenies File Manager, FTP support), but developer@tps(aka lmirel) has released another choice in file management for the PS3, this is currently in the early stages and in the currently labeled as a test release. The file manager itself contains basic features, though with a name likeSimple File Managerthe developer intentions is more then likely focusing on perfecting the basic functions for a Simple File Manager that is easy to use. The ps3 homebrew utility currently supports exFAT and FAT file systems, view the release notes from the developer below​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T17:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Artemis r6.1 - Ps3 Cheat App updated by bucanero</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Artemis_r6.1_-_Ps3_Cheat_App_updated_by_bucanero.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/artemis-r6-1-ps3-cheat-app-updated-by-bucanero.29070/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Artemis_r6.1_-_Ps3_Cheat_App_updated_by_bucanero.jpg">A new update forArtemis(r6.1)has been been released by the developer@bucanerothat included some handy new enchantments for the Cheat System for both PS3 CFW user's and PS3HEN user's ,The app on startup will now check for a new update and process the update automatically, A new plugin selection system has been added, the reason for the implementation is that different version of the plugin run better depending on your console's exploration path (CFW or PS3HEN). For instances on PS3HEN the r5 plugin has performed much better then the later r6 plugin that is suggested for CFW user's. So the app gives you the ability to choose easily which plugin you would like to use. Several other new enchantments make their way in this latest update from a developer(seen the release notes below)that has been impressing lately with some of his PS3 projects likePS3 Apollo Save ToolandPKGi​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T12:13:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>IRISMAN 4.86 + MAMBA v8.3 update by Aldostools</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_4.86_+_MAMBA_v8.3_update_by_Aldostools.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/irisman-4-86-mamba-v8-3-update-by-aldostools.29059/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_4.86_+_MAMBA_v8.3_update_by_Aldostools.jpg">Update v4.86.1:see below for changesDeveloper@aldostoolswhom we recently interviewed inThe Power Supply Series,if you have not seen that interview yet, it can be seen>here<.Now the developer is back with a new update for the popularIRISMAN(AIO) manager for homebrew enabled PS3 consoles to support thenew 4.86 (firmware) update.The developer has not just added new FW support but has also made an update (v8.3) toMAMBApayload(an alternative for Cobra on non Cobra CFWs).This update to MAMBA(that's injected from IRISMAN)has added support for@DeViL303PoC of loading games from a modified Photo Columnthat appears in "Games". There are some other neat MAMBA features, like when you disable CFW syscalls they can be re enabled without a restart to the PS3 Console, This mamba update also provides some other tweaks and enchantments that the developer has outlined in the changelog below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-12T11:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>XForge PS QRC Tool -  Modifying aspects of the XMB is now easier then ever.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/XForge_PS_QRC_Tool_-__Modifying_aspects_of_the_XMB_is_now_easier_then_ever..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/xforge-ps-qrc-tool-modifying-aspects-of-the-xmb-is-now-easier-then-ever.28804/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/XForge_PS_QRC_Tool_-__Modifying_aspects_of_the_XMB_is_now_easier_then_ever..jpg">We have seen many XMB visual mods published so far in the lifetime of the PS3 but the QRC format (a type of container) has been always problematic, tricky, and very restricted.XForgeis intended to solve all this problems once for all, it allows full freedom torebuild the QRC filesand modify all his contentsThere are many files inside the QRC containers that are candidates to be modified, XForge is the first tool that allows to modify them in a "noob friendly" way, everything made from a intuitive interface with preview panelsSay goodbye to the previous manual methods that required dealing with zlib compressed files or injecting them with a hex-editor to create a custom wave, to replace XMB main icons, to change background wallpapers, etc... XForge supersedes all that tutorials, manuals methods, and tools, there is a long list of features supported by XForge, for more detailed descriptions see the feature list below​</description>
			<creators>pink1</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-4T15:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE 4] PS3 Toolset by bguerville: A powerful collection of tools fueled by new PS3 exploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_4]_PS3_Toolset_by_bguerville_A_powerful_collection_of_tools_fueled_by_new_PS3_exploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-4-ps3-toolset-by-bguerville-a-powerful-collection-of-tools-fueled-by-new-ps3-exploit.28658/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_4]_PS3_Toolset_by_bguerville_A_powerful_collection_of_tools_fueled_by_new_PS3_exploit.jpg">UPDATE FEB 2023 (The domain's of ** ** www.ps3xploit.net  > Domain no Longer owned by team**  (NEW URL = http://ps3toolset.com)  > Domain no Longer owned by team**  (NEW URL =  http://ps3toolset.com and .com are no longer in poccession of the team, A new address will be posted in future release coverage.Update (4) Now supporting 4.86 Fully  & Issue fixed with NAND console's in raresituationsYou may recall a recentarticlerevealing a few exclusive screenshots of bguerville's latest project, now the time has come to introduce the next evolution in PS3 Jailbreaking solutions. ThePlayStation 3 Toolsetby@bguervilleis a new suite of tools, built upon a new PS3 exploitation framework & fueled bya new exploit discovered on the PS3 by the developer.The new exploit (and the toolset project as a whole)is compatible withall PS3 models running 4.82 - 4.86 OFW/HFW/CFWWhileps3xploitteam member's@habibcontinued research and development ofPS3HENfor nonCFW models with assistance from@esc0rtd3w, @bguervillemeanwhile was working on his own research and developing other tools and exploits as you will see with this new PlayStation 3 Toolset, which thorough testing was conducted by@esc0rtd3w(whom we recently interviewed). All the team of talented devs have done some amazing work in the scene in recent years with all thePS3Xploitprojects and that trend continues with this release.ThePS3 toolsetis a project that@bguervillehas been working on for some time,the developer gave us a brief timeline of events since thePs3XploitTools 2.0 framework(flash writer and dumper(s)) that led to this new release (see the timeline section).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-4-1T20:48:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.86.1 REBUG LITE EDITION + REBUG TOOLBOX 2.03.04 MULTI RELEASED</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86.1_REBUG_LITE_EDITION_+_REBUG_TOOLBOX_2.03.04_MULTI_RELEASED.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-86-1-rebug-lite-edition-rebug-toolbox-2-03-04-multi-released.28809/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.86.1_REBUG_LITE_EDITION_+_REBUG_TOOLBOX_2.03.04_MULTI_RELEASED.jpg">UPDATE - Builds for Broken Console's (NoBD / NoBT / RSOD) - See link at bottom of articleIt has been a busy week and especially for the PS3, First we had introduction ofbguerville PS3 Toolset(which introduce a new ps3 Exploit along with some powerful tools). Then we had4.86 Official Firmwaredropped (no exploits patched)  Then  developer@JoonieofTeam Rebugwas quick to release an updatedHybridFirmWare(forPS3HENuser's when an update toPS3HENarrives for those nonCFW models)and now the developer follows that with the release of4.86.1 REBUG LITE Edition,supplying us with one of the best firmware as the first option for 4.86 Custom FirmwareChoices.This CFW comes equipped Cobra 8.2 payload, this payload provides various features some of those highlights include background running plugins, burnt optical media support as well as ISO Support are a few of the many Cobra features included in v8.2. The release details found below detail the various features & patches found in this CFW release. Also it's worth checking out at the download location (link below) the additional info and ":how to" information pertaining to use of REBUG LITE's CFW functionality.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-3-31T19:49:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.87.1 PS3 HFW (Hybrid Firmware) - HFW is helpful for installing PS3HEN on 4.84/4.85/4.86/4.87 FW</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.1_PS3_HFW_(Hybrid_Firmware)_-_HFW_is_helpful_for_installing_PS3HEN_on_4.844.854.864.87_FW.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-87-1-ps3-hfw-hybrid-firmware-hfw-is-helpful-for-installing-ps3hen-on-4-84-4-85-4-86-4-87-fw.23094/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.87.1_PS3_HFW_(Hybrid_Firmware)_-_HFW_is_helpful_for_installing_PS3HEN_on_4.844.854.864.87_FW.jpg">UPDATE (May, 2022) 4.89 HFW Releasedsee here.Original Article (4.84 HFW - March 2019): Huge News as the PS3 exploit ladder has taken a step up into 4.84 rung, with a new approach tobring back PS3Xploit functionality on 4.84.With a Hybrid Firmware (NOT A CFW) that can be installed onANY MODEL PS3 over any Official Firmware (OFW) version..The only thing this modified firmware essentially does is bring back the patched webkit from OFW 4.82 that was an entry point forPS3Xploit, if you recall when 4.84 was released developers@bguervilleand@esc0rtd3wstated the exploit was not actually patched but rather only the webkit entry used was removed in 4.83+ which rendered the actual exploit unreachable (not patched and could be restored). Now the webkit is back for 4.84 OFW thanks to this new clever magic that has allowed OFW user's to use and install this slightly modified Firmware.​</description>
			<creators>Joonie</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-3-22T12:07:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 04) - Our Guest Today: "PS3(Xploit) Developer @esc0rtd3w"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._04)_-_Our_Guest_Today_PS3(Xploit)_Developer_@esc0rtd3w.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-04-our-guest-today-ps3-xploit-developer-esc0rtd3w.28157/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._04)_-_Our_Guest_Today_PS3(Xploit)_Developer_@esc0rtd3w.jpg">OurInterview Seriesis a full success. Not only can you get anin-depth look behind all the great projectseach of those developer's have worked on in the past and their plans into the future, but also that you can get auseful overview with all important Homebrew Releasesmade by the developer's which willhelp you if you want to get the "Full Experience" from your hacked Console's and devices. For instance, we learned in ourlast Interviewwithdeveloper@aldostoolsthat he created the "Tools Collection" for the PS3, which containsOVER 50+ TOOLS! But while we had interviewed candidates before, who developed their projects after a Hack/Exploit was released, we thought about introducing you to another side of development, namely those, who make it possible for those previously mentioned developers to create their Homebrew running on your hacked devices. And since this mentioned "Tools Collection" contains mainly Tools for yourhacked PS3, it would be only fair to give you an in-depth look with one of the developers of thePS3Xploit-Team, who helpedreanimating you and your PS3with all those great projects. This developer work includes participation in projects like theFlash Writer'sthat provide theability for CFW Installation, then "PS3HEN" which brought Homebrew Support for "nonCFW Models" and also the variety of tools and dumpers released from thePS3Xploit-Team. So, without further waiting, our Guest Today is no other thanDeveloper and long-time Community Member -@esc0rtd3w!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T07:04:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Homebrew Revival PS3.1] Featuring "UFO Racer" by ThatOtherDev</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Homebrew_Revival_PS3.1]_Featuring_UFO_Racer_by_ThatOtherDev.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/homebrew-revival-ps3-1-featuring-ufo-racer-by-thatotherdev.36357/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Homebrew_Revival_PS3.1]_Featuring_UFO_Racer_by_ThatOtherDev.jpg">Homebrew Revialis a new feature at psx-place.com where we explore some great projects of the past to educate new user's on some homebrew they may not of known about and also to perhaps sparks some new development in various projects we spotlight in this series, checkout another exclusive psx-place series withThe Power Supplythat has interviewed various developer's who have powered the community (will continue with a new season of interviews soon).First up, we have a great homebrew game that was developed for the Wii and the PS3 by developerThatOtherDev(aka ThatOtherPerson)calledUFO Racer, it's a game with a great foundation and has alot of potential to be a really great homebrew title, but the original developer has not made an update since 2012, However the source code is available, using an early version of PSL1GHT.. Can this be a project that see's a rival in 2022, 10 years after it was released? Checkout some of the source code and the tutorials this developer wrote for the PS3. Also, take note during the source code release of UFO Racer and many other games created by ThatOtherDev. The developer states the following about using the source code: "Make something. There is an appalling, lack of original games being made in the homebrew community and I implore you to take part in changing this." see full statement in tab below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-2T11:15:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.2]  SATURN-FPKG - Convert Saturn Games into PS4 fPKGs!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.2]__SATURN-FPKG_-_Convert_Saturn_Games_into_PS4_fPKGs!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-2-saturn-fpkg-convert-saturn-games-into-ps4-fpkgs.36031/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.2]__SATURN-FPKG_-_Convert_Saturn_Games_into_PS4_fPKGs!.jpg">Following the recentPS4 9.00 Jailbreak, Ps4 developer@Jabuhas a new tool for 9.00 FW , you may remember this developer's previous release's for the PS4 with theps2-fpkgandpsx-fpkgtools that allowed for Ps2 / Ps1 games into a fpkg's  to install on a homebrew enabled PS4.  Following that same concept of injecting custom roms into an fpkg the developer now has a new tool that convertsSega Saturngames into PS4 fpkgs.  With the release of  "Cotton Guardian Force Saturn Tribute"(a Sega Saturn Game)for the PS4, it has equipped a useful Sega Saturn emulator that is said to be based off theSSF emulator.  (According to ZiL0G80) and performing well. Upon seeing this game release is when developer@Jabuinterest peaked and then decided to develop and release the following tool to make running your Sega Saturn games easily on your homebrew equipped PS4 (9.00 FW).....​</description>
			<creators>Jabu</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-1T13:12:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>TeamFAPS Release CEX2DEX for Vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TeamFAPS_Release_CEX2DEX_for_Vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/teamfaps-release-cex2dex-for-vita.36069/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TeamFAPS_Release_CEX2DEX_for_Vita.jpg">CEX2DEX for the PS VitaBy Team Fapps**PSTV & VitaTV planned for future date**​</description>
			<creators>atreyu187</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-12-12T23:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Firmware 9.00 Jailbreak Update (Released)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Firmware_9.00_Jailbreak_Update_(Released).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-firmware-9-00-jailbreak-update-released.35900/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Firmware_9.00_Jailbreak_Update_(Released).jpg">"In this project you will find an implementation that tries to make use of a filesystem bug for the Playstation 4 on firmware 9.00. The bug was found while diffing the 9.00 and 9.03 kernels. It will require a drive with a modified exfat filesystem. Successfully triggering it will allow you to run arbitrary code as kernel, to allow jailbreaking and kernel-level modifications to the system. will launch the usual payload launcher (on port 9020).- via project's official readme"PS4 Firmware 9.00Jailbreak Released(awesome work bychendochap&@Znullptr)​</description>
			<creators>Death_Dealer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-25T19:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.88.2 Evilnat Cobra (8.3) Custom FirmWare (CFW-CEX) Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.88.2_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.3)_Custom_FirmWare_(CFW-CEX)_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-88-2-evilnat-cobra-8-3-custom-firmware-cfw-cex-released.32057/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.88.2_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.3)_Custom_FirmWare_(CFW-CEX)_Released.jpg">UPDATE 4.88.2:PS3 Developer@Evilnathas updated and released4.88.2Evilnat (Cobra 8.3) CFW ,there is a number of new options like an added File manager, Option to toggle Cobra version, and various other new options detailed in the changlog provided below. Also the developer has provided a number of  fixes and improvements, View all the details of 4.88.2 release of this latest CFW by@Evilnat​</description>
			<creators>Evilnat</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-22T22:52:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch (PS2) Progress : New Cores incoming,  gpSP  (GameBoy Advance @ Full-Speed)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(PS2)_Progress__New_Cores_incoming,__gpSP__(GameBoy_Advance_@_Full-Speed).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-ps2-progress-new-cores-incoming-gpsp-gameboy-advance-full-speed.34680/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(PS2)_Progress__New_Cores_incoming,__gpSP__(GameBoy_Advance_@_Full-Speed).jpg">Emulation on a Homebrew Enabled PS2 Console has some great progress in the past year plus,  thanks to still very much active PS2 development scene.  Developer's like@fjtrujyhasported RetroArchto the PS2 about and since then has been adding more and more support for additional emulation with additional libretro core's., Recently the developer previewed some big things that  have been in the pipeline for the  PlayStation 2 port of RetroArch (a multi-system emulator).The PS2 now has a new full speedGBA (GameBoy Advance) emulatorcoming soon with thegpsplibretro corenow running very well @ full speed with the work of@fjtrujyand@davidgfnetcollaborating to bring dynarec to provide a full speed gba emu on the PS2 Console.  Also, the Lutro Core (Lua) improvements are right around the corner as well with some progress being made (seen here) to the core . See some of the progress that has been made on the PS2 port of RetroArch so far in 2021 below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-22T22:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>jfduke3d-vita + jfsw-vita + vitaRTCW released + Doom3 Port in the works</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/jfduke3d-vita_+_jfsw-vita_+_vitaRTCW_released_+_Doom3_Port_in_the_works.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/jfduke3d-vita-jfsw-vita-vitartcw-released-doom3-port-in-the-works.34648/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/jfduke3d-vita_+_jfsw-vita_+_vitaRTCW_released_+_Doom3_Port_in_the_works.jpg">Following theKYUHEN Homebrew Contest, the PS Vita platform has been getting some new homebrew updates and ports from a familiar developer to all in the PS Vita community. Developer@Rinnegatamanterecently provided updates toVitaQuakeIII (v1.0),re3-gta (v1.4)andVitaVoyager (v0.8)Following those updates another project seen an update with the release ofVitaRTCW (v0.4)here in the psx-place forum's,.Now comes the introduction of a few new projects, some have been released already here in the psx-place.com forums,1st up we havefsw-vita - Port of Shadow Warrior Classicand then today we seen the release ofjfduke3d-vita iport of jfduke3d (JonoF's Duke 3D).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-13T22:34:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>KYUHEN  PS Vita / PSTV  Homebrew Contest Winner's have been announced!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__PS_Vita__PSTV__Homebrew_Contest_Winner's_have_been_announced!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/kyuhen-ps-vita-pstv-homebrew-contest-winners-have-been-announced.34499/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__PS_Vita__PSTV__Homebrew_Contest_Winner's_have_been_announced!!.jpg">After a couple months of development of various homebrew projects for the PS Vita and PlayStation TV, theKYUHEN Contestfor the PS Vita has came to a close recently and now the Winners have been Announced (top 3 from each category). The Full Rankings (& Doiwnloads) can be found on the "Result" Page on the Contest's Official Website.  The Contest yielded36 entries(about the same as GekiHEN Contest (39))that spawned across the following 4 categories:Game 1 , Game 2, Utility, Port. No doubt has been some impressive showing and some great projects that are now available on your Homebrew Enabled PS Vita or PlayStation TV(vita tv).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-12T00:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>re3-Vita (Grand Theft Auto III port) updated to v1.4</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3-Vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_port)_updated_to_v1.4.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/re3-vita-grand-theft-auto-iii-port-updated-to-v1-4.34564/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3-Vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_port)_updated_to_v1.4.jpg">Recently the re3-vita (GTA III Port)is back with a new update with the release of version 1.4, this update provided by developer@Rinnegatamante, who has recently updatedVitaQuakeIII (v1.0)&VitaVoyager (v0.8)Has now updated this amazing vita port of re3 with various fixes for all "game-breaking issues affecting previous release's" and v1.4 also includes some features like the inclusion of a Game Manual.  To round out the update we have support for video playback now in v1.4 and instructions in how to get your Video's converted to work on the PS Vita / PSTV, Checkout all the details below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-6T19:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>VitaQuakeIII  v1.0   +  VitaVoyager v0.8:  New updates to vitaGL provides new performance boost !</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaQuakeIII__v1.0___+__VitaVoyager_v0.8__New_updates_to_vitaGL_provides_new_performance_boost_!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vitaquakeiii-v1-0-vitavoyager-v0-8-new-updates-to-vitagl-provides-new-performance-boost.34500/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaQuakeIII__v1.0___+__VitaVoyager_v0.8__New_updates_to_vitaGL_provides_new_performance_boost_!.jpg">Developer@Rinnegatamantedropped by the forums here at psx-place.com to release a couple of new items for the homebrew community.  First up we have an update toVitaQuakeIIIwith the release of version 1.0. This update has provided the port withMultitexturing supportandTexture CombinerWhat this does, is improves performance on the PS Vita and provides support for features like dynamic light that previously has been disabled prior to this update (see video below for a showcase of examples).  In regards to the recentadvancements to VitaGLthe developer states "Expect a branch of releases for idTech3 derivates plus maybe some new idTech 3 derivates ports in the future" be sure to keep a look out in the future here in thepsx-place forumsand @VitaDBfor when those release appear directly fromRinnegatamante.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-28T20:39:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>KYUHEN  - A New Vita Homebrew Contest (Now Live - Submissions ends on May 27, 2021)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__-_A_New_Vita_Homebrew_Contest_(Now_Live_-_Submissions_ends_on_May_27,_2021).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/kyuhen-a-new-vita-homebrew-contest-now-live-submissions-ends-on-may-27-2021.33403/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__-_A_New_Vita_Homebrew_Contest_(Now_Live_-_Submissions_ends_on_May_27,_2021).jpg">There is a newVita Homebrew Contestthat is starting in the Vita Community, in the past we have seen theRejuvenate Contestthat helped spark some early development in the Vita Scene, then later on we had theGekiHEN Contestwhich psx-place took a part in along with other scene sites, now we have the a new contest for the Vita Community calledKYUHEN,Spearheaded byCimmerian , 2old4Gaming , frangarcjwith assistance from psx-place.com / wololo.net / playstationhax.xyz / Customprotocol.com .The Contest will consist of a2 month development periodand spanacross 4 categories.  Those categories include 2 separate"Games"categories one for SDK Homebrew and one for Project powered by ported engine's such as Unity or GameMaker. Then there will be a separate category for"Ports"of  games/emulators ect..  Then to round out the last category there is"Utilities"and this one is open to both applications and plugins .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-17T20:02:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update] Apollo Save Tool v1.8.4 released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.8.4_released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-apollo-save-tool-v1-8-4-released.28124/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.8.4_released.jpg">Update v1.8.4 ReleasedOriginal Introduction:PS3 development has been seeing an upkick lately and developer@bucanerohas been one of the developers playing a part. The developer has recently updatedArtemis with new supportand also releasedPKGi (PS3)but now the developer shares a great utility that involves PS3 Game Saves calledApollo, built utilizing the Artemis GUI this homebrew capable of running on CFW and PS3HEN will allow you to Patch & Resign your Game Saves / Download Game Saves / Unlock Game Saves all from the convenience of your PS3 console and not PC tools are required.  Below you can see the release thread from the developer himself: So i'll let@bucanerotake it from here with another great release:​</description>
			<creators>bucanero</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-17T18:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>(Update 1.1) Grand Theft Auto:  Chinatown Wars  (GTA CTW)  Vita Port by @theflow0 /  @Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(Update_1.1)_Grand_Theft_Auto__Chinatown_Wars__(GTA_CTW)__Vita_Port_by_@theflow0___@Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-1-1-grand-theft-auto-chinatown-wars-gta-ctw-vita-port-by-theflow0-rinnegatamante.33283/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(Update_1.1)_Grand_Theft_Auto__Chinatown_Wars__(GTA_CTW)__Vita_Port_by_@theflow0___@Rinnegatamante.jpg">Update v1.1 ReleasedOriginal Article (March 17):The duo of PS Vita legends developer'sTheFlowand@Rinnegatamanteteam up again with another great release for the PS Vita Community. We have seen the family ofGrand Theft Auto Seriesmake the journey to the PS Vita with various ports and techniques but have we been missing one from the PSP era in the form of a native port? First we seen the release ofre3 (GTA III)followed byreVC (GTA: Vice City)which utilized a reversed engineered engine .. Then several weeks ago we seen those two classic GTA game's followed by what may be the most iconic game in the series withgtaSA_Vita (GTA: San Andreas)as we just witnessed updatev1.6released  Whichtook a different approach and utilized the Android port of the game and puts TheFlow's kubridge plugin to work serving as a wrapper for aiding in the porting some Android games to the PS Vita (seeMax Payneas another Android game ported)Now, that brings us to today's release with is a port of another GTA Classic from the PSP with the release ofGrand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars, (GTA:CFW Vita) a 3D top view game from the series , LikeMax PayneandGTASAthis is a port of the Android version with magic from@Rinnegatamanteand TheFlow.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-14T18:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>{UPDATE] PS4 Jailbreak 7.50 /7.55 w/ Mira Support Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{UPDATE]_PS4_Jailbreak_7.50_7.55_w_Mira_Support_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-ps4-jailbreak-7-50-7-55-w-mira-support-released.33239/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{UPDATE]_PS4_Jailbreak_7.50_7.55_w_Mira_Support_Released.jpg">UPDATE7.55 w/ Mira Support ReleasedOriginal Article (7.50) Not only did we just see aPS1 exploit released, the exploited PS4 firmware latter has extended a step to now firmware 7.50 has been officially exploited and released to the public as developerSleirsgoevyhas released the latest PS4 Jailbreak that has utilized the latest findings fromTheFlowin his disclosed bug that has the potential to work upto 7.55 but is currently targeted for 7.50 for this release.TheFlowhas tweeted several hints regarding 7.55 (tweet1/2) but 7.55 is yet to be solved by other,@zecoxaoprovided some details and shared via twitter see below.This is not a fully functional jailbreak yet as there is elements that are needed to be ported like the Mira/HEN and other Payload, so you should not update to this exploit from previous exploits yet. Let it mature, but if your on a PS4 on 7.50 or lower and missed out on previous exploits, Stay Tuned as this progresses,​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T21:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[PS3 XMB MOD] Now have Individual Gameboots for each emulator / system / homebrew launched</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[PS3_XMB_MOD]_Now_have_Individual_Gameboots_for_each_emulator__system__homebrew_launched.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-xmb-mod-now-have-individual-gameboots-for-each-emulator-system-homebrew-launched.33240/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[PS3_XMB_MOD]_Now_have_Individual_Gameboots_for_each_emulator__system__homebrew_launched.jpg">If you have an exploited PS3 and have been following some of the progress that@DeViL303has made with XMB modding ,then you already know about some of these great project's the xmb mod developer has been working on lately. For those of you new to his work, some recent mods from DeViL303 includeUltimate ToolboxandPixel Art possibilitiesand many more from the past .  Now the developer has taken on enhancing the Gameboot animation when launching content from the PS3's XMB.  Having the same boring sequence for all your content simply won't cut it anymore. Now withwebMAN MODhelping fuel the concept we now have the abilityto set individual Gameboots per contentsuch as bringing back those iconic start-ups from the PS1 and PS2 or having the system startups for your favorite retro roms. Well now you have that ability and more with the latest release from@DeViL303and the latest update to webMAN MOD from@aldostoolsthat helps power the concept the two have been working on the past several weeks seen here in the psx-place forums (here)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T19:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>tonyhax - A Software backup loader exploit for the PS1 (leverages save game exploit)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/tonyhax_-_A_Software_backup_loader_exploit_for_the_PS1_(leverages_save_game_exploit).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/tonyhax-a-software-backup-loader-exploit-for-the-ps1-leverages-save-game-exploit.33236/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/tonyhax_-_A_Software_backup_loader_exploit_for_the_PS1_(leverages_save_game_exploit).jpg">Looks like those Classic PlayStation Consoles are still making waves in the homebrew scene. We have seen vibrant development on the PS2 with just recent things likeOpenTunaand also recentMechaCon Firmware dumpedwhich can potentially bring various possibilities discussedhere. However the PS2 is not alone as its daddy the original OG the PlayStation 1 now has a Software Backup Loader Exploit that leverages saves game exploits from Tony Hawk Pro Skater 2 & 3 from developersocram8888. The developer has titled the project "tonyhax" and will work with both the PAL and NTSC versions of the gameThe developer has provided a technical write up and easy to follow explanation as well as a YouTube video we have also attached below. Checkout the latest exploit to hit the PS1.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T17:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>IRISMAN v4.87.1:   Adds support for mounting Compressed ISO's ( ZIP, RAR or 7-Zip)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_v4.87.1___Adds_support_for_mounting_Compressed_ISO's_(_ZIP,_RAR_or_7-Zip).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/irisman-v4-87-1-adds-support-for-mounting-compressed-isos-zip-rar-or-7-zip.33210/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_v4.87.1___Adds_support_for_mounting_Compressed_ISO's_(_ZIP,_RAR_or_7-Zip).jpg">Following some of the recent advancements made towebMAN MOD,  PlayStation 3 Homebrew developer@aldostoolshas now looked to incorporate a new feature in the PS3 Homebrew(CFW/PS3HEN) fbackup manager known asIRISMAN. It's currently a new and experimental feature added in the recent release ofv4.87.1that provides the backup manager the ability tomount compressed ISO in .zip / .7z / .rar formats.  This features supports thePS3's Internal HDD or a FAT32 external storage device for PS1 / PSP / PS2 / PS3/ DVD / BluRay ISO's..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-19T21:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Another new/old Exploit for the PS2! OpenTuna!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Another_newold_Exploit_for_the_PS2!_OpenTuna!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/another-new-old-exploit-for-the-ps2-opentuna.32893/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Another_newold_Exploit_for_the_PS2!_OpenTuna!.jpg">The year is 2021 and the PlayStation 2 Hacking Scene is still alive and kicking very well and we have a new/old Exploit for our PS2 to share!Even with later generations of PlayStation Console like the PS3 / PS4 / PS5 / PS Vita around, the PS2 is still thriving in the development / homebrew community, while serving a great audience for the console. We have seen the progression of several major projects and exploits in the past year for the PlayStation 2 (PS2) like the updates toOpen PS2 Loader  (OPL)to version 1.0.0 andFreeDVDBootexploit.We now have"OpenTuna", brought to you by@alexparrado!OpenTunaIt is an open source version of another recent exploit found and developed back in late 2019 for the PS2 called theFortuna exploit. Additional details about this newly open-source variant of the Fortuna project and what it could mean for the PS2 community can be found in the information provided below:​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-18T13:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Tools (Library w/ Unity Support) updated with "huge update" by The Darkprogrammer</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Tools_(Library_w_Unity_Support)_updated_with_huge_update_by_The_Darkprogrammer.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-tools-library-w-unity-support-updated-with-huge-update-by-the-darkprogrammer.32904/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Tools_(Library_w_Unity_Support)_updated_with_huge_update_by_The_Darkprogrammer.jpg">Alongside of the recent release ofPS4 Trophy UnlockerPS4 developer@The Darkprogrameralso had a big update forPS4 Tools, a Open Source suite of tools in all-in-one library. Various projects have utilized this library in their projects likePS4's PS2 Classic GUI,PS4 PKG Tool, ,PS4 Xploreralong with various other tools (listed below). but the dev is back with new updates for developer;s who may want to use this library that supports Unity development.  In this "huge update" from@The Darkprogramerdevs now have the ability to use the recently releasedTrophy Unlockerand other Recovery Tools in their projects. Not really an end-user release but useful for developer;s who especially have used Unity in creation of their projects. The DarkProgrammer has a homebrew he hopes to release very soon also utilizing this library. .​</description>
			<creators>The Darkprogramer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-18T13:54:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Trophy Unlocker v1.0 by The Darkprogramer</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Trophy_Unlocker_v1.0_by_The_Darkprogramer.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-trophy-unlocker-v1-0-by-the-darkprogramer.32970/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Trophy_Unlocker_v1.0_by_The_Darkprogramer.jpg">PlayStation 4 (PS4) developer@The Darkprogramerhas released a new project for the community calledPS4 TrophyUnlocker.  There is a PC utility that will unlock the trophies using a new method that relies on the game files itself to achieve, It will create a new pkg of the game installation, so if you have it installed already, be aware some files could potentially get lost if your have to overwrite your game. So be aware of that going in also this project isstill in the BETA stage, (v1.0 Released) so expect some bugs and different results depending on the game's trophies your unlocking. if you do experiance an error report it to the developer directly or in the comments below.. Also take note of the another recent release by this developer for developer with theupdate toPS4 Tools​</description>
			<creators>The Darkprogramer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-17T08:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.6] Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas now playable on the PS Vita / PSTV with new port</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.6]_Grand_Theft_Auto_San_Andreas_now_playable_on_the_PS_Vita__PSTV_with_new_port.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-6-grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-now-playable-on-the-ps-vita-pstv-with-new-port.32975/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.6]_Grand_Theft_Auto_San_Andreas_now_playable_on_the_PS_Vita__PSTV_with_new_port.jpg">UPDATE v1.6 Released:Another great release for the PS Vita community arrives today.. As many of you already know in recent daysGrand Theft Auto: III(updated to v1.3)& also just the other dayGrand Theft Auto: Vice Citywas ported by the PS Vita / PS TV from@Rinnegatamante/ @Theflow0,Now these devsTheflow/ Rinnegatamante&aapall had a role in development ofGrand Theft Auto:San Andreasto the PS Vita(& PSTV) ,where theflow states on release"We gave the PS Vita THE game it always deserved. GTA: SA with authentic PS2 atmosphere on-the-go" .Unlike the previous two vita ports in the GTA Series that used a reversed-engineered engine, GTA:SA-Vita is using the mobile version (apk-android)) of the game and adding a "wrapper", like what we saw inMax Paynevita Port recently released utilizing thekubridge.skprx. The wrapper/port contains many custom hooks and patches to get the game running well on the PS Vita. You will need to provide the Game FIles yourself, the game can be purchased on the Play Store.Also developer Rinnegatamante has provided a configuration app to configure various settings, easily.  Also, as usualMVG. has a great video, as the dev/youtuber is covering this release as he was one of the tester's,  that is for sure worth checking out for some additional insight.. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-16T19:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>webMAN MOD 1.47.34 - New  XMB / Startup enhancements from Aldostools in this update.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.34_-_New__XMB__Startup_enhancements_from_Aldostools_in_this_update..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/webman-mod-1-47-34-new-xmb-startup-enhancements-from-aldostools-in-this-update.32860/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.34_-_New__XMB__Startup_enhancements_from_Aldostools_in_this_update..jpg">DeveloperAldostools, a great developer in the PS3 Community continues the evolution of a tiny but powerful plugin that runs in the background of your CFW or HEN exploited systems that is capable of running background plugins (sprx).  Of course the plugin of mention iswebMAN MOD. This plugin contains alot of functionality alot and can give your exploited console a variety of new features & abilities (see readme tab)., In the latest updates to webMAN MOD the dev has turned his attention to XMB customization adding some functionality that gives user's some new creativity on your PS3's UI (or better known as its XMB), We recently seen the efforts inPixel Artby Aldostools and developer@DeViL303but now with this latest update to wMM we have some additional features for XMB customization.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-16T10:46:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Pixel Art w/ custom imagefont.bin (By DeViL303) for XMB & Pixel Art Editor (by Aldostools)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Pixel_Art_w_custom_imagefont.bin_(By_DeViL303)_for_XMB_&_Pixel_Art_Editor_(by_Aldostools).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pixel-art-w-custom-imagefont-bin-by-devil303-for-xmb-pixel-art-editor-by-aldostools.32861/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Pixel_Art_w_custom_imagefont.bin_(By_DeViL303)_for_XMB_&_Pixel_Art_Editor_(by_Aldostools).jpg">If you follow thePSX-Place Twitter Feed, you may of seen some tweets last week about this project already. The undisputed king of XMB Modding for the PS3@DeViL303,has been making various discoveries and implementing those various idea's as he investigates the inner workings of the XMB and the PS3's User Interface. Along those adventures the developer has discovered a clever way for displaying lines and shapes around text to highlight(see example below)them then aldostool had the idea forPixel Arton the PS3 XMB,  The idea has progressed as developer@aldostoolshas created a new editor for creation of some pixel-art for the PS3(and progressed the tool already with a few updates).Checkout additional details about this latest discovery and trick for your XMB customization. This should open the door to some new eye candy for the XMB like in the coldboot and other entries on the XMB such as titles and other area's were text is displayed with manipulation of the font files..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-14T10:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>reVC-vita (GTA: Vice City) port for PS Vita  /  PSTV by @theflow0  & @Rinnegatamante Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/reVC-vita_(GTA_Vice_City)_port_for_PS_Vita____PSTV_by_@theflow0__&_@Rinnegatamante_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/revc-vita-gta-vice-city-port-for-ps-vita-pstv-by-theflow0-rinnegatamante-released.32928/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/reVC-vita_(GTA_Vice_City)_port_for_PS_Vita____PSTV_by_@theflow0__&_@Rinnegatamante_Released.jpg">The PS Vita / PlayStation TV devices are getting another great release for the Vita Homebrew Scene. Iconic developer's in the Vita Community who have done so much for the platform in@Rinnegatamanteand developer@TheFlow, have continued on another great project in a follow-up toreIII-Vita (A port of GTA III to the PS Vita).The devs have now successfully ported anotherGrand Theft Autoclassic in the series & are now ready for release as they dropreVC-Vita - A Port of Grand Theft Auto: Vice Cityto the Vita Community.reVC-Vitais a fully reversed - reimplementation ofGTA: Vice City using thelibrw engine(a full and open source version of RenderWare Graphic Engine),like we seen used inre3-Vita. In order to play this release you need to own a copy of the PC Game (can be purchased on Steam) and move needed game fiies, additional information can be viewed in the installation notes​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-6T10:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 08) - Our Guest Today: "well-known multiconsole Developer @CelesteBlue123"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._08)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well-known_multiconsole_Developer_@CelesteBlue123.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-08-our-guest-today-well-known-multiconsole-developer-celesteblue123.30581/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._08)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well-known_multiconsole_Developer_@CelesteBlue123.jpg">Since you liked ourpast Interviews so farwhere we talk withDevelopers across all PlayStation consoles- and especiallyone of our latest Interviewwhere wetalked with a Developer who tinkers with various consoles simultaneously- we thought about to do this again. Today's Guest is alsowell-known for releasing various Homebrew Applicationsmainly for thePlayStation Vita, but also for thePlayStation 4. In fact in this interview, you will learn not only what he released so far for both consoles, but alsowhat it means to develop for the PS Vita as for the PS4 in terms of "connectivity" for both consoles. But what does this mean exactly? Maybe you can remember back when the PS4 got presented back at E3 2013,Sony itself tried to make it more tasty for you not only to play with their newest Home Console, but also with the previous released PS Vita as well, especially when using the official "Remote Play" Feature. While this didn't worked quite well for Sony to be honest -although even the newest PS4 Games today still supports "Remote Play"- this Developer took a similar approachto understand the "connectivity" between both consoles but in terms of hacking them and to create useful Homebrew for it. And his results are impressive as well. So without further ado,our Guest Today is well-known multiconsole Developer@CelesteBlue.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-29T14:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Max Payne Mobile Ported to PS Vita / PS TV</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Max_Payne_Mobile_Ported_to_PS_Vita__PS_TV.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/max-payne-mobile-ported-to-ps-vita-ps-tv.32752/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Max_Payne_Mobile_Ported_to_PS_Vita__PS_TV.jpg">While the Vita scene patiently awaits the arrival of the nextGrand Theft Autoports rumored to be released soon, we have a surprise release coming fromfgsfdsandTheFloW. Today, the mobile version ofMax Paynehas been ported to the PS Vita / PS TV. Thanks to the recent release of TheFloW'skubridge, developers are able to bypass dynamic recompilation limits that had been previously set in place. You can take a look at the full list of credits in our dedicated resource thread (linked below) to see all the developers who helped in bringing this game to the PS Vita / PS TV.Similar to other ports,in order to enjoy Max Payne Mobile on your PS Vita / PS TV, you will need to obtain the legitimate assets from your own copy of the game. You will find detailed instructions on how​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-23T10:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 07) - Our Guest Today: "well known multi-console Developer @mathieulh"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._07)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well_known_multi-console_Developer_@mathieulh.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-07-our-guest-today-well-known-multi-console-developer-mathieulh.28915/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._07)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well_known_multi-console_Developer_@mathieulh.jpg">OurInterview Seriesconducted various Interviews with Developers, who worked either mainly for the PlayStation 3 or for the PlayStation 4 (andone time for the PlayStation Vita). But sometimes, there are well-known Developers who say to themselves thatworking on one console isn't enough for me. In fact the older readers will probably remember back when the magical 3.55 Firmware got hacked for the PS3 how many useful stuff we saw from the PSP Development for instance,which led into daily new releases and achievements for both consoles. As you can see, working on several consoles within the same "family" can be an advantage. So when we thought about new candidates for this series of interviews, we quickly recognized that if you want to interview a"multi-console" Developer, then there is someone, where his name will come immediately in every mind. In fact ournext candidate worked with so many both home and portable consoles in the past and still in present days, we would probaly need a complete new sub-section inside the forum to list all of his releases and achievements he did for the community.And you can't imagine how difficult it was for us "questioners" how to begin this interview with such a great person or how to find the right words for him. :P But somehow we think we managed it quite good and this time we have even aspecial question for our female readersout there. ^^ This man needs no more introduction.Here is our guest today, Developer@mathieulh!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-7T13:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Dreamcast Emulation Comes to PS Vita and PS TV with flycast-vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dreamcast_Emulation_Comes_to_PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_with_flycast-vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/dreamcast-emulation-comes-to-ps-vita-and-ps-tv-with-flycast-vita.32450/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dreamcast_Emulation_Comes_to_PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_with_flycast-vita.jpg">Earlier this year, there were plans put into motion by@Rinnegatamanteto bringDreamcast emulation to the PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV. Nowadays, the nameRinnegatamanteshould synonymous with Vita ports, as he is responsible for multiple major ports, all which come with a high level of polish. You will have to look no further than the work he andThe FlOwhave performed in bringingGrand Theft Auto IIInatively to the scene, and all the advancements that have been made since the initial release. Or, watch as the continually evolvingDaedalus X64(Nintendo 64 emulator) make leaps and bounds in allowing us to enjoy all of our favorite N64 games once again. Simply put, take a look at ourVita Homebrewsection of the forum to see all the hard work and amazing releasesRinnegatamantehas been providing for us.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-6T17:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita Monthly Release Round Up - December 2020</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Release_Round_Up_-_December_2020.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-monthly-release-round-up-december-2020.32439/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Release_Round_Up_-_December_2020.jpg">We are officially almost one week into the year of 2021, and in this article we are going to look back and see what goodies the month of December brought your PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV. Whether you were naughty or nice, the Vita scene developers still supplied us all with another round of amazing projects and updates. Let us take a glimpse at some of the gifts we received last month.@Rinnegatamantewas Santa's number one helper, with a total of four updates this holiday season, including three homebrew games (SuperMarioWar,mertious, andDstroy) and an update to the super popular Nintendo 64 emulator,Daedalus X64. Another one of Santa's elves, the developer by the name ofisage(a.k.a.sarcasticat), also game us two updates to existing homebrew games (Open Fodder Vita, anddevilutionX) as well as one new one (REminiscence). There were many, many more homebrew games and homebrew applications released this month, so please take a look at the list below for all the details. It is also important to mentiondevnoname120updated hisVitabrightplugin, as well as added a new user application (Vitabright Lut Editior) to allow us to easily adjust the...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
	</spc>
</nsx>