<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<nsx anno="" lt-id="131" min-sys-ver="1" rev="1093" ver="1.0">
	<spc anno="csxad=1&amp;adspace=9,10,11,12,13" id="33537" multi="o" rep="t">
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-8-1T20:30:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>FuHEN Contest Submissions - The Four of Us Are Dying / Beat2x / Zik-Zak Vita / Sonic SMS 3 Timelines</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/FuHEN_Contest_Submissions_-_The_Four_of_Us_Are_Dying__Beat2x__Zik-Zak_Vita__Sonic_SMS_3_Timelines.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/fuhen-contest-submissions-the-four-of-us-are-dying-beat2x-zik-zak-vita-sonic-sms-3-timelines.41305/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/FuHEN_Contest_Submissions_-_The_Four_of_Us_Are_Dying__Beat2x__Zik-Zak_Vita__Sonic_SMS_3_Timelines.jpg">The FuHEN - PS Vita Contest is underway and we have already 4 submissions that have been approved for entry: We have seen 3 Game Ports submitted and also a new Original Game for the PS Vita.  If you have not heard yet, there is a a PS Vita Contest that is currently on going and the submission period for projects is fromJuly 22nd, 2023  September 22nd, 2023You can learn more about the contest prizes, rules and the submissions process at the official website.We have an ambitious Original Game that has been in the making for awhile and aims to provide AAA graphics and effects. The gameplay is still early but the developer has big plans for the game called "The Four of us are Dying".byJosh Allen / noradninja.this game is a Silent Hill 2/Alan Wake style survival horror game.In the Game Port category we have seen 3 entries approved we have seen PS Vita legendary developer@Rinnegatamanteprovide three projects the first being"Beat2k" (A Dance Dance Revolution Clone)and also the developer has entered"Zik-Zak Vita"which is a great game that testes your reaction time getting through each level , Then@Rinnegatamantealso submitted "Eldritch" is a first person shooter inspired by games like roguelikes, immersive sims, and H. P. Lovecraft.  Then tou round out the first wave of entries we have seen developer@MDashKenter"Sonic SMS 3 Timelines"which is port of a fan made Sonic game that takes Sonic on a new adventure.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-3-2T20:38:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>Rinnegatamante ports 6 new title's  (Anomaly / Funky Smuggler's / Sleepwalker's Journey / ..</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Rinnegatamante_ports_6_new_title's__(Anomaly__Funky_Smuggler's__Sleepwalker's_Journey__...jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/rinnegatamante-ports-6-new-titles-anomaly-funky-smugglers-sleepwalkers-journey.39723/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Rinnegatamante_ports_6_new_title's__(Anomaly__Funky_Smuggler's__Sleepwalker's_Journey__...jpg">The PS Vita Scene has been nothing short of incredible if you enjoy homebrew and game port's, Since it's creator's abandon its hardware of the Ps Vita and its cousin the PlayStation TV.  The homebrew community took over, providing the platform a 2nd wind and it keeps getting better with new support for many games. Thanks to TheFlow release of the kubridge.skprx, that has allowed forsome Android gamesto be ported to the PS Vita we have nowseen 40 gamesnow ported to the Ps Vita, this does not even include the vast amount of homebrew available on the vita unrelated to Android Wrapper ports, Its been a healthy community with releases happening very often. Developer@Rinnegatamantehas been a developer who has provided many projects you can see afull list hereon his website Vita DB and many of this release threads for some of those projectshereNow the developer has been dropped 6 new ports for the ps vita, These Android/wrapper ports Include​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-1-15T23:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>Quakespasm-Spiked v1.6 Update released by @Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Quakespasm-Spiked_v1.6_Update_released_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/quakespasm-spiked-v1-6-update-released-by-rinnegatamante.39095/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Quakespasm-Spiked_v1.6_Update_released_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg">If you are a fan of Retro first person shooter's or the Iconic Quake Series, then developer@Rinnegatamantehas something that you may enjoy for your PS VIta or PlayStation TV enabled for Homebrew, The famed Vita developer stopped by the official release thread ofQuakespasm-Spiketo drop the v1.6 updateThe update labeled as version 1.6  has fixed a number of bugs, along with a few new options that have been added, Also the developer has possibly a solution to use higher demanding mods by increasing the available memory for the engine. All the details can be seen in the changelog below, for setup instruction and additional details see the link at bottom of this post​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-1-14T00:31:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Dead Space v1.3  (Vita Port) Released by gl33ntwine</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Dead_Space_v1.3__(Vita_Port)_Released_by_gl33ntwine.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/dead-space-v1-3-vita-port-released-by-gl33ntwine.39039/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Dead_Space_v1.3__(Vita_Port)_Released_by_gl33ntwine.jpg">The release of v1.3Dead Space (Vita)has been released by developer @gl33ntwine, in this update the developer has made several improvements and enchanments with analog contols, FPS limiter option, to fix the audio cut off issue's the developer hopes increasing the audio buffer to 1MB will do the trick, See Complete changelog provided in the details below.In order to play this game you will need as quoted from the readme  "Legally obtain your copy ofDead Space Mobile for Xperia Playin a form of an.apk file.The version for regular Android devices, also known as the latest/Google Play version,will not work!Make sure that your game isv1.1.33(this is the last one supported on Xperia Play and provided via EA Store back in 2012)." so be sure to grab the right game if you do not already own it.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-12-28T08:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>HENlo - WebKit+Kernel exploit chain for all PS Vita firmwares by TheFl0w</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/HENlo_-_WebKit+Kernel_exploit_chain_for_all_PS_Vita_firmwares_by_TheFl0w.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/henlo-webkit-kernel-exploit-chain-for-all-ps-vita-firmwares-by-thefl0w.38982/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/HENlo_-_WebKit+Kernel_exploit_chain_for_all_PS_Vita_firmwares_by_TheFl0w.jpg">Well known console developer and hackerAndy Nguyen@theflow0has released an old project of his for the PS Vita a "WebKit+Kernel exploit chain for all PS Vita firmwares" the exploit works, but the developer never made into a full jailbreak as there really has never been a need. Its just another solution to have around but the most useful part may just be the research for others at this moment. The hacker has made a few comments about the release as we have attached below the quotes and related links to the project.This release is more for the development and developer's who wish to learn more as we already have solutions for the PS Vita and PSTV but the developer does hope to see someone pick up the project and make a full jailbreak out of it. As the developer states it could be a great learning experience for some to finish the project.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-25T20:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Apollo Save Tool v1.1.0 - View bucanero latest changes to the PS Vita port</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.1.0_-_View_bucanero_latest_changes_to_the_PS_Vita_port.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/apollo-save-tool-v1-1-0-view-bucanero-latest-changes-to-the-ps-vita-port.38551/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.1.0_-_View_bucanero_latest_changes_to_the_PS_Vita_port.jpg">Developer@bucanerohas a new update forApollo Save Tool (Vita), as some of you may or may not know the developer also has aPS3andPS4version of the homebrew utility available for those platforms as well. The utility is a great app for your save game files as you can resign and unlock and even download save's from other from the database.  The tool originally debuted on the PS3 when developer@bucaneroforked the GUI ofArtemis-a Cheat Engine by Dnawrkshp for the PS3Since thatPS3 releaseand many updates we seen aPS4 versionemerge and also aPS Vita port.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-25T19:19:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Flycast-Vita  (Dreamcast Emulator) v1.1:  Fast GDRom Load option + Latest downstreamed commits</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Flycast-Vita__(Dreamcast_Emulator)_v1.1__Fast_GDRom_Load_option_+_Latest_downstreamed_commits.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/flycast-vita-dreamcast-emulator-v1-1-fast-gdrom-load-option-latest-downstreamed-commits.38548/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Flycast-Vita__(Dreamcast_Emulator)_v1.1__Fast_GDRom_Load_option_+_Latest_downstreamed_commits.jpg">PlayStation Vita developer@Rinnegatamantecontinues the magic in the homebrew scene.  Over the last weeks we have already seen various release's likeDoom64EX/VitaDB Downloader/RigelEngine Vita /Zelda3 Vitaand today the developer stopped by the forum to release v1.1 update ofFlycast-Vita (Dreamcast Emulator),in this update the option for "Fast GDRom Load" has been added, this will provide faster loading times, however the v1.1 chanelog also warns that some games may cause more issues then benefits with this option enables.  Also in the update this port was Downstreamed to the latest official Flycast commit, Take note that BoxArt Support is now disabled by default. This should help performance if you have alot of roms in your directory.Find the installation process and setup along with some tips in the official release thread >here< in the psx-place forums​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-8-24T21:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Latest Vita Homebrew by @Rinnegatamante includes Flycast (Dreamcast) / Nanosaur / Wordle / Tomb Rai.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Latest_Vita_Homebrew_by_@Rinnegatamante_includes_Flycast_(Dreamcast)__Nanosaur__Wordle__Tomb_Rai..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/latest-vita-homebrew-by-rinnegatamante-includes-flycast-dreamcast-nanosaur-wordle-tomb-rai.38191/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Latest_Vita_Homebrew_by_@Rinnegatamante_includes_Flycast_(Dreamcast)__Nanosaur__Wordle__Tomb_Rai..jpg">PS Vita Developer@Rinnegatamantehas shared several releases in the psx-place forum's over the past week(s), One of the highlights was released in recent days has been a major update toFlycast Vita-(A Sega Dreamcast emulator)for the PS Vita and PlaStation TV (PSTV) . Updating from the initial release ofv0.1 from Jan. 2021tonow v1.0.2with assistance from developer@Bythosfor the latest update.Earlier in the month of August we seen Rinnegatamante with two other ports released here in the forums with:Nanosaur Vita  (A Port of Nanosaur)&Wordle SDL(A clone of Wordle),which are both welcome additions to the Vita collection. Developer rinnegatamante has been busy with various other release's as well over the past few months.    In case you missed some of the other recent releases from@Rinnegatamantelike theTomb Raider 1 & 2 Classic Collectionsport to the Vita, you can also checkout his...​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-3-1T00:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>uKaruga demake (new) + VitaRTCW (Return to Castle Wolfenstien) v0.5 update by Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uKaruga_demake_(new)_+_VitaRTCW_(Return_to_Castle_Wolfenstien)_v0.5_update_by_Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ukaruga-demake-new-vitartcw-return-to-castle-wolfenstien-v0-5-update-by-rinnegatamante.36656/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uKaruga_demake_(new)_+_VitaRTCW_(Return_to_Castle_Wolfenstien)_v0.5_update_by_Rinnegatamante.jpg">Following up on the recent update ofvitaFF4 v1.2,  developer@Rinnegatamantehas also updated another existing project withv0.5 of VitaRTCW(Return to Castle Wolfenstein based on iortcw) which incorporates the latest vitaGL changes and graphical enchantments like fixing of fog rending  also a new Aim Assist Feature for single player has been added in this update. Then the vita developer also introduced a new homebrew release with a very interesting demake with the release ofnKaruga.A vertical shoot 'em up game that is a"demake popular bullet hell game Ikaruga, released in 2002 for Dreamcast and 2003 for Gamecube".​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-2-18T20:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>FF4-Vita v.1.2:   Final Fantasy IV (Android) port for PS-Vita by Rinnegatamante, frangarcj & TheFloW</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/FF4-Vita_v.1.2___Final_Fantasy_IV_(Android)_port_for_PS-Vita_by_Rinnegatamante,_frangarcj_&_TheFloW.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ff4-vita-v-1-2-final-fantasy-iv-android-port-for-ps-vita-by-rinnegatamante-frangarcj-theflow.36556/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/FF4-Vita_v.1.2___Final_Fantasy_IV_(Android)_port_for_PS-Vita_by_Rinnegatamante,_frangarcj_&_TheFloW.jpg">PS Vita developer'sRinnegatamante,frangarcj&TheFloWhave updated their Wrapper/Port ofFinal Fantasy 4 (IV)(Android)for your PS Vita or PlayStation TV(& Vita TV}to version 1.2 with a few new changes and enchantments by updating to the latest vitaShaRK & vitaGL commits, Also included in v1.2 an added option to swapOandXbutton functionality and to round out the update the added possibility to "force english dub usage". was added in 1.2If you are fan of Final Fantasy and have a Homebrew enabled PS Vita (or PS TV), then you must checkout the other android ports ofFinal Fantasy III&Final Fantasy V (5)from this same trio of talented developer's. Also, checkout some of other projects by these developer's found at VitaDB.viewRinnegatamante,frangarcj&TheFloWpages for more excellent brew by these developer's who continue to share some great projects to us all. You will find great projects like a wrapper ports ofGrand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars&Grand Theft Auto: San Andreasand many other projects that are now powered by the community supported PS Vita Platform, lead by some great developer's that have brought some amazing projects to the platform.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-9T11:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN 3.4.0 + HFW 4.92 - Officially released by esc0rtd3w of Team PS3Xploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3HEN_3.4.0_+_HFW_4.92_-_Officially_released_by_esc0rtd3w_of_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-3-4-0-hfw-4-92-officially-released-by-esc0rtd3w-of-team-ps3xploit.46959/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3HEN_3.4.0_+_HFW_4.92_-_Officially_released_by_esc0rtd3w_of_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg">PS3 Developer@esc0rtd3whas released the latest update toPS3HENwith support to recent firmware updateof 4.92.  Along with the PS3HEN update is the release ofHybrid Firmware (HFW), which is just an official firmware (4.92) with the "silk_webkit.sprx" file replace from 4.82 OFW (that has a vulnerability patched in 4.83 OFW, the last attempt Sony made to curb homebrew). HFW was created by@Joonieand has been apart of this 4.92 release of well.There have been a number of new changes in this update marked v3.4.0 as it does not just provide 4.92 support but various changes as seen in the changelog provided​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-5T21:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 4.92 Official FIrmware has been released - PS3 CFW & PS3HEN DO NOT UPDATE to 4.92</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3_4.92_Official_FIrmware_has_been_released_-_PS3_CFW_&_PS3HEN_DO_NOT_UPDATE_to_4.92.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-4-92-official-firmware-has-been-released-ps3-cfw-ps3hen-do-not-update-to-4-92.46837/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3_4.92_Official_FIrmware_has_been_released_-_PS3_CFW_&_PS3HEN_DO_NOT_UPDATE_to_4.92.jpg">As expectedthe PlayStation 3 has receivedfirmware update 4.92, if you are currently usingPS3HENorCFWyouSHOULD NOT updateyour PS3 Firmware to 4.92 at this time. Otherwise you will be temporary losing your jailbreak's and ability to run homebrew on the console, until developer's release new exploits/jailbreaks that support the new 4.92 firmware update. There isa processin which need to take place for things to catch up, as developer's@bguerville@esc0rtd3w@Evilnatand other's havebeen readyfor the update to launch to get to work quickly.We learned last week that@bguervillehas an update for the PS3 Toolset with new features being deployed as the developer explains in these two post >1<​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-12-25T12:44:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Update 4.91.3  > > > [PS3 CFW] Evilnat's 4.91.2 Custom Firmware's Collection Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Update_4.91.3_____[PS3_CFW]_Evilnat's_4.91.2_Custom_Firmware's_Collection_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-4-91-3-ps3-cfw-evilnats-4-91-2-custom-firmwares-collection-released.45604/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Update_4.91.3_____[PS3_CFW]_Evilnat's_4.91.2_Custom_Firmware's_Collection_Released.jpg">UPDATEJanuary 2025:CFW Evilnat 4.91.3[BETA 1] released>>Click Here<<December '24:Merry Christmas and Happy Holiday's to everyone, PS3 Custom firmware developer@Evilnathas dropped by the psx-place forum's on this Christmas day to present the final build(4.91.2)of the developer's ps3 Custom Firmware suite, after a series of Open Beta releases, v4.91.2  now officially drops the "BETA" tag and in its final form for 4.91.2.  For discussion and full details about this PS3 firmware release and the various cfw types offered in this suite of releases, checkout the developer's release thread here in the forum's detailing all the various features and functions in Evilnat's latest releases notes and details for4.91 Evilnat's CFW (w/ Cobra v8.5).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-11-8T00:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>New PS1/PS2 Emulation Features for PS3 CFW user's + Evilnat's 4.91.2-BETA 12</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/New_PS1PS2_Emulation_Features_for_PS3_CFW_user's_+_Evilnat's_4.91.2-BETA_12.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/new-ps1-ps2-emulation-features-for-ps3-cfw-users-evilnats-4-91-2-beta-12.45233/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/New_PS1PS2_Emulation_Features_for_PS3_CFW_user's_+_Evilnat's_4.91.2-BETA_12.jpg">UPDATE: January 2025:ps2gxemu (for CECH-C/E ps3 models) has been updated by@kozarovv+ netemu to gxemu config conversion tool by@Zarhas been released, see details at bottomNov. 2024:  Recently we have had some great news with developments surroundingPS1 & PS2 Emulation on the PS3 for Custom Firmware user'sas the emulator's that reside in the PlayStation 3 Firmware have receivedsome modded tweaksthanks to@kozarovv&@mrjaredbeta, The files can be added manually to many firmware's or you can update to the latest release ofEvilnat's 4.91.2 CFW (BETA 12)that have these newly modded emulator's already installed and ready to go thanks to@Evilnat.The changes and feature's depend on the PS2/PS1 emulator being used and also on which model of the PS3 (with PS2). Below you will find a brief explanation of the emulator, mixed in with the readme details and some added screenshot. Some of the feature's need more testing to see how affective they may be such as the partial antiblur and EE Overclocking/Underclocking patches.  View all the details and related links found below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-7-16T21:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>CFW Flash Writer - Unofficial 4.91 update</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/CFW_Flash_Writer_-_Unofficial_4.91_update.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/cfw-flash-writer-unofficial-4-91-update.44229/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/CFW_Flash_Writer_-_Unofficial_4.91_update.jpg">Developer@aldostoolshas released an unofficial update for theCFW Flash Writerto supportHFW 4.91on the PS3. This can be a secondary candidate for allowing Custom Firmware installations whenbguerville's PS3Toolset (https://www.ps3toolset.com/bgtoolset/)isn't accessible or a self hosting offline option. However, ThePs3toolset is still the preferred  and safest method when available for hacking your capable ps3 model so its ready for PS3 Custom Firmware installations.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-4-30T22:05:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PPPwn - PlayStation 4 PPPoE RCE - (The First PS4 Kernel RCE - Supporting upto FW 11.00) by TheFlow</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PPPwn_-_PlayStation_4_PPPoE_RCE_-_(The_First_PS4_Kernel_RCE_-_Supporting_upto_FW_11.00)_by_TheFlow.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pppwn-playstation-4-pppoe-rce-the-first-ps4-kernel-rce-supporting-upto-fw-11-00-by-theflow.43655/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PPPwn_-_PlayStation_4_PPPoE_RCE_-_(The_First_PS4_Kernel_RCE_-_Supporting_upto_FW_11.00)_by_TheFlow.jpg">Scene Developer & HackerTheFlowwho has been a legend in various PlayStation Scene's, has done it yet again!! This time the developer has released "The first PlayStation 4 Kernel RCE, Supporting FWs upto 11.00".With the newly released (PoC) jailbreak the community will be able to update popular Homebrew Enabler's (Mira & GoldHEN) to support firmware 11.00 with this new jailbreak that TheFlow has disclosed (CVE-2006-4304) through the bounty program and has been patched in the latest PS4 firmware available​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-16T23:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Official PS3 Toolset Update (v1.2.007) Release (4.91 Support)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Official_PS3_Toolset_Update_(v1.2.007)_Release_(4.91_Support).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-ps3-toolset-update-v1-2-007-release-4-91-support.43211/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Official_PS3_Toolset_Update_(v1.2.007)_Release_(4.91_Support).jpg">FollowingSony firmware update of 4.91for the PS3, developer's across the scene have been updating various exploits and tools. We have seen developer@Evilnatrelease his4.91 PS3 Custom Firmware'searlier in the week. Then we recently just had@esc0rtd3w&@JoonieprovidePS3HEN (& HFW) updated with 4.91 Support. Now we have developer@bguervillewith an update to hisPS3 Toolsetto support the exploiting of 4.91 OFW for custom firmware installation for capable models.​</description>
			<creators>bguerville</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-16T07:42:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Official PS3HEN v3.3.0  + HFW Released for 4.91 Firmware from Team PS3Xploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Official_PS3HEN_v3.3.0__+_HFW_Released_for_4.91_Firmware_from_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-ps3hen-v3-3-0-hfw-released-for-4-91-firmware-from-team-ps3xploit.43199/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Official_PS3HEN_v3.3.0__+_HFW_Released_for_4.91_Firmware_from_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg">TheOfficial PS3HENexploit has beenupdated to v3.3.0with some new changes from@esc0rtd3wand@JoonieofTeam PS3Xploitto support 4.91.  Also, developer Joonie has brought back the webkit exploit from 4.82 to 4.91 with the official HFW release(HFW = OFW with old webkit injected). Its best to use the official HFW when using the official PS3HEN release.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-9T19:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update Re-Release] PS3 Custom Firmware - 4.91 Evilnat Cobra (8.4) CFW Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/[Update_Re-Release]_PS3_Custom_Firmware_-_4.91_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.4)_CFW_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-re-release-ps3-custom-firmware-4-91-evilnat-cobra-8-4-cfw-released.43110/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/[Update_Re-Release]_PS3_Custom_Firmware_-_4.91_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.4)_CFW_Released.jpg">UPDATE -See 1st post for details, Re-Release a few bugs correctedPlayStation 3 CFW developer@Evilnathas just released his much anticipated4.91 Evilnat Custom Firmwarefollowingthe recent routine updatefrom Sony when they dropped firmware 4.91 last week.  If you are on any Custom Firmware currently all you have to do is install this CFW PuP by the USB method. You will not need to wait for an update to bguerville's PS3 Toolset to exploit your system (as its already exploited if you are running CFW).If you had updated to 4.91 OFW or by mistake installed a HFW you will have to wait for the PS3 Toolset to be updated. Developerbguervillewas waiting for the first 4.91 CFW to drop before making his update and that has just occurred with this release, so it should not be to long before we see bguerville provide a 4.91 update to the toolset as the developerdescribed herein the psx-place forums..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-2-27T05:25:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 4.91 Firmware Released - Do Not Update!!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3_4.91_Firmware_Released_-_Do_Not_Update!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-4-91-firmware-released-do-not-update.42992/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3_4.91_Firmware_Released_-_Do_Not_Update!!!.jpg">UPDATE:its now safe to update to 4.91. PS3HEN (& HFW), CFW & PS3 Toolset have been updated to support 4.91.PS3 Firmware 4.91 is now LiveThe expected once a year firmware update has been executed by Sony, PS3 4.91 Firmware is now Live. While an expected update, could this bring other changes to the firmware? Likely not but its still early to conclude as this update is fresh as of writing .Do not update, various exploits / tools / essential homebrew will need to be updated to support the latest firmware update of 4.91. See below for a short FAQ on 4.91, as there is always some confusions around the update process. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-30T10:41:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Movian M7 (by deank)  - "libav" swapped for "ffmpeg"  & slight name change</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Movian_M7_(by_deank)__-_libav_swapped_for_ffmpeg__&_slight_name_change.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/movian-m7-by-deank-libav-swapped-for-ffmpeg-slight-name-change.42453/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Movian_M7_(by_deank)__-_libav_swapped_for_ffmpeg__&_slight_name_change.jpg">Developer@deankwho has been continuing development of the (modded version) of the original media center that started on the PS3(now runs on Android, Amazon Fire Stick, MacOS ,Windown ,Linux  & Raspberry pi). The media center originally was named "Showtime" on the PS3 but later renamed to "Movian" by the original developerAndreas Omanyears ago.Since that time, we have not seen the official project do much in recent years (currentlyhome siteis down as of writing), but developer deank has been keeping the project alive and evolving (see changelogsover at brewologyfor all archived changes). One of the biggest changes you will see within Movian-M7 compared to older version, is the change from the older (abandoned) "libav" video decoders/parsers to the current "ffmpeg" that was just replaced in the recent M7 update . This should improve compatibility and make for a more up-to date and versatile media player for all supported platforms including the PS3.Also, deank  has made a quick stop in the forum's, then to see a reported issue and provided a fix (seen here) that is now present in v7.0.2​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-27T22:41:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.06] Itemzflow (PS5) -  Homebrew & Game Manager with PS5 game Support</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/[Update_v1.06]_Itemzflow_(PS5)_-__Homebrew_&_Game_Manager_with_PS5_game_Support.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-06-itemzflow-ps5-homebrew-game-manager-with-ps5-game-support.42429/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/[Update_v1.06]_Itemzflow_(PS5)_-__Homebrew_&_Game_Manager_with_PS5_game_Support.jpg">Following the release ofetaHEN(AIO Homebrew Enabler for the PS5)last month from@lightingModz.Now, the release ofItemzFlowhas arrived for the PlayStation 5 from developer @ligthingmodz. Originally thisHomebrew & Game Managerwas released on the PS4, but the developer has made a special Christmas Release now bringing the homebrew app for the PS5 that is handy for managing and preserving your personal backups.(JUN 27, 2024) Update: v1.06has been released with new improvements and features.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-12-19T21:10:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Alien Resurrection - (A cheat code to unlock boot disc feature for backups)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Alien_Resurrection_-_(A_cheat_code_to_unlock_boot_disc_feature_for_backups).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/alien-resurrection-a-cheat-code-to-unlock-boot-disc-feature-for-backups.42354/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Alien_Resurrection_-_(A_cheat_code_to_unlock_boot_disc_feature_for_backups).jpg">This is a very interesting discovery or rather disclosure from one of the developer's of the PlayStation 1 (PS1) gameAlien Resurrection(Martin Piper) who had reached out to YouTuberMVGwho has been given permission to disclose something that has always been there all this time in the game, but needed a cheat code to unlock the ability to run backups on a stock retail PS1, acting as a boot disc for the swap method.  MVG details the process here in this video:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-11-5T08:21:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.8B] etaHEN - AIO Homebrew enabler for the PS5</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/default.png</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-8b-etahen-aio-homebrew-enabler-for-the-ps5.42050/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/[Update_v1.8B]_etaHEN_-_AIO_Homebrew_enabler_for_the_PS5.jpg">The PlayStation 5 has an early Christmas gift this year as developerLighting Modshas releasedetaHEN - AIO Homebrew Enabler for the PlayStation 5 (PS5), Currently there is not much homebrew to launch for the PS5, but the developer hasported his PS4 HB Store to the PlayStation 5and thanks to theability to run PS4 fpkgs on the PS5, there is various PS4 homebrew that can run such as some of Lapy's homebrew games.Update (Aug. 12):New update has been released by @ligthingmods, now bringing etaHEN to v1.8B, See changelog tab below or guthub links for latest changes and features incorporated in this update and other updates since its release that has jump started the PS5 community. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-10-14T10:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Celebrating Nine Year's of PSX-Place.com</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/default.png</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/celebrating-nine-years-of-psx-place-com.41855/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Celebrating_Nine_Year's_of_PSX-Place.com.jpg">The psx-place.com website celebrates its 9th birthday on this day, originally opening in2014onOctober 14to the public. The site remains a pillar in the PlayStation Homebrew / Hacking community, thanks to the tremendous developer & user support that has blessed our forums. The past 9 years we have witnessed some amazing things in these forums, we have seen idea's and theories mature into full blown exploits and projects, we have seen developer's share and bounce idea to each other and even teamed up, which have spawned and improved many projects/aspects in the community. We have seen many developer's choose the psx-place forum to host their Release/Support threads for their projects. It has been a destination for developer's and user's to learn more about the community and even take part in it. Truly a place where people can come together for a common goal and that goal has been getting the most out of our beloved PlayStation devices.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-8-12T07:19:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Athena - A performant JavaScript Runtime Environment for the PS2</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/default.png</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/athena-a-performant-javascript-runtime-environment-for-the-ps2.41393/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/Athena_-_A_performant_JavaScript_Runtime_Environment_for_the_PS2.jpg">AthenaEnv (JavaScript-Runtime) and the bright future of development on the PS2!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-6-21T17:22:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Future of the PlayStation 2 Internal Hard Drive by Berion</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/The_Future_of_the_PlayStation_2_Internal_Hard_Drive_by_Berion.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-future-of-the-playstation-2-internal-hard-drive-by-berion.40924/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/The_Future_of_the_PlayStation_2_Internal_Hard_Drive_by_Berion.jpg">The Future of the PlayStation 2 Internal Hard DriveWe have recently started 2023, and the so-called PlayStation 2 console scene is surprisingly still doing well, yes, even better than ever before and better than on not one newer platform! And one of the leading projects that anyone interested can mention without a long moment's hesitation isOpen PS2 Loader- the successor to HDLoader and USB Advance, a program used to run games from USB, i.Link (FireWire), MX4SIO (a reader for e.g. SDXC in the Memory Card slot), the local network and the internal hard drive, whose operation is still stuck in the darkness of the Middle Ages.Before I get into specifics, it's worth recalling what the current, extremely exotic logical disk structure that Sony designed looks like, and which is supported by every software written to date that supports theinternalhard drive. Without understanding the APA, you won't understand the idea of a hybrid drive. It is only later that I will discuss the concept of building a Frankenstein with something modern, familiar, while providing a full or residual layer of compatibility.​</description>
			<creators>Berion</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-5-4T20:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>(Update) Baryon Sweeper: Unbrick PSP 1000, 2000, 3000 /PSP Slim 04g, 07g, 09g/ PSP Street 11g  model</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/default.png</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-baryon-sweeper-unbrick-psp-1000-2000-3000-psp-slim-04g-07g-09g-psp-street-11g-model.32503/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/(Update)_Baryon_Sweeper_Unbrick_PSP_1000,_2000,_3000_PSP_Slim_04g,_07g,_09g_PSP_Street_11g__model.jpg">Update (May - 2023):Now PSP models Slim 04g, 07g, 09g models, & the PSP Street 11g model are now supported >> See Details from@zecoxaoin the post via>>this link<<Original Article (Jan 2021): For more than ten years PSP-3000 owner's have been used to the fact that their device couldn't be restored (unbricked) at home. Many fear the brick as if it's the worst nightmare that could ever happen when experimenting with your device.  Even worse in 2021, now because warranty for all PSPs are over, so bricked later (psp) models go either for parts or are doomed to dust in boxes and drawers they'd never return from... that is, if this thread didn't appear with the release ofBaryon Sweeper R1:^)​</description>
			<creators>zecoxao</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-4-1T01:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN v3.2.2 - New Additions/ Fixes & Backported Firmware's  Support from Team PS3Xploit.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/default.png</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-v3-2-2-new-additions-fixes-backported-firmwares-support-from-team-ps3xploit.40129/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>
			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/PS3HEN_v3.2.2_-_New_Additions_Fixes_&_Backported_Firmware's__Support_from_Team_PS3Xploit..jpg">Update 4/25/2023: PS3HEN 3.2.2 has been released. Check the changelog for details.We have seen a lot of developer's back in the fold after the4.90 official firmware updatethat hit the PlayStation 3 several weeks ago. We seen a couple weeks ago developer's@Joonieand@esc0rtd3wof thePs3Xploit Teamupdate Ps3HEN to v3.2.0, now we have a new update with the release of v3.2.1..Ps3HENis a Homebrew Enabler that is an alternative exploit to custom firmware (cfw) for models that can not install a CFW. unlikecustom firmwareon the ps3, Ps3HEN has the ability to run on all ps3 model's, while many feature that are in CFW can be found in PS3HEN it does not completely replicate the CFW experience so if your PS3 has the ability to run a CFW that is the better route, but Ps3HEN is a very powerful and capable exploit. See a CFW vs Ps3HEN comparison>here<for a rundown of feature's.In the update v3.2.1, there has been a number of changes and added support to Ps3HEN.@Jooniehas released a backport ofHFW (hybrid firmware) for 4.83, this was done as Ps3HEN has provided support for 4.83 FW, plus 4.84 DEX firmware is also now supported.  There has been a number of other supported firmware and various other changes in the payload and plugin to PS3HEN, Plus this fixes the wMM bug that was creating freezing issue in v3.2.0.  See latest changelogs provided below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
	</spc>
</nsx>