<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<nsx anno="" lt-id="131" min-sys-ver="1" rev="1093" ver="1.0">
	<spc anno="csxad=1&amp;adspace=9,10,11,12,13" id="33537" multi="o" rep="t">
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-8-1T20:30:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>FuHEN Contest Submissions - The Four of Us Are Dying / Beat2x / Zik-Zak Vita / Sonic SMS 3 Timelines</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FuHEN_Contest_Submissions_-_The_Four_of_Us_Are_Dying__Beat2x__Zik-Zak_Vita__Sonic_SMS_3_Timelines.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/fuhen-contest-submissions-the-four-of-us-are-dying-beat2x-zik-zak-vita-sonic-sms-3-timelines.41305/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FuHEN_Contest_Submissions_-_The_Four_of_Us_Are_Dying__Beat2x__Zik-Zak_Vita__Sonic_SMS_3_Timelines.jpg">The FuHEN - PS Vita Contest is underway and we have already 4 submissions that have been approved for entry: We have seen 3 Game Ports submitted and also a new Original Game for the PS Vita.  If you have not heard yet, there is a a PS Vita Contest that is currently on going and the submission period for projects is fromJuly 22nd, 2023  September 22nd, 2023You can learn more about the contest prizes, rules and the submissions process at the official website.We have an ambitious Original Game that has been in the making for awhile and aims to provide AAA graphics and effects. The gameplay is still early but the developer has big plans for the game called "The Four of us are Dying".byJosh Allen / noradninja.this game is a Silent Hill 2/Alan Wake style survival horror game.In the Game Port category we have seen 3 entries approved we have seen PS Vita legendary developer@Rinnegatamanteprovide three projects the first being"Beat2k" (A Dance Dance Revolution Clone)and also the developer has entered"Zik-Zak Vita"which is a great game that testes your reaction time getting through each level , Then@Rinnegatamantealso submitted "Eldritch" is a first person shooter inspired by games like roguelikes, immersive sims, and H. P. Lovecraft.  Then tou round out the first wave of entries we have seen developer@MDashKenter"Sonic SMS 3 Timelines"which is port of a fan made Sonic game that takes Sonic on a new adventure.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-3-2T20:38:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>Rinnegatamante ports 6 new title's  (Anomaly / Funky Smuggler's / Sleepwalker's Journey / ........</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Rinnegatamante_ports_6_new_title's__(Anomaly__Funky_Smuggler's__Sleepwalker's_Journey__.........jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/rinnegatamante-ports-6-new-titles-anomaly-funky-smugglers-sleepwalkers-journey.39723/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Rinnegatamante_ports_6_new_title's__(Anomaly__Funky_Smuggler's__Sleepwalker's_Journey__.........jpg">The PS Vita Scene has been nothing short of incredible if you enjoy homebrew and game port's, Since it's creator's abandon its hardware of the Ps Vita and its cousin the PlayStation TV.  The homebrew community took over, providing the platform a 2nd wind and it keeps getting better with new support for many games. Thanks to TheFlow release of the kubridge.skprx, that has allowed forsome Android gamesto be ported to the PS Vita we have nowseen 40 gamesnow ported to the Ps Vita, this does not even include the vast amount of homebrew available on the vita unrelated to Android Wrapper ports, Its been a healthy community with releases happening very often. Developer@Rinnegatamantehas been a developer who has provided many projects you can see afull list hereon his website Vita DB and many of this release threads for some of those projectshereNow the developer has been dropped 6 new ports for the ps vita, These Android/wrapper ports Include​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-1-15T23:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z" anno="picks=1">
			<desc>Quakespasm-Spiked v1.6 Update released by @Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Quakespasm-Spiked_v1.6_Update_released_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/quakespasm-spiked-v1-6-update-released-by-rinnegatamante.39095/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Quakespasm-Spiked_v1.6_Update_released_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg">If you are a fan of Retro first person shooter's or the Iconic Quake Series, then developer@Rinnegatamantehas something that you may enjoy for your PS VIta or PlayStation TV enabled for Homebrew, The famed Vita developer stopped by the official release thread ofQuakespasm-Spiketo drop the v1.6 updateThe update labeled as version 1.6  has fixed a number of bugs, along with a few new options that have been added, Also the developer has possibly a solution to use higher demanding mods by increasing the available memory for the engine. All the details can be seen in the changelog below, for setup instruction and additional details see the link at bottom of this post​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2023-1-14T00:31:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Dead Space v1.3  (Vita Port) Released by gl33ntwine</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dead_Space_v1.3__(Vita_Port)_Released_by_gl33ntwine.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/dead-space-v1-3-vita-port-released-by-gl33ntwine.39039/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dead_Space_v1.3__(Vita_Port)_Released_by_gl33ntwine.jpg">The release of v1.3Dead Space (Vita)has been released by developer @gl33ntwine, in this update the developer has made several improvements and enchanments with analog contols, FPS limiter option, to fix the audio cut off issue's the developer hopes increasing the audio buffer to 1MB will do the trick, See Complete changelog provided in the details below.In order to play this game you will need as quoted from the readme  "Legally obtain your copy ofDead Space Mobile for Xperia Playin a form of an.apk file.The version for regular Android devices, also known as the latest/Google Play version,will not work!Make sure that your game isv1.1.33(this is the last one supported on Xperia Play and provided via EA Store back in 2012)." so be sure to grab the right game if you do not already own it.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-12-28T08:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>HENlo - WebKit+Kernel exploit chain for all PS Vita firmwares by TheFl0w</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/HENlo_-_WebKit+Kernel_exploit_chain_for_all_PS_Vita_firmwares_by_TheFl0w.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/henlo-webkit-kernel-exploit-chain-for-all-ps-vita-firmwares-by-thefl0w.38982/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/HENlo_-_WebKit+Kernel_exploit_chain_for_all_PS_Vita_firmwares_by_TheFl0w.jpg">Well known console developer and hackerAndy Nguyen@theflow0has released an old project of his for the PS Vita a "WebKit+Kernel exploit chain for all PS Vita firmwares" the exploit works, but the developer never made into a full jailbreak as there really has never been a need. Its just another solution to have around but the most useful part may just be the research for others at this moment. The hacker has made a few comments about the release as we have attached below the quotes and related links to the project.This release is more for the development and developer's who wish to learn more as we already have solutions for the PS Vita and PSTV but the developer does hope to see someone pick up the project and make a full jailbreak out of it. As the developer states it could be a great learning experience for some to finish the project.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-25T20:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Apollo Save Tool v1.1.0 - View bucanero latest changes to the PS Vita port</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.1.0_-_View_bucanero_latest_changes_to_the_PS_Vita_port.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/apollo-save-tool-v1-1-0-view-bucanero-latest-changes-to-the-ps-vita-port.38551/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.1.0_-_View_bucanero_latest_changes_to_the_PS_Vita_port.jpg">Developer@bucanerohas a new update forApollo Save Tool (Vita), as some of you may or may not know the developer also has aPS3andPS4version of the homebrew utility available for those platforms as well. The utility is a great app for your save game files as you can resign and unlock and even download save's from other from the database.  The tool originally debuted on the PS3 when developer@bucaneroforked the GUI ofArtemis-a Cheat Engine by Dnawrkshp for the PS3Since thatPS3 releaseand many updates we seen aPS4 versionemerge and also aPS Vita port.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-10-25T19:19:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Flycast-Vita  (Dreamcast Emulator) v1.1:  Fast GDRom Load option + Latest downstreamed commits</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Flycast-Vita__(Dreamcast_Emulator)_v1.1__Fast_GDRom_Load_option_+_Latest_downstreamed_commits.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/flycast-vita-dreamcast-emulator-v1-1-fast-gdrom-load-option-latest-downstreamed-commits.38548/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Flycast-Vita__(Dreamcast_Emulator)_v1.1__Fast_GDRom_Load_option_+_Latest_downstreamed_commits.jpg">PlayStation Vita developer@Rinnegatamantecontinues the magic in the homebrew scene.  Over the last weeks we have already seen various release's likeDoom64EX/VitaDB Downloader/RigelEngine Vita /Zelda3 Vitaand today the developer stopped by the forum to release v1.1 update ofFlycast-Vita (Dreamcast Emulator),in this update the option for "Fast GDRom Load" has been added, this will provide faster loading times, however the v1.1 chanelog also warns that some games may cause more issues then benefits with this option enables.  Also in the update this port was Downstreamed to the latest official Flycast commit, Take note that BoxArt Support is now disabled by default. This should help performance if you have alot of roms in your directory.Find the installation process and setup along with some tips in the official release thread >here< in the psx-place forums​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-8-24T21:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Latest Vita Homebrew by @Rinnegatamante includes Flycast (Dreamcast) / Nanosaur / Wordle / Tomb Rai.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Latest_Vita_Homebrew_by_@Rinnegatamante_includes_Flycast_(Dreamcast)__Nanosaur__Wordle__Tomb_Rai..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/latest-vita-homebrew-by-rinnegatamante-includes-flycast-dreamcast-nanosaur-wordle-tomb-rai.38191/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Latest_Vita_Homebrew_by_@Rinnegatamante_includes_Flycast_(Dreamcast)__Nanosaur__Wordle__Tomb_Rai..jpg">PS Vita Developer@Rinnegatamantehas shared several releases in the psx-place forum's over the past week(s), One of the highlights was released in recent days has been a major update toFlycast Vita-(A Sega Dreamcast emulator)for the PS Vita and PlaStation TV (PSTV) . Updating from the initial release ofv0.1 from Jan. 2021tonow v1.0.2with assistance from developer@Bythosfor the latest update.Earlier in the month of August we seen Rinnegatamante with two other ports released here in the forums with:Nanosaur Vita  (A Port of Nanosaur)&Wordle SDL(A clone of Wordle),which are both welcome additions to the Vita collection. Developer rinnegatamante has been busy with various other release's as well over the past few months.    In case you missed some of the other recent releases from@Rinnegatamantelike theTomb Raider 1 & 2 Classic Collectionsport to the Vita, you can also checkout his...​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-3-1T00:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>uKaruga demake (new) + VitaRTCW (Return to Castle Wolfenstien) v0.5 update by Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/uKaruga_demake_(new)_+_VitaRTCW_(Return_to_Castle_Wolfenstien)_v0.5_update_by_Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ukaruga-demake-new-vitartcw-return-to-castle-wolfenstien-v0-5-update-by-rinnegatamante.36656/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/uKaruga_demake_(new)_+_VitaRTCW_(Return_to_Castle_Wolfenstien)_v0.5_update_by_Rinnegatamante.jpg">Following up on the recent update ofvitaFF4 v1.2,  developer@Rinnegatamantehas also updated another existing project withv0.5 of VitaRTCW(Return to Castle Wolfenstein based on iortcw) which incorporates the latest vitaGL changes and graphical enchantments like fixing of fog rending  also a new Aim Assist Feature for single player has been added in this update. Then the vita developer also introduced a new homebrew release with a very interesting demake with the release ofnKaruga.A vertical shoot 'em up game that is a"demake popular bullet hell game Ikaruga, released in 2002 for Dreamcast and 2003 for Gamecube".​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-2-18T20:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>FF4-Vita v.1.2:   Final Fantasy IV (Android) port for PS-Vita by Rinnegatamante, frangarcj & TheFloW</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FF4-Vita_v.1.2___Final_Fantasy_IV_(Android)_port_for_PS-Vita_by_Rinnegatamante,_frangarcj_&_TheFloW.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ff4-vita-v-1-2-final-fantasy-iv-android-port-for-ps-vita-by-rinnegatamante-frangarcj-theflow.36556/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/FF4-Vita_v.1.2___Final_Fantasy_IV_(Android)_port_for_PS-Vita_by_Rinnegatamante,_frangarcj_&_TheFloW.jpg">PS Vita developer'sRinnegatamante,frangarcj&TheFloWhave updated their Wrapper/Port ofFinal Fantasy 4 (IV)(Android)for your PS Vita or PlayStation TV(& Vita TV}to version 1.2 with a few new changes and enchantments by updating to the latest vitaShaRK & vitaGL commits, Also included in v1.2 an added option to swapOandXbutton functionality and to round out the update the added possibility to "force english dub usage". was added in 1.2If you are fan of Final Fantasy and have a Homebrew enabled PS Vita (or PS TV), then you must checkout the other android ports ofFinal Fantasy III&Final Fantasy V (5)from this same trio of talented developer's. Also, checkout some of other projects by these developer's found at VitaDB.viewRinnegatamante,frangarcj&TheFloWpages for more excellent brew by these developer's who continue to share some great projects to us all. You will find great projects like a wrapper ports ofGrand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars&Grand Theft Auto: San Andreasand many other projects that are now powered by the community supported PS Vita Platform, lead by some great developer's that have brought some amazing projects to the platform.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-9T11:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3HEN 3.4.0 + HFW 4.92 - Officially released by esc0rtd3w of Team PS3Xploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_3.4.0_+_HFW_4.92_-_Officially_released_by_esc0rtd3w_of_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3hen-3-4-0-hfw-4-92-officially-released-by-esc0rtd3w-of-team-ps3xploit.46959/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3HEN_3.4.0_+_HFW_4.92_-_Officially_released_by_esc0rtd3w_of_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg">PS3 Developer@esc0rtd3whas released the latest update toPS3HENwith support to recent firmware updateof 4.92.  Along with the PS3HEN update is the release ofHybrid Firmware (HFW), which is just an official firmware (4.92) with the "silk_webkit.sprx" file replace from 4.82 OFW (that has a vulnerability patched in 4.83 OFW, the last attempt Sony made to curb homebrew). HFW was created by@Joonieand has been apart of this 4.92 release of well.There have been a number of new changes in this update marked v3.4.0 as it does not just provide 4.92 support but various changes as seen in the changelog provided​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2025-3-5T21:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 4.92 Official FIrmware has been released - PS3 CFW & PS3HEN DO NOT UPDATE to 4.92</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_4.92_Official_FIrmware_has_been_released_-_PS3_CFW_&_PS3HEN_DO_NOT_UPDATE_to_4.92.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-4-92-official-firmware-has-been-released-ps3-cfw-ps3hen-do-not-update-to-4-92.46837/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_4.92_Official_FIrmware_has_been_released_-_PS3_CFW_&_PS3HEN_DO_NOT_UPDATE_to_4.92.jpg">As expectedthe PlayStation 3 has receivedfirmware update 4.92, if you are currently usingPS3HENorCFWyouSHOULD NOT updateyour PS3 Firmware to 4.92 at this time. Otherwise you will be temporary losing your jailbreak's and ability to run homebrew on the console, until developer's release new exploits/jailbreaks that support the new 4.92 firmware update. There isa processin which need to take place for things to catch up, as developer's@bguerville@esc0rtd3w@Evilnatand other's havebeen readyfor the update to launch to get to work quickly.We learned last week that@bguervillehas an update for the PS3 Toolset with new features being deployed as the developer explains in these two post >1<​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-12-25T12:44:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Update 4.91.3  > > > [PS3 CFW] Evilnat's 4.91.2 Custom Firmware's Collection Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Update_4.91.3_____[PS3_CFW]_Evilnat's_4.91.2_Custom_Firmware's_Collection_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-4-91-3-ps3-cfw-evilnats-4-91-2-custom-firmwares-collection-released.45604/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Update_4.91.3_____[PS3_CFW]_Evilnat's_4.91.2_Custom_Firmware's_Collection_Released.jpg">UPDATEJanuary 2025:CFW Evilnat 4.91.3[BETA 1] released>>Click Here<<December '24:Merry Christmas and Happy Holiday's to everyone, PS3 Custom firmware developer@Evilnathas dropped by the psx-place forum's on this Christmas day to present the final build(4.91.2)of the developer's ps3 Custom Firmware suite, after a series of Open Beta releases, v4.91.2  now officially drops the "BETA" tag and in its final form for 4.91.2.  For discussion and full details about this PS3 firmware release and the various cfw types offered in this suite of releases, checkout the developer's release thread here in the forum's detailing all the various features and functions in Evilnat's latest releases notes and details for4.91 Evilnat's CFW (w/ Cobra v8.5).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-11-8T00:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>New PS1/PS2 Emulation Features for PS3 CFW user's + Evilnat's 4.91.2-BETA 12</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/New_PS1PS2_Emulation_Features_for_PS3_CFW_user's_+_Evilnat's_4.91.2-BETA_12.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/new-ps1-ps2-emulation-features-for-ps3-cfw-users-evilnats-4-91-2-beta-12.45233/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/New_PS1PS2_Emulation_Features_for_PS3_CFW_user's_+_Evilnat's_4.91.2-BETA_12.jpg">UPDATE: January 2025:ps2gxemu (for CECH-C/E ps3 models) has been updated by@kozarovv+ netemu to gxemu config conversion tool by@Zarhas been released, see details at bottomNov. 2024:  Recently we have had some great news with developments surroundingPS1 & PS2 Emulation on the PS3 for Custom Firmware user'sas the emulator's that reside in the PlayStation 3 Firmware have receivedsome modded tweaksthanks to@kozarovv&@mrjaredbeta, The files can be added manually to many firmware's or you can update to the latest release ofEvilnat's 4.91.2 CFW (BETA 12)that have these newly modded emulator's already installed and ready to go thanks to@Evilnat.The changes and feature's depend on the PS2/PS1 emulator being used and also on which model of the PS3 (with PS2). Below you will find a brief explanation of the emulator, mixed in with the readme details and some added screenshot. Some of the feature's need more testing to see how affective they may be such as the partial antiblur and EE Overclocking/Underclocking patches.  View all the details and related links found below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-7-16T21:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>CFW Flash Writer - Unofficial 4.91 update</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/CFW_Flash_Writer_-_Unofficial_4.91_update.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/cfw-flash-writer-unofficial-4-91-update.44229/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/CFW_Flash_Writer_-_Unofficial_4.91_update.jpg">Developer@aldostoolshas released an unofficial update for theCFW Flash Writerto supportHFW 4.91on the PS3. This can be a secondary candidate for allowing Custom Firmware installations whenbguerville's PS3Toolset (https://www.ps3toolset.com/bgtoolset/)isn't accessible or a self hosting offline option. However, ThePs3toolset is still the preferred  and safest method when available for hacking your capable ps3 model so its ready for PS3 Custom Firmware installations.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-4-30T22:05:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PPPwn - PlayStation 4 PPPoE RCE - (The First PS4 Kernel RCE - Supporting upto FW 11.00) by TheFlow</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PPPwn_-_PlayStation_4_PPPoE_RCE_-_(The_First_PS4_Kernel_RCE_-_Supporting_upto_FW_11.00)_by_TheFlow.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pppwn-playstation-4-pppoe-rce-the-first-ps4-kernel-rce-supporting-upto-fw-11-00-by-theflow.43655/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PPPwn_-_PlayStation_4_PPPoE_RCE_-_(The_First_PS4_Kernel_RCE_-_Supporting_upto_FW_11.00)_by_TheFlow.jpg">Scene Developer & HackerTheFlowwho has been a legend in various PlayStation Scene's, has done it yet again!! This time the developer has released "The first PlayStation 4 Kernel RCE, Supporting FWs upto 11.00".With the newly released (PoC) jailbreak the community will be able to update popular Homebrew Enabler's (Mira & GoldHEN) to support firmware 11.00 with this new jailbreak that TheFlow has disclosed (CVE-2006-4304) through the bounty program and has been patched in the latest PS4 firmware available​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-16T23:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Official PS3 Toolset Update (v1.2.007) Release (4.91 Support)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3_Toolset_Update_(v1.2.007)_Release_(4.91_Support).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-ps3-toolset-update-v1-2-007-release-4-91-support.43211/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3_Toolset_Update_(v1.2.007)_Release_(4.91_Support).jpg">FollowingSony firmware update of 4.91for the PS3, developer's across the scene have been updating various exploits and tools. We have seen developer@Evilnatrelease his4.91 PS3 Custom Firmware'searlier in the week. Then we recently just had@esc0rtd3w&@JoonieprovidePS3HEN (& HFW) updated with 4.91 Support. Now we have developer@bguervillewith an update to hisPS3 Toolsetto support the exploiting of 4.91 OFW for custom firmware installation for capable models.​</description>
			<creators>bguerville</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-16T07:42:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Official PS3HEN v3.3.0  + HFW Released for 4.91 Firmware from Team PS3Xploit</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3HEN_v3.3.0__+_HFW_Released_for_4.91_Firmware_from_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/official-ps3hen-v3-3-0-hfw-released-for-4-91-firmware-from-team-ps3xploit.43199/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Official_PS3HEN_v3.3.0__+_HFW_Released_for_4.91_Firmware_from_Team_PS3Xploit.jpg">TheOfficial PS3HENexploit has beenupdated to v3.3.0with some new changes from@esc0rtd3wand@JoonieofTeam PS3Xploitto support 4.91.  Also, developer Joonie has brought back the webkit exploit from 4.82 to 4.91 with the official HFW release(HFW = OFW with old webkit injected). Its best to use the official HFW when using the official PS3HEN release.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-3-9T19:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update Re-Release] PS3 Custom Firmware - 4.91 Evilnat Cobra (8.4) CFW Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_Re-Release]_PS3_Custom_Firmware_-_4.91_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.4)_CFW_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-re-release-ps3-custom-firmware-4-91-evilnat-cobra-8-4-cfw-released.43110/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_Re-Release]_PS3_Custom_Firmware_-_4.91_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.4)_CFW_Released.jpg">UPDATE -See 1st post for details, Re-Release a few bugs correctedPlayStation 3 CFW developer@Evilnathas just released his much anticipated4.91 Evilnat Custom Firmwarefollowingthe recent routine updatefrom Sony when they dropped firmware 4.91 last week.  If you are on any Custom Firmware currently all you have to do is install this CFW PuP by the USB method. You will not need to wait for an update to bguerville's PS3 Toolset to exploit your system (as its already exploited if you are running CFW).If you had updated to 4.91 OFW or by mistake installed a HFW you will have to wait for the PS3 Toolset to be updated. Developerbguervillewas waiting for the first 4.91 CFW to drop before making his update and that has just occurred with this release, so it should not be to long before we see bguerville provide a 4.91 update to the toolset as the developerdescribed herein the psx-place forums..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2024-2-27T05:25:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS3 4.91 Firmware Released - Do Not Update!!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_4.91_Firmware_Released_-_Do_Not_Update!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-4-91-firmware-released-do-not-update.42992/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS3_4.91_Firmware_Released_-_Do_Not_Update!!!.jpg">UPDATE:its now safe to update to 4.91. PS3HEN (& HFW), CFW & PS3 Toolset have been updated to support 4.91.PS3 Firmware 4.91 is now LiveThe expected once a year firmware update has been executed by Sony, PS3 4.91 Firmware is now Live. While an expected update, could this bring other changes to the firmware? Likely not but its still early to conclude as this update is fresh as of writing .Do not update, various exploits / tools / essential homebrew will need to be updated to support the latest firmware update of 4.91. See below for a short FAQ on 4.91, as there is always some confusions around the update process. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-6T17:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita Monthly Release Round Up - December 2020</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Release_Round_Up_-_December_2020.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-monthly-release-round-up-december-2020.32439/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Release_Round_Up_-_December_2020.jpg">We are officially almost one week into the year of 2021, and in this article we are going to look back and see what goodies the month of December brought your PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV. Whether you were naughty or nice, the Vita scene developers still supplied us all with another round of amazing projects and updates. Let us take a glimpse at some of the gifts we received last month.@Rinnegatamantewas Santa's number one helper, with a total of four updates this holiday season, including three homebrew games (SuperMarioWar,mertious, andDstroy) and an update to the super popular Nintendo 64 emulator,Daedalus X64. Another one of Santa's elves, the developer by the name ofisage(a.k.a.sarcasticat), also game us two updates to existing homebrew games (Open Fodder Vita, anddevilutionX) as well as one new one (REminiscence). There were many, many more homebrew games and homebrew applications released this month, so please take a look at the list below for all the details. It is also important to mentiondevnoname120updated hisVitabrightplugin, as well as added a new user application (Vitabright Lut Editior) to allow us to easily adjust the...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-5T21:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>re3 (A re-implementation of GTA III)  v1.2 Released:   New Improvements & Optimizations</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3_(A_re-implementation_of_GTA_III)__v1.2_Released___New_Improvements_&_Optimizations.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/re3-a-re-implementation-of-gta-iii-v1-2-released-new-improvements-optimizations.32430/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3_(A_re-implementation_of_GTA_III)__v1.2_Released___New_Improvements_&_Optimizations.jpg">We have been seeing some amazing projects on the PS Vita and its vibrant homebrew community, One of those projects was recently re3-vita from developer's@Rinnegatamante& @TheFlow who have provided us with a new update (v1.2) to the Open Source re-implementation of Grand Theft Auto III Engine,  Now you can easily play your PC (or Steam) version of the game on your PS Vita and the developer have been progressing the project as seen now with several updates.In version 1.2 some updates like using the latest commits of VitaGL & re3 (Engine) have been applied, also improvements to rainy scene's in the gameplay have been improved with increased framerate. This was done by backporting effects from GTAVC,  This update contains other changes like Triple Buffering, which you should notice when​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-13T14:21:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Daedalus x64 (Vita) v0.6:  N64 Emulator receives performance update & new translations</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Daedalus_x64_(Vita)_v0.6__N64_Emulator_receives_performance_update_&_new_translations.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/daedalus-x64-vita-v0-6-n64-emulator-receives-performance-update-new-translations.32097/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Daedalus_x64_(Vita)_v0.6__N64_Emulator_receives_performance_update_&_new_translations.jpg">Following the recent update ofDstroy Vita, Mentious, SuperMarioWar&re3 vita (GTA III)@Rinnegatamanteas promisedhas provided a new update for theNintendo 64 emulators for your jailbroken PS Vita or PlayStation TV (pstv). Following theprevious release, in version 0.6 ofDaedalus X64- Vita there has been more performance gains, this time around thanks to ARM DynaRec Backporting to the Vita build by developerTheFl0wwho also has had a hand in developing this port. With these performance gains@Rinnegatamantehas mentioned some games that were playing at a crawl in previous versions are now playing at full speed with these changes and implementations. It's currently unclear how many games this update helps, but be sure to report your success or failures(here).  See al the changes in the full changelog provided below​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-13T11:37:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Post Processing Effects & more added to Dstroy Vita, Meritous & SuperMarioWar by @Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Post_Processing_Effects_&_more_added_to_Dstroy_Vita,_Meritous_&_SuperMarioWar_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/post-processing-effects-more-added-to-dstroy-vita-meritous-supermariowar-by-rinnegatamante.32034/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Post_Processing_Effects_&_more_added_to_Dstroy_Vita,_Meritous_&_SuperMarioWar_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg">Following the recent release ofVitaQuakeII (v2.4)&VitaWolfen (v1.7)which providedPost Processing Effects & VSync Support,the developer (@Rinnegatamante)has now extended those advancements to other vita projects likeDstroy Vita,meritous&SuperMarioWar, along with other changes brought forward for these updated projects seen in the tabs provided below for each corresponding update.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-12-1T16:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita Monthly Round Up - November 2020</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Round_Up_-_November_2020.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-monthly-round-up-november-2020.31936/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Round_Up_-_November_2020.jpg">November is gone, and December is here; which means it's time for anothermonthly round upof all the PS Vita and PS TV releases we have seen in the month of November. We saw 28 releases this month, which averages out to about 1 a day. Some of these were brand new, and some were updates to previous releases.Looking at the applications we saw in November, it is safe to say it had been a great month for gamers. Starting the month off we hadNorthfear'sFHeros2receive an update, which broughtmajor performance enhancements to free Heros of Might and Magic II engine. Speaking of big boosts,fgsfdsgsreleased an update ofPrBoom Plusthatgreatly increased the software renderer performance, so you can enjoy all yourDoom wadseven more.GrahpenCtreleased an update toMARISA Highlow, which uses hislatest developer libraries. We saw many fixes and additions tousineur'sHODE, which isa rewrite of the Heart of Darkness engine.Rinnegatamanteblessed us with 3 updates this month,increasing performance and visuals to the following ports:​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-30T18:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>vitaQuakeII (v2.4) & vitaWolfen (v1.7) released by @Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/vitaQuakeII_(v2.4)_&_vitaWolfen_(v1.7)_released_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vitaquakeii-v2-4-vitawolfen-v1-7-released-by-rinnegatamante.31929/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/vitaQuakeII_(v2.4)_&_vitaWolfen_(v1.7)_released_by_@Rinnegatamante.jpg">Developer@Rinnegatamante, who has provided us with various homebrew projects like the recent releases ofDeadalusX64-Vita(n64 emulator)&re3-vita(A GTA III re-implementation)and has followed up therecent v1.1update with a round of updates to some other great projects likeVitaQuakeIIand alsoVitaWolfenhave both been updated with new support and features. Both homebrew projects are compatible for either your PS Vita or PlayStation TV deviceIn both project'sVitaQuakeII(v2.4)&VitaWolfen(v1.7)we have seen added support forPost Processing effects,  As well as updated support for the latestVitaGL commitsand also the latestVitaSDK.Plus each update provides a different bug fix unique for each project and additional changes as outlined in each projects respective changelogs found below, for more information and usage of these projects please visit the links attached at the bottom of this news listing.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-24T16:47:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: v1.1] re3-vita (Grand Theft Auto III for PS Vita / PS TV) by @Rinnegatamante / @theflow0</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v1.1]_re3-vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_for_PS_Vita__PS_TV)_by_@Rinnegatamante__@theflow0.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-1-re3-vita-grand-theft-auto-iii-for-ps-vita-ps-tv-by-rinnegatamante-theflow0.31589/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v1.1]_re3-vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_for_PS_Vita__PS_TV)_by_@Rinnegatamante__@theflow0.jpg">For those of us watching the Vita scene, we have probably noticed developer@Rinnegatamanterecently working on bringing a port ofGrand Theft Auto IIIto thePS VitaandPS TV. If you are like me, then you probably have beenwatching his Twitch streamsshowcasing the steady progress he was making, and also reading hislatest tweets on Twitterregarding development. At that point you might start thinking, when is this going to get released? Perhaps for Christmas, or maybe on Thanksgiving... possibly a Halloween treat! Well, the short and sweet answer is that it will not be released in the future... becauseRinnegatamante just stopped by PSX-Place a few moments ago to make his official release thread for re3-vita.If you own a copy of GTA3 for the PC, then you can now launch it on your PS Vita and PS TV. All you have to do is follow some rather simple instructions to get the necessary files transfer to you console/system, and you will be taken to a land of nostalgia as you play this revolutionary (for it's time) masterpiece of a game.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-2T13:25:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita Monthly Round Up - October 2020</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Round_Up_-_October_2020.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-monthly-round-up-october-2020.31663/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_Monthly_Round_Up_-_October_2020.jpg">It is the end of another month, and it is time to round up another batch of PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV releases. Previously, we have been providing our members and readers with mid-month round ups (see:August,September), but we figured why not just put together a list at the end of each month that collects all the great new additions and updates we have seen in the past 30 days. It is a great time to be a part of the Vita scene with it's thriving developer community that continually improves this soon to be 9-year old console.Before we dive right into the list, let's review some of the highlights we have seen in the month of October 2020. In the last week alone we saw@Rinnegatamanteand TheFloW releasere3, an open source Grand Theft Auto 3 now fully playable on the Vita and the PS TV, and we also saw the first implemenation of anOpenGL ES 2.0 graphic library for the Vitafrom Team CBPS. Developer@thehero_(theheroGAC) continued his effort to help every user get the latest and greatest applications and plugins with hisAutoPlugin 2and​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-11-1T21:57:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>OpenGL GLES 2.0 comes to the PS Vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OpenGL_GLES_2.0_comes_to_the_PS_Vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opengl-gles-2-0-comes-to-the-ps-vita.31655/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OpenGL_GLES_2.0_comes_to_the_PS_Vita.jpg">These past couple of months we have seen some major ports make their way to the Vita console. First we saw the reverse engineered source code forSuper Mario 64make it's way onto the Vita and PS TV, and then just last week we saw the same thing happen withGrand Theft Auto 3. With Grand Theft Auto Vice City reportedly being worked on, some of us might be asking what other kind of ports might we see in the future.Well, we have some great news in the development scene of the Vita.SonicMastrhas releasedPigs in a Blanket, the firstOpenGLGLES 2.0graphics library for the Vita scene. What that means for the end user is that developers will not only have an easier time bringing there project to the console, but that there will be more tools for them to use as well. A project like this can really open the doors to what is possible on the Vita and PS TV. I would not be surprised to see more and more ports start showing up on the console that are taking advantage of this release.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-28T20:07:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>HexFlow-Launcher v0.2.1:  Game/HB Launcher adds new Settings Menu / PSP Adrenaline bubble support /.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/HexFlow-Launcher_v0.2.1__GameHB_Launcher_adds_new_Settings_Menu__PSP_Adrenaline_bubble_support_..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/hexflow-launcher-v0-2-1-game-hb-launcher-adds-new-settings-menu-psp-adrenaline-bubble-support.31572/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/HexFlow-Launcher_v0.2.1__GameHB_Launcher_adds_new_Settings_Menu__PSP_Adrenaline_bubble_support_..jpg">DeveloperVitaHEXhas a new creation for the PS Vita / PlayStation TV community, following the recent PS Vita / PS4 Homebrew releaseConsolepedia(seen here onPS4andVita). Now the dev is back with the release of a new project titledHexFlow Launcher.With this app you will be to launch your games and also homebrew with a 3D CoverFlow interface that allows for Custom Covers to be used as well.  The eye candy looks great and comes with some good features out of the gate in this that has just been updated to v0.2.x following the initial release this past weekend.In v0.2 there has been added support for PSP (adrenaline) bubbles, A new settings menu, new viewing option that displays a bigger view, plus various other changes(v0.2.1 hot fix was just issues as well, so if you have already updated to 0.2 beware there was a quick hotfix)  in what appears to be another great projects for the Vita, which has been no stranger to some great homebrew.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-11T09:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: Version 1.13] Autoplugin 2 released by @TheheroGAC & ONElua Team!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_Version_1.13]_Autoplugin_2_released_by_@TheheroGAC_&_ONElua_Team!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-version-1-13-autoplugin-2-released-by-theherogac-onelua-team.28370/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_Version_1.13]_Autoplugin_2_released_by_@TheheroGAC_&_ONElua_Team!.jpg">Unlike the PlayStation 4 with it's slow Homebrew Content, thePlayStation Vitaalways saw a strong Content of Homebrew and other useful Plugins, which makes your life easier with a hacked PS Vita.In fact, we still see today new plugins released for this Handheld Console, no matter if you want toOverclock your PS Vitato make your favourite Games even better performing or if you just need some handy tools like analways running FTP Server, where you can transfer your favourite Games and other Homebrew Releases on-the-fly. But installing them wasn't always a easy task and there was even a risk when adding them manually, which could harm your complete System when pressing a wrong button. In short, it was always elaborate to install all those wonderful Plugins bit by bit. But luckily we hadAutopluginfor this in the past and today, well-known Developer@thehero_together with theONElua Teamare releasingVersion 2, where not only you can now seewhich Plugins you have already installed on your PS Vita, but also that you can nowdirectly download all translations inside of Autoplugin without any need to quit the Appas it was necessary before. Together with more new Features you can see down below and with a new Design,Autoplugin 2will make your life even more easier now for both you and your PS Vita!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-10-4T14:00:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE: v0.19.1] GE Patch - PSP Native Resolution on the PS Vita for Some Games</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v0.19.1]_GE_Patch_-_PSP_Native_Resolution_on_the_PS_Vita_for_Some_Games.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v0-19-1-ge-patch-psp-native-resolution-on-the-ps-vita-for-some-games.31106/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE_v0.19.1]_GE_Patch_-_PSP_Native_Resolution_on_the_PS_Vita_for_Some_Games.jpg">Last time we reported news aboutThefl0w(a.k.a. TheFloW, a.k.a. TheOfficialFloW, a.k.a. Flow The Bounty Hunter), he had disclosed hisPS4 Kernal Exploit for OFW 7.02. Today, we now are receiving news that he may be on the bounty chase again, this time going after PSP native resolution on the PS Vita and PS TV. Thecurrent bounty for bringing native resolution to PSP games on the PS Vita is at $1,535.00.GE Patch Pluginmay just be the start of that, which was released asversion 0.1just earlier today (andversion 0.11was just released hours ago)Currently, PSP games being ran on the Vita are actually being run through an ME (media engine) which is emulated by the Vita's CPU. As it stands, most games only run at half the resolution of actual PS Vita games, with the exception of a couple of GTA titles where full resolution has been achieved (from none other than TheFloW himself:see here). The end goal is for the PS Vita to to emulate the GE GPU and redirect the drawing to the Vita's GPU, allowing for full native resolution.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-28T17:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Get Your ADRENALINE Pumping with TheFloW - eCFW Updates</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Get_Your_ADRENALINE_Pumping_with_TheFloW_-_eCFW_Updates.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/get-your-adrenaline-pumping-with-theflow-ecfw-updates.31292/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Get_Your_ADRENALINE_Pumping_with_TheFloW_-_eCFW_Updates.jpg">There has been a lot of commotion going on in the Vita scene regardingplaying PSP games at native resolution on your PS Vita and PS TVs. We first saw the release ofTheFloW'sGePatch, which essentially isa plugin that would allow for some PSP games to utilize the Vita's hardware to run at a much better resolution. Since the initial release, we have already seen11 updatesin less than half a month; with each new releaseadding more support and bringing us closer to the dream of playing all of our PSP games at full native resolution.Along with the updates of GePatch,TheFloWalso released an updated version of the custom PSP firmwareAdrenalinefor end-user consumption,bringing even more compatibility to his incredible plugin. Following close behind this release,there has been a flood of updated Adrenaline related applications, plugins and tools,​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-16T17:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Vita Release Round-up for August & September</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Vita_Release_Round-up_for_August_&_September.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vita-release-round-up-for-august-september.31162/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Vita_Release_Round-up_for_August_&_September.jpg">Well, it has been a month since our lastPS Vita and PS TV Mid-Month Release Roundup, and the Vita Scene shows no signs to slowing down anytime soon (just take a look at our ever-growingPS Vita Resource Section). Another 30 days has brought us many, many more releases for end-users and developers alike. Just in these past several weeks we have seen many amazing releases for the Vita, including: the long awaited release of a plugin (GePatch) thatallows for some PSP games to run in full resolutionon the PS Vita, aport of Super Mario 64that is not to be confused with an emulator, and speaking of emulators we saw somemajor updates and improvements to the Nintendo64 emulator(Daedalus X64), and the list continues on and on.This month I decided to do a little something different, and I have created a couple of great looking lists for our members and readers. If you take a look below, you will see I have put together a collection ofAugustandSeptemberreleases inchronological order. Next to the name of each release, you will find abrief descriptionof what the release is or does. And if you click theNAMEof the release, you will be taken to a page that includes more information and downloads about that specific homebew. Also, be sure to flip...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-15T15:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>GrapheneCt's Recent PS Vita / PS TV Releases</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/GrapheneCt's_Recent_PS_Vita__PS_TV_Releases.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/graphenects-recent-ps-vita-ps-tv-releases.31138/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/GrapheneCt's_Recent_PS_Vita__PS_TV_Releases.jpg">After creating last month'sPS Vita and PS TV Mid-Month Release Roundup, I noticed another developer had been hard at work releasing several PS Vita and PS TV projects. I figured I should spotlight all the tremendous applications and pluginsGrapheneCthad been producing last month, both for end-users and developers.Let's take a look at his releases, starting with the beginning of August. TheHonRipper v1.0plugin was released August 1st, and itallows users to extract data from .MNH (Marlin-Hon format) booksthrough the PS Vita Sony Reader application; and on the same day,libShellAudiov1.1 was released for developers, which is aPS Vita library that can be used in system and music applications to play audio files using SceShell resources. On August 2nd, we saw two releases:MARISA Highlow PS Vita v2.1, aport of a homebrew highlow card game; andBGFTP v3.1, an application that allows forBackground FTP transferto and from your PS Vita and PS TV. Seven days later on August 9th, we saw two releases for developers:libvitaSASv1.01, aSceSas and libaudiodec library wrapperthat supports system mode applications; andlibvita2d_sysv1.22, a2D library for the PS Vitathat​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-9-6T11:33:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Daedalus X64 (N64 Emulator) v0.5:  Adds Network Loading of Roms / Shaders / Overlay / Playtime count</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Daedalus_X64_(N64_Emulator)_v0.5__Adds_Network_Loading_of_Roms__Shaders__Overlay__Playtime_count.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/daedalus-x64-n64-emulator-v0-5-adds-network-loading-of-roms-shaders-overlay-playtime-count.31044/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Daedalus_X64_(N64_Emulator)_v0.5__Adds_Network_Loading_of_Roms__Shaders__Overlay__Playtime_count.jpg">Following theprevious update(v0.4),developer@Rinnegatamantehas unleashed a massive update to theDaedalus x64 (Nintendo 64) emulatortoday for the PS Vita / PlayStation TV  With the project now maturing toversion 0.5with this latest update the dev has provided various fixes and new implementation of featuresas well (some seen already if you keep up with the nightly builds.).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-8-16T12:52:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita and PS TV Mid-Month Release Roundup</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_Mid-Month_Release_Roundup.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-and-ps-tv-mid-month-release-roundup.30809/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_Mid-Month_Release_Roundup.jpg">It has been a busy month for the Vita scene with several homebrew game releases, a couple of ports, a few of updates to some handy utilities, and even a new version of everyone's favorite GBA emulator. To start off, on the last day of July, we saw an update toJoel16'sVITAlbum, bringing the multi-format picture viewer up to version 1.10; and we also saw the much anticipated release ofVitaHEX Games'The Hallway v1.0, the P.T. clone that now features a puzzle that allows you to escape the house. In the first few days of August, endrift releasedmGBA v0.8.3, which brought many bugfixes and stability improvements to this Gameboy Advance emulator. That same weekNorthfearreleasedGemRB Port for PS Vita, which allows users to play several games designed for Bioware's Infinity Engine. The following daySKGlebareleasedYAMT v4.0. a great tool for SD2VITA users that now supports PSVSD and USB, plus allows you to format your SD/USB to TexFAT directly from your Vita.  Just in this last week alone, we saw four releases: a port ofBaldi's Basics Classicby hat,Crekeryopreleased v0.65 of his manga/comic reader...​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-6-28T17:33:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE-4] Daedalus X64 v.0.4 by @Rinnegatamante ---  N64 emulation is progressing on the PS Vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE-4]_Daedalus_X64_v.0.4_by_@Rinnegatamante_---__N64_emulation_is_progressing_on_the_PS_Vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-4-daedalus-x64-v-0-4-by-rinnegatamante-n64-emulation-is-progressing-on-the-ps-vita.29064/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE-4]_Daedalus_X64_v.0.4_by_@Rinnegatamante_---__N64_emulation_is_progressing_on_the_PS_Vita.jpg">UPDATE4- v0.4 Released -SeeCHANGELOGtab for latest changesDaedalusX64 (n64 emulator for the PS Vita / PSTV powered by VitaGL)has recently been updated to version 0.4 by port developer@Rinnegatamantethis update was a jam-packed update, that includes various improvements to the overall experience. The project has been incorporating news features to the emulator and also improving emuation performance as more games issue are being resolves. The emulator still has more work but with that said there is many games that are working very well and provide a great gameplay experience. The emulator contains an internal compatibility list that seeks online updates and plus there is a web-based page for this port's compatibility also.  Also,  developer@Rinnegatamantehas recently decided to move his release's thread here in the psx-place forums. So we would like to welcome another great developer in the scene to our community and hope to continue to see this progress of this port and other projects by the developer in the future, Now there are many changes in v0.4 and your just going to have to checkout the v0.4 changelog provided to get a grasp on al the work being done on this project.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-6-3T22:22:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update(3) - New Plans (flycast)] ReDream (DreamCast Emulator)  porting to VITA from Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update(3)_-_New_Plans_(flycast)]_ReDream_(DreamCast_Emulator)__porting_to_VITA_from_Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-3-new-plans-flycast-redream-dreamcast-emulator-porting-to-vita-from-rinnegatamante.29914/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update(3)_-_New_Plans_(flycast)]_ReDream_(DreamCast_Emulator)__porting_to_VITA_from_Rinnegatamante.jpg">Update (3) See latest progress of this port in development for the PS Vita and PlayStation TVUPDATE(1):Change in port plans, view new details listed bellow in marked updateDeveloperRinnegatamantewhomwe recently interviewedin thePower Supply Seriesand who has ported a Nintendo 64 emulator to the PS Vita / PS TV recently with the release ofDeadalus x64.Has another emulation project that many will be excited for as this shapes up, especially after seeing the great progress of d x64's n64 emulation so far to this point. NowReDream(A Sega Dreamcast Emulator) is being ported to the PS Vita as a libretro core running onRetroArch (Vita),so far its early progress, However, it looks like potential could be untapped from a developer who has some experience with the platform and emulation porting.. So far its rendering of graphics are in the early stages, so stay tuned for more progress reports from the developer..Until then tell us in the comments below what is your favorite Dreamcast Game or memories from SEGA last hardware adventure.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-1-20T08:29:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Universal Media Server v9.2.0 Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Universal_Media_Server_v9.2.0_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/universal-media-server-v9-2-0-released.27904/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Universal_Media_Server_v9.2.0_Released.jpg">Universal Media Serverhas now been updated and matured tov9.2.0by theUMS team, lead by developerSubunk.TheUPnP / DLNA&HTTP/S Media serverworks on yourPS Vita / PlayStation TV,  PlayStation 3 (PS3)andPlayStation 4 (PS4)and a tons of other devices you may own(see tab below for all devices supported)This is an extremely well built project that has been in development for years now and continues to evolve and grow with the dedication from the UMS development team. This utility will run on many operating systems and will connect to your supported devices to stream your personal collections of media (audio/video)  via your locally connected network. See many details included below and also at the UMS official website we have linked below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-1-12T10:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>vitaQuakeIII v0.9 Released - Data Files Downloader Added +  "Urban Terror" support added</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/vitaQuakeIII_v0.9_Released_-_Data_Files_Downloader_Added_+__Urban_Terror_support_added.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vitaquakeiii-v0-9-released-data-files-downloader-added-urban-terror-support-added.27789/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/vitaQuakeIII_v0.9_Released_-_Data_Files_Downloader_Added_+__Urban_Terror_support_added.jpg">Rinnegatamantehas released version 0.9 ofVitaQuakeIIIfor your homebrew enabled PS Vita for when your on the go or your PlayStation TV / Vita TV when your gaming away on the big screen. Either way this is an enjoyable homebrew port. In this version marked as 0.9 the developer has added anAutomatic Data FIle Downloaderwhen data files are not present. This makes the release much easier to install and setup and a nice edition to the vita homebre. There has been alot of attention to performance as well in this update the addition of dynamic libraries support for OpenArena core has provided a significant boost. Also, this update provides someexperimental supportforUrban Terror.This add-on is multiplayer,  but as the vita port developer explains in the release notes provided below there will be some issue as outlined due to this was a release designed for the PC and the Rinnegatamante had to do quite a bit of work to get it running on the Vita:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2020-1-11T02:24:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Volume Control Pack (by GrapheneCt):  Control system Audio in real-time</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Volume_Control_Pack_(by_GrapheneCt)__Control_system_Audio_in_real-time.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/volume-control-pack-by-graphenect-control-system-audio-in-real-time.27767/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Volume_Control_Pack_(by_GrapheneCt)__Control_system_Audio_in_real-time.jpg">One of the advantages of having an exploited system is the ability to create solutions and developerGrapheneCthas done just that with this latest release for the PS Vita or a PlayStation TV/Vita TV. If you find yourself with a hardware limitations/malfunction (like a broken volume button) or simply the ability to adjust the volume in real-time by an alternate means, thenVolume Control Packis something to keep a watch on as this project develops. In thisinitial releaseyou can install the vpk or you can also install plugin for some added functionality.According to famed Vita developer@Rinnegatamantethis release marks the first "system app" homebrew.. "system appwhich means you can run it while another app is running (eg: Open VitaShell and then open this homebrew and it won't ask you to kill VitaShell at app launch)"​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-8-26T14:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>h-encore² released by TheFloW - Surprise Release for System Firmwares 3.65 until 3.72!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/h-encore²_released_by_TheFloW_-_Surprise_Release_for_System_Firmwares_3.65_until_3.72!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/h-encore-released-by-theflow-surprise-release-for-system-firmwares-3-65-until-3-72.25860/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/h-encore²_released_by_TheFloW_-_Surprise_Release_for_System_Firmwares_3.65_until_3.72!.jpg">It is a little bit quiet in these summer days, don't you think?Most people were enjoying their holidays by all the sunshine. Luckilyfamous PlayStation Vita-DeveloperTheFloWwas busy these days and brings you a suprising Release with anupdated Version of h-encore- namelyh-encore². Yes, his last release already had asimilar namebut nevertheless, the main headline for this release is that with this updated Version, you are now againallowed to install you favourite Homebrew, Pluginsor you can even Downgrade your PlayStation Vita to a lower System Firmware(thanks to Developer@SKGleba, the latter is now supported with his self-madeplaintext loader)and all that from thenewest Original System Firmware (OFW)released by Sony (by the time of writing this article). This is huge news, especially for users, who were on a higher System Firmware, which was unsupported to do all those things and the coolest thing is, this Exploitworks as simple as the previous Version did.So without any further ado, here are each Steps needed to get this exploit running on your PlayStation Vita. Happy Cracking.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-5-5T15:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Trinity Exploit for PS Vita System Firmwares 3.69  & 3.70 released by TheFloW!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Trinity_Exploit_for_PS_Vita_System_Firmwares_3.69__&_3.70_released_by_TheFloW!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/trinity-exploit-for-ps-vita-system-firmwares-3-69-3-70-released-by-theflow.24030/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Trinity_Exploit_for_PS_Vita_System_Firmwares_3.69__&_3.70_released_by_TheFloW!.jpg">Following up after theAnnouncement from@TheFloWback at theEnd of Marchthis year, today@TheFloW"let the cat out of the bag" by releasing hisnewest Jailbreak for the PlayStation Vita, which will allow you tojailbreak both your PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV even on the newest System Firmwares 3.69 and 3.70(which weren't able to jailbreak before). But not only that. While you can jailbreak your Devices on the specific System Firmwares mentioned before, you can alsoDowngrade your PlayStation Vita / TV to a lower Firmware to get the full potential of your Devicelike with the famous Hacks and Exploits on System Firmware 3.60 (such asHENkakuandmodoru) and 3.65/3.67/3.68 (such ash-encore). So while you have been probably already prepared for this release back at the first announcement, together with the fact that@TheFloWwas so kind to release his final Jailbreak even earlier as previous announced, we won't keep you on tenterhooks anymore. Here is everything you need to know.​</description>
			<creators>kozarovv</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-3-30T10:15:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS Vita 3.69/3.70 Jailbreak announced by TheFloW - Get your PS Vita prepared!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_3.693.70_Jailbreak_announced_by_TheFloW_-_Get_your_PS_Vita_prepared!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps-vita-3-69-3-70-jailbreak-announced-by-theflow-get-your-ps-vita-prepared.23294/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS_Vita_3.693.70_Jailbreak_announced_by_TheFloW_-_Get_your_PS_Vita_prepared!.jpg">The PlayStation Vita came quite short with some News for this Month. But don't worry.Developer@TheFloWis still there and he has somevery good News for your PlayStation Vita today.Since both the newestSystem Firmwares 3.69 and 3.70are still not exploitable,Developer@TheFloWgives you in hisnewest GitHub Announcementan overview aboutwhat you can expectin the next few weeks with the main goal thatyou can prepare your PlayStation Vitawith everything which is necessary needed tojailbreakthose mentioned System Firmwares to enjoy your PlayStation Vita again with your favourite Homebrews while staying on the newest System Firmware. And the good thing is, it is actuallypretty easy for everyone to get prepared for the Release of his newest Jailbreak!The only thing which could get worse is when you miss his deadline, he gave the community to prepare your PlayStation Vitas.Luckily with the 3G Model, you can finish the preparation while being outside and enjoying the sun together with the start of the spring time, like I already did.​</description>
			<creators>kozarovv</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-23T18:58:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Hallway (a clone of Silent Hill PT demo) by VitaHEX Games</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Hallway_(a_clone_of_Silent_Hill_PT_demo)_by_VitaHEX_Games.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-hallway-a-clone-of-silent-hill-pt-demo-by-vitahex-games.22669/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Hallway_(a_clone_of_Silent_Hill_PT_demo)_by_VitaHEX_Games.jpg">Once again, VitaHEX Gamesis bringing another hit for the PS Vita & PlayStation TV homebrew community with the release ofThe Hallway, following the release of the smash hit ofZombiebound Reloaded,(A CoD Zombies style game) the developer is back with aSilent Hill P.T.(the infamous demo) inspired game called The Hallway. This game powered by Unity is a reincarnation of the famous PS4 demo that excited many only to see the original game canceled. Now VitaHEX brings his vision with high quality sounds that are great in a surround sound environment or as the developer suggest headphones for a truly horrifying experience[​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-23T13:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Adrenaline Version 6.8 updated by TheFloW - Now Supports h-encore 2.0</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Adrenaline_Version_6.8_updated_by_TheFloW_-_Now_Supports_h-encore_2.0.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/adrenaline-version-6-8-updated-by-theflow-now-supports-h-encore-2-0.22666/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Adrenaline_Version_6.8_updated_by_TheFloW_-_Now_Supports_h-encore_2.0.jpg">With the release ofh-encore2.0 byTheFloW, thePlayStation Vitashines more and more into astrong and powerful Gaming Devicebykeeping the capability of using Homebrews and other cool Stuffwhile staying nearby on the newest System Firmware released by Sony. Together with his Release fromModoru, which allows you toDowngrade your PlayStation Vita to a lower System Firmware, DeveloperTheFloWwon't stop here. Since his Homebrew Applications were already known before for older Exploits and Firmwares, it was just a Question of Time when hisAdrenalineApplication gets updatedto the newest "Family of Vita Homebrew" as well. In case you ask whatAdrenalineexactly is, it allows you tomodify the internal PSP Emulator on your Vitawhich will give youfull accessto it, including the famous XMB-Menu. But of course your question would be, why you need this Application? Well, the answer is simple here. While the Vita supports many "PSP Classics", the internal Emulator used by Sony isn't perfect, which can lead to Games, not compatible with your Vita. But withAdrenaline, you are able to fix those mentioned problems by giving a better support for your PSP Games and especially for older PS1 Game Titles.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-21T12:22:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[UPDATE] Autoplugin v3.79 by @TheheroGAC - Now supports h-encore 2.0 as well!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE]_Autoplugin_v3.79_by_@TheheroGAC_-_Now_supports_h-encore_2.0_as_well!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-autoplugin-v3-79-by-theherogac-now-supports-h-encore-2-0-as-well.22477/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[UPDATE]_Autoplugin_v3.79_by_@TheheroGAC_-_Now_supports_h-encore_2.0_as_well!.jpg">So you successfullyhackedyour PS Vita and/or your PS TV and you want to enjoy all the cool Homebrew Releases outside for this system. Maybe you asked:How?Don't worry, there is help for you. But in fact, while thePlayStation Vita has a very strong Homebrew supply, the Installation for each Application can be complicated sometimes. Many Homebrew Applications installson the flyso you can start immediately tinkering with it after the installation without any other work necessary to do. But sometimes, there arePluginswhere you need tochange various Configuration Files(like theux0:/tai/config.txtfor instance) to get them running, which means that a simple Installation won't be enough.Such Configurations and Modifications for those mentioned Plugins are necessarylike when you want toOverclock the CPU from your PS Vitaor when you want toInstall Games which requires a higher System Firmware than 3.60 or 3.65and modifying something wrong inside those Configuration Files manually can take some hazardous Damage for your PS Vita, which no one asks for that. But there is a simple Homebrew Solution available made by@thehero_which allows you not only toinstall such mentioned Pluginsautomatically, it alsomodifies those Configuration Filesby it's ownwhere nothing can get wrong inside your PS Vita and where you won't need torack your brainanymore. How convenient is that, isn't it?​</description>
			<creators>thehero_</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-19T14:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>h-encore 2.0 released by TheFloW - Supports 3.70 spoofing (for PSN Access)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/h-encore_2.0_released_by_TheFloW_-_Supports_3.70_spoofing_(for_PSN_Access).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/h-encore-2-0-released-by-theflow-supports-3-70-spoofing-for-psn-access.22611/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/h-encore_2.0_released_by_TheFloW_-_Supports_3.70_spoofing_(for_PSN_Access).jpg">Following up after the release ofModorulast week, which allows you toDowngrade your PlayStation Vita to a lower System Firmware to enjoy again great Hacks and Exploits written for System Firmware 3.60 or even below, today same DeveloperTheFloWreleased an updated Version ofh-encore, namely withVersion 2.0!While this update gives younew and additional Features like spoofing your PlayStation Vita to Sony's newest System Firmware 3.70, DeveloperTheFloWreminds you that if you aren't still in use ofh-encore, then now it is the right time,especially since you can Downgrade your PlayStation Vita now if h-encore isn't enough for youand you want even more "out from your Device". This is recommended for abetter Game Compatibility as well as for Homebrew, which needshigher Permissionsfrom your Device, such as the famousHENkaku Ensōfor instance. This update should also allow you touse the PlayStation Storemore easier again but keep in mind that connecting to the PlayStation Store with a "hacked" and "exploited" Device -especially when the core of the Device is still based on a lower System Firmware-can always be dangerous and brings huge risks to a banned Account and/or similar. So please use this with caution.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-17T12:09:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ZombieBound Released (v0.21) Released + Upcoming "The Hallway"  Game  by VitaHEX Games</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ZombieBound_Released_(v0.21)_Released_+_Upcoming_The_Hallway__Game__by_VitaHEX_Games.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/zombiebound-released-v0-21-released-upcoming-the-hallway-game-by-vitahex-games.22581/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ZombieBound_Released_(v0.21)_Released_+_Upcoming_The_Hallway__Game__by_VitaHEX_Games.jpg">VitaHEX Gamesis bringing theheatwith his recent release ofZombieBound Reloaded(a CoD Zombie inspired game) and then with the  much anticipated game (upcoming) release simply titled  "The Hallway", when you see the first screenshot of this game you will see that all the title needs as its remake of the Hallway from the infamous Silent Hill P.T. demo, Then as we all know that game was unfortunately abruptly canceled, but this inspired VitaHEX to bring his vision of the game he created some time ago to the PS Vita / PlayStation TV through the power ofUnity 3Dwhich has also been seeing its fair share ofPS4 Releases as wellof late.. Wink Wink @ VitaHEX have any plans/interest for some PS4 ports of your awesome games creations?Let's take a look at the recent update toZombieBound Reloaded(v0.21 currently) as the homebrew game has seen a lot of improvements in the latest updates. Since the initial release of "Reloaded," we can now buy/unlock new weapons and purchase new levels (w/ in-game currency (gold bars)) from the Store that has now been included.  4 new weapons appear, New Level "The Hospital" has been added, New Zombie Sounds, Improved Fog and Lighting  are just some of the new inclusions in v0.20 and 0.21 (which was quickly released to address a shotgun aiming bug,)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-15T20:37:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Modoru (1.0v) - PSVITA/PSTV - Downgrader (3.65-3.70) - By The_Flow</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Modoru_(1.0v)_-_PSVITAPSTV_-_Downgrader_(3.65-3.70)_-_By_The_Flow.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/modoru-1-0v-psvita-pstv-downgrader-3-65-3-70-by-the_flow.22525/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Modoru_(1.0v)_-_PSVITAPSTV_-_Downgrader_(3.65-3.70)_-_By_The_Flow.jpg">Great news for the PlayStation Vita scene, as today developerThe_Flow, just hit a huge milestone with the developer's newest release to the community,Modoru (1.0v)for the PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV (Vita TV) provides user's with the amazing ability to Downgrade your device with supported Firmwares up to 3.70. An incredible achievement that includes additional details below for executing this on your device.​</description>
			<creators>Naked_Snake1995</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-4T01:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch v1.7.6 - PS2 Port Now Available w/ 4 Cores + PS4 Progress Report + many platforms updated</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_v1.7.6_-_PS2_Port_Now_Available_w_4_Cores_+_PS4_Progress_Report_+_many_platforms_updated.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-v1-7-6-ps2-port-now-available-w-4-cores-ps4-progress-report-many-platforms-updated.22416/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_v1.7.6_-_PS2_Port_Now_Available_w_4_Cores_+_PS4_Progress_Report_+_many_platforms_updated.jpg">The official release ofRetroArch v1.7.6has been released and one of many highlights in this release is the official introduction of the PlayStation 2 Port of RetroArch from developerfjtrujy, After the developer launched the Nigthly builds this marks the first official release and offers 4 libretro cores to start out and those include2048(Puzzle Game) /QuickNES(Nintendo NES) /FCEUmm(Nintendo NES / Famicom / Disk System) /PicoDrive(Sega Genesis/Master Drive/32x), to keep up on the progress give the dev'stwittera follow and look tothis thread, where pkgs for running this on PS3 HAN and the PS4 through those console's internal PS2 emulators ..Pluswe have the latest progress report on theupcoming PS4 portas well.As of writing this the PS3 link was not up, but we have alerted Libretro and will update once we have a response(Update:PS3/PS Vita/PSTV/PS2/PSP builds all online). Checkout some of the highlights below and be sure to checkout the included source link at the bottom for FULL release notes and details surrounding v1.7.6​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-2T00:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Vita Homebrew Browser (VHBB) v0.83 - MOD:</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Vita_Homebrew_Browser_(VHBB)_v0.83_-_MOD.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vita-homebrew-browser-vhbb-v0-83-mod.22384/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Vita_Homebrew_Browser_(VHBB)_v0.83_-_MOD.jpg">The Homebrew Store for your exploited PS Vita / PlayStation TV known asVita Homebrew Browser(VHBB)has received an unofficial mod, which adds a new host(Vita Homebrew Wiki)to supply the DL's.. In the official releasesVitaDBwas the supplier but due to a disagreement with OneLua developers  VitaDB does not carry those OneLua powered Homebrew (which is quite alot of homebrew). So this mod to the homebrew browser adds their own Vita homebrew to the store on the popular Homebrew Store in this modded version of VHBB.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-2-1T23:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Zombiebound Reloaded Alpha (by VitaHEX Games)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Zombiebound_Reloaded_Alpha_(by_VitaHEX_Games).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/zombiebound-reloaded-alpha-by-vitahex-games.22379/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Zombiebound_Reloaded_Alpha_(by_VitaHEX_Games).jpg">VitaHEX Gameshas revisited one of his Homebrew Games for the PS Vita known asZombiebound(from 2017) with an update and complete overhaul of the game that is now powered by Unity. Now calledZombiebound Reloaded, the survival zombie experience is back in a big way with this recent update from the developer. This Alpha version comes with two levels and various (4) weapons available, future updates are planned but the dev might get sidetracked for good reason as the next project has already been teased and this one might really interesting.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2019-1-13T12:12:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>ref00d (plugin) Released -  Run Games / Apps that require a higher FW from your own</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ref00d_(plugin)_Released_-__Run_Games__Apps_that_require_a_higher_FW_from_your_own.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ref00d-plugin-released-run-games-apps-that-require-a-higher-fw-from-your-own.22136/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/ref00d_(plugin)_Released_-__Run_Games__Apps_that_require_a_higher_FW_from_your_own.jpg">Following the big news fromTeam Moleculeseveral weeks ago andeffectively opening the system wide open, it was only a matter of time before we would start to see other developer's start putting the finding to use and we have seen theFAPS Team (team members listed below)have recently released a new(taiHEN)plugin calledref00d, this plugin is a big deal, as it will allows users/devs to use content that would otherwise require a higher firmware to be played/executed on a lower firmware for your exploited PS Vita or PlayStation TV.  Typically not an easy task to reach but thanks to Team Molecule's research and the FAPS Team we now have a ready to use simple plugin solution to remove those firmware restrictions, see additional details about this plugin release in the release notes provided below by the development team.​</description>
			<creators>Zwei</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-5-10T18:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.89 PS3 Firmware is now live. - Does it affect a Jailbroken / Homebrew Enabled  PS3?</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.89_PS3_Firmware_is_now_live._-_Does_it_affect_a_Jailbroken__Homebrew_Enabled__PS3.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-89-ps3-firmware-is-now-live-does-it-affect-a-jailbroken-homebrew-enabled-ps3.37206/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.89_PS3_Firmware_is_now_live._-_Does_it_affect_a_Jailbroken__Homebrew_Enabled__PS3.jpg">Latest Status Update (May 20)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-2-13T12:38:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>pPlay v3.8: A homebrew Video Player now with PS4 Support by Cpasjuste</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/pPlay_v3.8_A_homebrew_Video_Player_now_with_PS4_Support_by_Cpasjuste.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pplay-v3-8-a-homebrew-video-player-now-with-ps4-support-by-cpasjuste.36505/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/pPlay_v3.8_A_homebrew_Video_Player_now_with_PS4_Support_by_Cpasjuste.jpg">Homebrew enabled PlayStation 4's (PS4) have seen a new homebrew release from a developer who has been killing it with some great releases of late(some of those includedpNESpSNES&pFBNEOto name a few of the recent PS4 releases). Now PS4 devCpasjustehas ported another project from the Switch with the release ofpPlay (a new video player for the PS4). Starting in v3.6 (now resides at v3.8 time of this writing) the developer provided PS4 support for the project (source codehere) and since then provided several quick updates (in v3.7 &  v3.8) to improve the PS4 port of this handy application for your PS4 Console.The PlayStation 4 has another Video Player for the PS4 calledPS4 Playerfrom developer Lapy, which is a useful app but an application that has only seen maintenance updates for sometime and has limited codec support . This video player (pPlay) aims to provided a needed solution for the PS4.  The PS3 had a great media player inMovainand hopefully pPlay can emerge and become a must have option for your homebrew enabled PS4 as well..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-2-8T22:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch (Community Edition) Beta 4  - Unofficial PS3 Port by Crystal</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(Community_Edition)_Beta_4__-_Unofficial_PS3_Port_by_Crystal.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-community-edition-beta-4-unofficial-ps3-port-by-crystal.36469/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(Community_Edition)_Beta_4__-_Unofficial_PS3_Port_by_Crystal.jpg">RetroArch(CommunityEdition)has reachedBeta 4with a recent update provided by PlayStation 3 Homebrew developer@Crystal,.  RetroArch (CE)  "is a community effort to restore a functional build for the homebrew PS3 Community,". The official port for the PS3 from the libretro team been temporary shelved during a code transition. So, that is whereRetroArch  (CE)has been filling the gap in providing a port that has fixed some longstanding issues on the PS3 with a greater focus on the console itself. The result becomes one of the most stable RetroArch builds on the PS3 with more libretro core's (emulators) then ever to add to the RetroArch (frontend) for your Homebrew enabled PS3 powered by either your favoriteCFWorPS3HEN.,There is alot more information on this unofficial port along with various links and details for instructions to setup many of the libretro cores being used. Checkout the officialthread herein the PSX-Place forumsand join the discussion for this unofficial PS3 Port.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-31T19:54:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 EMC (SouthBridge) CFW for PHAT Models CUH-1000 / CUH-1100 (Tutorial by zecoxao)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_EMC_(SouthBridge)_CFW_for_PHAT_Models_CUH-1000__CUH-1100_(Tutorial_by_zecoxao).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-emc-southbridge-cfw-for-phat-models-cuh-1000-cuh-1100-tutorial-by-zecoxao.36389/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_EMC_(SouthBridge)_CFW_for_PHAT_Models_CUH-1000__CUH-1100_(Tutorial_by_zecoxao).jpg">Update (Additional Tutorial):Software method for 5.05 only(5.05 hackable CUH-1000 and CUH-1100 ONLY!):We had some interesting developments on thePlayStation 5's 4.03 firmware just recently, Now developer@zecoxaohas dropped news for the PS4 in the psx-place forums today with a new tutorial that i must say interesting for the PlayStation 4 (PS4) community, asPS4 PHAT Models (CUH-1000 / 1100)now has theability for a CFW (in the southbridge emc that acts like a second syscon).  Now, this is an advanced task and you can do some damage to your PS4 if you do not follow the instructions and even so there is always a risk when your messing with internal flash (EMC in this case) ,So this is aUSE AT YOUR OWN RISKrelease.You have been warned of the potentials.This works on firmware upto 9.03, also works on devkits / early testkits  From@zecoxao"This only grants permanence over the southbridge and syscon, but does not grant permanence over samu it's just over southbridge and syscon you can think of it as a second syscon" So in laymen terms this is not like your traditional PSP/PS3 CFW, but rather a firmware for the EMC chip not the actual PS4's firmware (don't confuse the two).,The CFW (EMC) will allow for various things like " making the console beep, change temperature limits, increase or decrease fan speed etc"​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T19:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Icon Mask ( update  v1.05)  Change the appearance of your PS4 icons</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Icon_Mask_(_update__v1.05)__Change_the_appearance_of_your_PS4_icons.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/icon-mask-update-v1-05-change-the-appearance-of-your-ps4-icons.36373/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Icon_Mask_(_update__v1.05)__Change_the_appearance_of_your_PS4_icons.jpg">Update v1.05 ReleasedOriginal article: DeveloperLapyhas a new utility ps4 homebrew he has released recently along with two quick updates to provide additional functionality with the release ofIcon Mask. Many of you know Lapy from his various homebrew creations on the Ps4 / PS Vita. We have seen from Lapy Games titles likeDuck Hunt remake/Wild Gunman RemakeBrain Splitter& various others you can see in theLapy Games Collection.  the developer has released various utility applications likePS4-Xplorer/PS4 Tempature&PS4 App LockNow withIcon Maskthe developer has gave user's an easy way to customizes Icons on the PS4's main menu, giving a custom look to the UI with a variety of "mask" that can be used with more planned to be added in the future.. Below are some of the details of Icon Mask (which currently sits at v1.02 and supports 9.00 FW)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T16:20:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>pFBNEO (FBA) / pSNES (SNES9x) / pNES (Nestopia) Released for PS4 (9.00 FW) ports by Cpasjuste</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/pFBNEO_(FBA)__pSNES_(SNES9x)__pNES_(Nestopia)_Released_for_PS4_(9.00_FW)_ports_by_Cpasjuste.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pfbneo-fba-psnes-snes9x-pnes-nestopia-released-for-ps4-9-00-fw-ports-by-cpasjuste.36372/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/pFBNEO_(FBA)__pSNES_(SNES9x)__pNES_(Nestopia)_Released_for_PS4_(9.00_FW)_ports_by_Cpasjuste.jpg">You may know developerCpasjustework from the PS Vita with releases likepFBA/pSNES / pNES, well the developer recently released 3 emulator ports for the PS4.pFBNEO(a Final Burn Alpha emulator)/pSNES(SNES9X (Super Nintendo) Emulator/pNES(Nestopia (Nintendo NES) emulator).These emulators are compatible with the 9.00 jailbreak. View each below for the corresponding emulator details​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T13:37:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>A small writeup + code for  ROP userland execution for PS5 firmware 4.03</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/A_small_writeup_+_code_for__ROP_userland_execution_for_PS5_firmware_4.03.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/a-small-writeup-code-for-rop-userland-execution-for-ps5-firmware-4-03.36369/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/A_small_writeup_+_code_for__ROP_userland_execution_for_PS5_firmware_4.03.jpg">Following the recent9.00 PS4 Jailbreak. developer's:Znullptr&ChendoChapnow recently have released a small write-up and some code examples forROPuserlandexecutionon PS5firmware 4.03. Now this isnota jailbreak. what we have is a userland exploit via webkit, an entry point essentially.  A way to attack / control the kernel will be the next obstacle and typically the more difficult task to achieve but this provides a  sorta foot into the door for future exploration and what hopes to be a future kernel exploit to combine with this entry point.However it may prove to also be a great window to learn more about the PS5 for developer's and hacker's as it still new and they are still trying to figure out how Sony has tried to keep other's out. The developer's have stated the PS5 security is vastly improved over the PS4.  It will be a process and take sometime but looks like there is a crack open in 4.03 for more exploration. Will it lead to the front-door being busted wide open in the future and a full fledged jailbreak? Only time will tell in the meantime checkout the interesting write up below and what the experts have to say on this write-up... ​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T10:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update 3- v1.0.0 Released] Apollo Save Tool (new PS4 version) Released by bucanero</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_3-_v1.0.0_Released]_Apollo_Save_Tool_(new_PS4_version)_Released_by_bucanero.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-3-v1-0-0-released-apollo-save-tool-new-ps4-version-released-by-bucanero.36085/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_3-_v1.0.0_Released]_Apollo_Save_Tool_(new_PS4_version)_Released_by_bucanero.jpg">Update 3 (Jan. 30 2022)-v1.00 ReleasedFrequent PS3/PS4 developer seen in the psx-place forums@bucanerohas now officially released a new homebrew for the PS4(graduating from somerecent Beta testbuilds), Bringing a  PS4 version of his popular PS3 homebrew utility for handling and managing saves games now for the PS4 Jailbroken user's(9.00 Support currently not supported, but will bein next update),  TheApollo Save Toolis a homebrew app that runs on a homebrew enabled PS4 console and as PS3 CFW / HEN user;s will tell you its been a very useful utility for Save Games Management over the past couple of years with lots of handy features and frequent updates that have brought alot of new functionality and features.  .Recently, the developer decided to try and bring this concept and homebrew tp the PS4 and the developer has managed to do just that with this recent release for the PS4. The development journey can be seen in hisdevelopment threadthat tracked progress of the PS4 version from the developerfound herein the forum's( also, here is the development thread forthe PS3 versionand also therelease threadhere for the PS3 app for those interested with a PS3.).View all the details of the latest PS4 release from developer@bucanerofound below​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-30T07:04:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Homebrew Revival PS3.1] Featuring "UFO Racer" by ThatOtherDev</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Homebrew_Revival_PS3.1]_Featuring_UFO_Racer_by_ThatOtherDev.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/homebrew-revival-ps3-1-featuring-ufo-racer-by-thatotherdev.36357/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Homebrew_Revival_PS3.1]_Featuring_UFO_Racer_by_ThatOtherDev.jpg">Homebrew Revialis a new feature at psx-place.com where we explore some great projects of the past to educate new user's on some homebrew they may not of known about and also to perhaps sparks some new development in various projects we spotlight in this series, checkout another exclusive psx-place series withThe Power Supplythat has interviewed various developer's who have powered the community (will continue with a new season of interviews soon).First up, we have a great homebrew game that was developed for the Wii and the PS3 by developerThatOtherDev(aka ThatOtherPerson)calledUFO Racer, it's a game with a great foundation and has alot of potential to be a really great homebrew title, but the original developer has not made an update since 2012, However the source code is available, using an early version of PSL1GHT.. Can this be a project that see's a rival in 2022, 10 years after it was released? Checkout some of the source code and the tutorials this developer wrote for the PS3. Also, take note during the source code release of UFO Racer and many other games created by ThatOtherDev. The developer states the following about using the source code: "Make something. There is an appalling, lack of original games being made in the homebrew community and I implore you to take part in changing this." see full statement in tab below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-2T11:15:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.2]  SATURN-FPKG - Convert Saturn Games into PS4 fPKGs!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.2]__SATURN-FPKG_-_Convert_Saturn_Games_into_PS4_fPKGs!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-2-saturn-fpkg-convert-saturn-games-into-ps4-fpkgs.36031/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.2]__SATURN-FPKG_-_Convert_Saturn_Games_into_PS4_fPKGs!.jpg">Following the recentPS4 9.00 Jailbreak, Ps4 developer@Jabuhas a new tool for 9.00 FW , you may remember this developer's previous release's for the PS4 with theps2-fpkgandpsx-fpkgtools that allowed for Ps2 / Ps1 games into a fpkg's  to install on a homebrew enabled PS4.  Following that same concept of injecting custom roms into an fpkg the developer now has a new tool that convertsSega Saturngames into PS4 fpkgs.  With the release of  "Cotton Guardian Force Saturn Tribute"(a Sega Saturn Game)for the PS4, it has equipped a useful Sega Saturn emulator that is said to be based off theSSF emulator.  (According to ZiL0G80) and performing well. Upon seeing this game release is when developer@Jabuinterest peaked and then decided to develop and release the following tool to make running your Sega Saturn games easily on your homebrew equipped PS4 (9.00 FW).....​</description>
			<creators>Jabu</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2022-1-1T13:12:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>TeamFAPS Release CEX2DEX for Vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TeamFAPS_Release_CEX2DEX_for_Vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/teamfaps-release-cex2dex-for-vita.36069/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/TeamFAPS_Release_CEX2DEX_for_Vita.jpg">CEX2DEX for the PS VitaBy Team Fapps**PSTV & VitaTV planned for future date**​</description>
			<creators>atreyu187</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-12-12T23:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Firmware 9.00 Jailbreak Update (Released)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Firmware_9.00_Jailbreak_Update_(Released).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-firmware-9-00-jailbreak-update-released.35900/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Firmware_9.00_Jailbreak_Update_(Released).jpg">"In this project you will find an implementation that tries to make use of a filesystem bug for the Playstation 4 on firmware 9.00. The bug was found while diffing the 9.00 and 9.03 kernels. It will require a drive with a modified exfat filesystem. Successfully triggering it will allow you to run arbitrary code as kernel, to allow jailbreaking and kernel-level modifications to the system. will launch the usual payload launcher (on port 9020).- via project's official readme"PS4 Firmware 9.00Jailbreak Released(awesome work bychendochap&@Znullptr)​</description>
			<creators>Death_Dealer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-25T19:06:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>4.88.2 Evilnat Cobra (8.3) Custom FirmWare (CFW-CEX) Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.88.2_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.3)_Custom_FirmWare_(CFW-CEX)_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/4-88-2-evilnat-cobra-8-3-custom-firmware-cfw-cex-released.32057/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/4.88.2_Evilnat_Cobra_(8.3)_Custom_FirmWare_(CFW-CEX)_Released.jpg">UPDATE 4.88.2:PS3 Developer@Evilnathas updated and released4.88.2Evilnat (Cobra 8.3) CFW ,there is a number of new options like an added File manager, Option to toggle Cobra version, and various other new options detailed in the changlog provided below. Also the developer has provided a number of  fixes and improvements, View all the details of 4.88.2 release of this latest CFW by@Evilnat​</description>
			<creators>Evilnat</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-22T22:52:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>RetroArch (PS2) Progress : New Cores incoming,  gpSP  (GameBoy Advance @ Full-Speed)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(PS2)_Progress__New_Cores_incoming,__gpSP__(GameBoy_Advance_@_Full-Speed).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/retroarch-ps2-progress-new-cores-incoming-gpsp-gameboy-advance-full-speed.34680/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/RetroArch_(PS2)_Progress__New_Cores_incoming,__gpSP__(GameBoy_Advance_@_Full-Speed).jpg">Emulation on a Homebrew Enabled PS2 Console has some great progress in the past year plus,  thanks to still very much active PS2 development scene.  Developer's like@fjtrujyhasported RetroArchto the PS2 about and since then has been adding more and more support for additional emulation with additional libretro core's., Recently the developer previewed some big things that  have been in the pipeline for the  PlayStation 2 port of RetroArch (a multi-system emulator).The PS2 now has a new full speedGBA (GameBoy Advance) emulatorcoming soon with thegpsplibretro corenow running very well @ full speed with the work of@fjtrujyand@davidgfnetcollaborating to bring dynarec to provide a full speed gba emu on the PS2 Console.  Also, the Lutro Core (Lua) improvements are right around the corner as well with some progress being made (seen here) to the core . See some of the progress that has been made on the PS2 port of RetroArch so far in 2021 below.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-22T22:28:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>jfduke3d-vita + jfsw-vita + vitaRTCW released + Doom3 Port in the works</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/jfduke3d-vita_+_jfsw-vita_+_vitaRTCW_released_+_Doom3_Port_in_the_works.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/jfduke3d-vita-jfsw-vita-vitartcw-released-doom3-port-in-the-works.34648/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/jfduke3d-vita_+_jfsw-vita_+_vitaRTCW_released_+_Doom3_Port_in_the_works.jpg">Following theKYUHEN Homebrew Contest, the PS Vita platform has been getting some new homebrew updates and ports from a familiar developer to all in the PS Vita community. Developer@Rinnegatamanterecently provided updates toVitaQuakeIII (v1.0),re3-gta (v1.4)andVitaVoyager (v0.8)Following those updates another project seen an update with the release ofVitaRTCW (v0.4)here in the psx-place forum's,.Now comes the introduction of a few new projects, some have been released already here in the psx-place.com forums,1st up we havefsw-vita - Port of Shadow Warrior Classicand then today we seen the release ofjfduke3d-vita iport of jfduke3d (JonoF's Duke 3D).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-13T22:34:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>KYUHEN  PS Vita / PSTV  Homebrew Contest Winner's have been announced!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__PS_Vita__PSTV__Homebrew_Contest_Winner's_have_been_announced!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/kyuhen-ps-vita-pstv-homebrew-contest-winners-have-been-announced.34499/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__PS_Vita__PSTV__Homebrew_Contest_Winner's_have_been_announced!!.jpg">After a couple months of development of various homebrew projects for the PS Vita and PlayStation TV, theKYUHEN Contestfor the PS Vita has came to a close recently and now the Winners have been Announced (top 3 from each category). The Full Rankings (& Doiwnloads) can be found on the "Result" Page on the Contest's Official Website.  The Contest yielded36 entries(about the same as GekiHEN Contest (39))that spawned across the following 4 categories:Game 1 , Game 2, Utility, Port. No doubt has been some impressive showing and some great projects that are now available on your Homebrew Enabled PS Vita or PlayStation TV(vita tv).​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-12T00:26:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>re3-Vita (Grand Theft Auto III port) updated to v1.4</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3-Vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_port)_updated_to_v1.4.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/re3-vita-grand-theft-auto-iii-port-updated-to-v1-4.34564/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/re3-Vita_(Grand_Theft_Auto_III_port)_updated_to_v1.4.jpg">Recently the re3-vita (GTA III Port)is back with a new update with the release of version 1.4, this update provided by developer@Rinnegatamante, who has recently updatedVitaQuakeIII (v1.0)&VitaVoyager (v0.8)Has now updated this amazing vita port of re3 with various fixes for all "game-breaking issues affecting previous release's" and v1.4 also includes some features like the inclusion of a Game Manual.  To round out the update we have support for video playback now in v1.4 and instructions in how to get your Video's converted to work on the PS Vita / PSTV, Checkout all the details below:​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-7-6T19:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>VitaQuakeIII  v1.0   +  VitaVoyager v0.8:  New updates to vitaGL provides new performance boost !</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaQuakeIII__v1.0___+__VitaVoyager_v0.8__New_updates_to_vitaGL_provides_new_performance_boost_!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/vitaquakeiii-v1-0-vitavoyager-v0-8-new-updates-to-vitagl-provides-new-performance-boost.34500/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/VitaQuakeIII__v1.0___+__VitaVoyager_v0.8__New_updates_to_vitaGL_provides_new_performance_boost_!.jpg">Developer@Rinnegatamantedropped by the forums here at psx-place.com to release a couple of new items for the homebrew community.  First up we have an update toVitaQuakeIIIwith the release of version 1.0. This update has provided the port withMultitexturing supportandTexture CombinerWhat this does, is improves performance on the PS Vita and provides support for features like dynamic light that previously has been disabled prior to this update (see video below for a showcase of examples).  In regards to the recentadvancements to VitaGLthe developer states "Expect a branch of releases for idTech3 derivates plus maybe some new idTech 3 derivates ports in the future" be sure to keep a look out in the future here in thepsx-place forumsand @VitaDBfor when those release appear directly fromRinnegatamante.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-28T20:39:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>KYUHEN  - A New Vita Homebrew Contest (Now Live - Submissions ends on May 27, 2021)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__-_A_New_Vita_Homebrew_Contest_(Now_Live_-_Submissions_ends_on_May_27,_2021).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/kyuhen-a-new-vita-homebrew-contest-now-live-submissions-ends-on-may-27-2021.33403/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/KYUHEN__-_A_New_Vita_Homebrew_Contest_(Now_Live_-_Submissions_ends_on_May_27,_2021).jpg">There is a newVita Homebrew Contestthat is starting in the Vita Community, in the past we have seen theRejuvenate Contestthat helped spark some early development in the Vita Scene, then later on we had theGekiHEN Contestwhich psx-place took a part in along with other scene sites, now we have the a new contest for the Vita Community calledKYUHEN,Spearheaded byCimmerian , 2old4Gaming , frangarcjwith assistance from psx-place.com / wololo.net / playstationhax.xyz / Customprotocol.com .The Contest will consist of a2 month development periodand spanacross 4 categories.  Those categories include 2 separate"Games"categories one for SDK Homebrew and one for Project powered by ported engine's such as Unity or GameMaker. Then there will be a separate category for"Ports"of  games/emulators ect..  Then to round out the last category there is"Utilities"and this one is open to both applications and plugins .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-17T20:02:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update] Apollo Save Tool v1.8.4 released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.8.4_released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-apollo-save-tool-v1-8-4-released.28124/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update]_Apollo_Save_Tool_v1.8.4_released.jpg">Update v1.8.4 ReleasedOriginal Introduction:PS3 development has been seeing an upkick lately and developer@bucanerohas been one of the developers playing a part. The developer has recently updatedArtemis with new supportand also releasedPKGi (PS3)but now the developer shares a great utility that involves PS3 Game Saves calledApollo, built utilizing the Artemis GUI this homebrew capable of running on CFW and PS3HEN will allow you to Patch & Resign your Game Saves / Download Game Saves / Unlock Game Saves all from the convenience of your PS3 console and not PC tools are required.  Below you can see the release thread from the developer himself: So i'll let@bucanerotake it from here with another great release:​</description>
			<creators>bucanero</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-17T18:59:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>(Update 1.1) Grand Theft Auto:  Chinatown Wars  (GTA CTW)  Vita Port by @theflow0 /  @Rinnegatamante</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(Update_1.1)_Grand_Theft_Auto__Chinatown_Wars__(GTA_CTW)__Vita_Port_by_@theflow0___@Rinnegatamante.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-1-1-grand-theft-auto-chinatown-wars-gta-ctw-vita-port-by-theflow0-rinnegatamante.33283/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/(Update_1.1)_Grand_Theft_Auto__Chinatown_Wars__(GTA_CTW)__Vita_Port_by_@theflow0___@Rinnegatamante.jpg">Update v1.1 ReleasedOriginal Article (March 17):The duo of PS Vita legends developer'sTheFlowand@Rinnegatamanteteam up again with another great release for the PS Vita Community. We have seen the family ofGrand Theft Auto Seriesmake the journey to the PS Vita with various ports and techniques but have we been missing one from the PSP era in the form of a native port? First we seen the release ofre3 (GTA III)followed byreVC (GTA: Vice City)which utilized a reversed engineered engine .. Then several weeks ago we seen those two classic GTA game's followed by what may be the most iconic game in the series withgtaSA_Vita (GTA: San Andreas)as we just witnessed updatev1.6released  Whichtook a different approach and utilized the Android port of the game and puts TheFlow's kubridge plugin to work serving as a wrapper for aiding in the porting some Android games to the PS Vita (seeMax Payneas another Android game ported)Now, that brings us to today's release with is a port of another GTA Classic from the PSP with the release ofGrand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars, (GTA:CFW Vita) a 3D top view game from the series , LikeMax PayneandGTASAthis is a port of the Android version with magic from@Rinnegatamanteand TheFlow.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-14T18:35:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>{UPDATE] PS4 Jailbreak 7.50 /7.55 w/ Mira Support Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{UPDATE]_PS4_Jailbreak_7.50_7.55_w_Mira_Support_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-ps4-jailbreak-7-50-7-55-w-mira-support-released.33239/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/{UPDATE]_PS4_Jailbreak_7.50_7.55_w_Mira_Support_Released.jpg">UPDATE7.55 w/ Mira Support ReleasedOriginal Article (7.50) Not only did we just see aPS1 exploit released, the exploited PS4 firmware latter has extended a step to now firmware 7.50 has been officially exploited and released to the public as developerSleirsgoevyhas released the latest PS4 Jailbreak that has utilized the latest findings fromTheFlowin his disclosed bug that has the potential to work upto 7.55 but is currently targeted for 7.50 for this release.TheFlowhas tweeted several hints regarding 7.55 (tweet1/2) but 7.55 is yet to be solved by other,@zecoxaoprovided some details and shared via twitter see below.This is not a fully functional jailbreak yet as there is elements that are needed to be ported like the Mira/HEN and other Payload, so you should not update to this exploit from previous exploits yet. Let it mature, but if your on a PS4 on 7.50 or lower and missed out on previous exploits, Stay Tuned as this progresses,​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T21:51:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[PS3 XMB MOD] Now have Individual Gameboots for each emulator / system / homebrew launched</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[PS3_XMB_MOD]_Now_have_Individual_Gameboots_for_each_emulator__system__homebrew_launched.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps3-xmb-mod-now-have-individual-gameboots-for-each-emulator-system-homebrew-launched.33240/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[PS3_XMB_MOD]_Now_have_Individual_Gameboots_for_each_emulator__system__homebrew_launched.jpg">If you have an exploited PS3 and have been following some of the progress that@DeViL303has made with XMB modding ,then you already know about some of these great project's the xmb mod developer has been working on lately. For those of you new to his work, some recent mods from DeViL303 includeUltimate ToolboxandPixel Art possibilitiesand many more from the past .  Now the developer has taken on enhancing the Gameboot animation when launching content from the PS3's XMB.  Having the same boring sequence for all your content simply won't cut it anymore. Now withwebMAN MODhelping fuel the concept we now have the abilityto set individual Gameboots per contentsuch as bringing back those iconic start-ups from the PS1 and PS2 or having the system startups for your favorite retro roms. Well now you have that ability and more with the latest release from@DeViL303and the latest update to webMAN MOD from@aldostoolsthat helps power the concept the two have been working on the past several weeks seen here in the psx-place forums (here)​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T19:18:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>tonyhax - A Software backup loader exploit for the PS1 (leverages save game exploit)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/tonyhax_-_A_Software_backup_loader_exploit_for_the_PS1_(leverages_save_game_exploit).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/tonyhax-a-software-backup-loader-exploit-for-the-ps1-leverages-save-game-exploit.33236/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/tonyhax_-_A_Software_backup_loader_exploit_for_the_PS1_(leverages_save_game_exploit).jpg">Looks like those Classic PlayStation Consoles are still making waves in the homebrew scene. We have seen vibrant development on the PS2 with just recent things likeOpenTunaand also recentMechaCon Firmware dumpedwhich can potentially bring various possibilities discussedhere. However the PS2 is not alone as its daddy the original OG the PlayStation 1 now has a Software Backup Loader Exploit that leverages saves game exploits from Tony Hawk Pro Skater 2 & 3 from developersocram8888. The developer has titled the project "tonyhax" and will work with both the PAL and NTSC versions of the gameThe developer has provided a technical write up and easy to follow explanation as well as a YouTube video we have also attached below. Checkout the latest exploit to hit the PS1.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-3-12T17:45:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>IRISMAN v4.87.1:   Adds support for mounting Compressed ISO's ( ZIP, RAR or 7-Zip)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_v4.87.1___Adds_support_for_mounting_Compressed_ISO's_(_ZIP,_RAR_or_7-Zip).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/irisman-v4-87-1-adds-support-for-mounting-compressed-isos-zip-rar-or-7-zip.33210/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/IRISMAN_v4.87.1___Adds_support_for_mounting_Compressed_ISO's_(_ZIP,_RAR_or_7-Zip).jpg">Following some of the recent advancements made towebMAN MOD,  PlayStation 3 Homebrew developer@aldostoolshas now looked to incorporate a new feature in the PS3 Homebrew(CFW/PS3HEN) fbackup manager known asIRISMAN. It's currently a new and experimental feature added in the recent release ofv4.87.1that provides the backup manager the ability tomount compressed ISO in .zip / .7z / .rar formats.  This features supports thePS3's Internal HDD or a FAT32 external storage device for PS1 / PSP / PS2 / PS3/ DVD / BluRay ISO's..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-19T21:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Another new/old Exploit for the PS2! OpenTuna!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Another_newold_Exploit_for_the_PS2!_OpenTuna!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/another-new-old-exploit-for-the-ps2-opentuna.32893/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Another_newold_Exploit_for_the_PS2!_OpenTuna!.jpg">The year is 2021 and the PlayStation 2 Hacking Scene is still alive and kicking very well and we have a new/old Exploit for our PS2 to share!Even with later generations of PlayStation Console like the PS3 / PS4 / PS5 / PS Vita around, the PS2 is still thriving in the development / homebrew community, while serving a great audience for the console. We have seen the progression of several major projects and exploits in the past year for the PlayStation 2 (PS2) like the updates toOpen PS2 Loader  (OPL)to version 1.0.0 andFreeDVDBootexploit.We now have"OpenTuna", brought to you by@alexparrado!OpenTunaIt is an open source version of another recent exploit found and developed back in late 2019 for the PS2 called theFortuna exploit. Additional details about this newly open-source variant of the Fortuna project and what it could mean for the PS2 community can be found in the information provided below:​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-18T13:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Tools (Library w/ Unity Support) updated with "huge update" by The Darkprogrammer</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Tools_(Library_w_Unity_Support)_updated_with_huge_update_by_The_Darkprogrammer.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-tools-library-w-unity-support-updated-with-huge-update-by-the-darkprogrammer.32904/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Tools_(Library_w_Unity_Support)_updated_with_huge_update_by_The_Darkprogrammer.jpg">Alongside of the recent release ofPS4 Trophy UnlockerPS4 developer@The Darkprogrameralso had a big update forPS4 Tools, a Open Source suite of tools in all-in-one library. Various projects have utilized this library in their projects likePS4's PS2 Classic GUI,PS4 PKG Tool, ,PS4 Xploreralong with various other tools (listed below). but the dev is back with new updates for developer;s who may want to use this library that supports Unity development.  In this "huge update" from@The Darkprogramerdevs now have the ability to use the recently releasedTrophy Unlockerand other Recovery Tools in their projects. Not really an end-user release but useful for developer;s who especially have used Unity in creation of their projects. The DarkProgrammer has a homebrew he hopes to release very soon also utilizing this library. .​</description>
			<creators>The Darkprogramer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-18T13:54:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>PS4 Trophy Unlocker v1.0 by The Darkprogramer</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Trophy_Unlocker_v1.0_by_The_Darkprogramer.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/ps4-trophy-unlocker-v1-0-by-the-darkprogramer.32970/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/PS4_Trophy_Unlocker_v1.0_by_The_Darkprogramer.jpg">PlayStation 4 (PS4) developer@The Darkprogramerhas released a new project for the community calledPS4 TrophyUnlocker.  There is a PC utility that will unlock the trophies using a new method that relies on the game files itself to achieve, It will create a new pkg of the game installation, so if you have it installed already, be aware some files could potentially get lost if your have to overwrite your game. So be aware of that going in also this project isstill in the BETA stage, (v1.0 Released) so expect some bugs and different results depending on the game's trophies your unlocking. if you do experiance an error report it to the developer directly or in the comments below.. Also take note of the another recent release by this developer for developer with theupdate toPS4 Tools​</description>
			<creators>The Darkprogramer</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-17T08:23:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>[Update v1.6] Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas now playable on the PS Vita / PSTV with new port</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.6]_Grand_Theft_Auto_San_Andreas_now_playable_on_the_PS_Vita__PSTV_with_new_port.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/update-v1-6-grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-now-playable-on-the-ps-vita-pstv-with-new-port.32975/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/[Update_v1.6]_Grand_Theft_Auto_San_Andreas_now_playable_on_the_PS_Vita__PSTV_with_new_port.jpg">UPDATE v1.6 Released:Another great release for the PS Vita community arrives today.. As many of you already know in recent daysGrand Theft Auto: III(updated to v1.3)& also just the other dayGrand Theft Auto: Vice Citywas ported by the PS Vita / PS TV from@Rinnegatamante/ @Theflow0,Now these devsTheflow/ Rinnegatamante&aapall had a role in development ofGrand Theft Auto:San Andreasto the PS Vita(& PSTV) ,where theflow states on release"We gave the PS Vita THE game it always deserved. GTA: SA with authentic PS2 atmosphere on-the-go" .Unlike the previous two vita ports in the GTA Series that used a reversed-engineered engine, GTA:SA-Vita is using the mobile version (apk-android)) of the game and adding a "wrapper", like what we saw inMax Paynevita Port recently released utilizing thekubridge.skprx. The wrapper/port contains many custom hooks and patches to get the game running well on the PS Vita. You will need to provide the Game FIles yourself, the game can be purchased on the Play Store.Also developer Rinnegatamante has provided a configuration app to configure various settings, easily.  Also, as usualMVG. has a great video, as the dev/youtuber is covering this release as he was one of the tester's,  that is for sure worth checking out for some additional insight.. .​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-16T19:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>webMAN MOD 1.47.34 - New  XMB / Startup enhancements from Aldostools in this update.</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.34_-_New__XMB__Startup_enhancements_from_Aldostools_in_this_update..jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/webman-mod-1-47-34-new-xmb-startup-enhancements-from-aldostools-in-this-update.32860/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/webMAN_MOD_1.47.34_-_New__XMB__Startup_enhancements_from_Aldostools_in_this_update..jpg">DeveloperAldostools, a great developer in the PS3 Community continues the evolution of a tiny but powerful plugin that runs in the background of your CFW or HEN exploited systems that is capable of running background plugins (sprx).  Of course the plugin of mention iswebMAN MOD. This plugin contains alot of functionality alot and can give your exploited console a variety of new features & abilities (see readme tab)., In the latest updates to webMAN MOD the dev has turned his attention to XMB customization adding some functionality that gives user's some new creativity on your PS3's UI (or better known as its XMB), We recently seen the efforts inPixel Artby Aldostools and developer@DeViL303but now with this latest update to wMM we have some additional features for XMB customization.​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-16T10:46:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Pixel Art w/ custom imagefont.bin (By DeViL303) for XMB & Pixel Art Editor (by Aldostools)</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Pixel_Art_w_custom_imagefont.bin_(By_DeViL303)_for_XMB_&_Pixel_Art_Editor_(by_Aldostools).jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/pixel-art-w-custom-imagefont-bin-by-devil303-for-xmb-pixel-art-editor-by-aldostools.32861/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Pixel_Art_w_custom_imagefont.bin_(By_DeViL303)_for_XMB_&_Pixel_Art_Editor_(by_Aldostools).jpg">If you follow thePSX-Place Twitter Feed, you may of seen some tweets last week about this project already. The undisputed king of XMB Modding for the PS3@DeViL303,has been making various discoveries and implementing those various idea's as he investigates the inner workings of the XMB and the PS3's User Interface. Along those adventures the developer has discovered a clever way for displaying lines and shapes around text to highlight(see example below)them then aldostool had the idea forPixel Arton the PS3 XMB,  The idea has progressed as developer@aldostoolshas created a new editor for creation of some pixel-art for the PS3(and progressed the tool already with a few updates).Checkout additional details about this latest discovery and trick for your XMB customization. This should open the door to some new eye candy for the XMB like in the coldboot and other entries on the XMB such as titles and other area's were text is displayed with manipulation of the font files..​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-14T10:27:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>reVC-vita (GTA: Vice City) port for PS Vita  /  PSTV by @theflow0  & @Rinnegatamante Released</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/reVC-vita_(GTA_Vice_City)_port_for_PS_Vita____PSTV_by_@theflow0__&_@Rinnegatamante_Released.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/revc-vita-gta-vice-city-port-for-ps-vita-pstv-by-theflow0-rinnegatamante-released.32928/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/reVC-vita_(GTA_Vice_City)_port_for_PS_Vita____PSTV_by_@theflow0__&_@Rinnegatamante_Released.jpg">The PS Vita / PlayStation TV devices are getting another great release for the Vita Homebrew Scene. Iconic developer's in the Vita Community who have done so much for the platform in@Rinnegatamanteand developer@TheFlow, have continued on another great project in a follow-up toreIII-Vita (A port of GTA III to the PS Vita).The devs have now successfully ported anotherGrand Theft Autoclassic in the series & are now ready for release as they dropreVC-Vita - A Port of Grand Theft Auto: Vice Cityto the Vita Community.reVC-Vitais a fully reversed - reimplementation ofGTA: Vice City using thelibrw engine(a full and open source version of RenderWare Graphic Engine),like we seen used inre3-Vita. In order to play this release you need to own a copy of the PC Game (can be purchased on Steam) and move needed game fiies, additional information can be viewed in the installation notes​</description>
			<creators>STLcardsWS</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-2-6T10:08:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 08) - Our Guest Today: "well-known multiconsole Developer @CelesteBlue123"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._08)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well-known_multiconsole_Developer_@CelesteBlue123.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-08-our-guest-today-well-known-multiconsole-developer-celesteblue123.30581/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._08)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well-known_multiconsole_Developer_@CelesteBlue123.jpg">Since you liked ourpast Interviews so farwhere we talk withDevelopers across all PlayStation consoles- and especiallyone of our latest Interviewwhere wetalked with a Developer who tinkers with various consoles simultaneously- we thought about to do this again. Today's Guest is alsowell-known for releasing various Homebrew Applicationsmainly for thePlayStation Vita, but also for thePlayStation 4. In fact in this interview, you will learn not only what he released so far for both consoles, but alsowhat it means to develop for the PS Vita as for the PS4 in terms of "connectivity" for both consoles. But what does this mean exactly? Maybe you can remember back when the PS4 got presented back at E3 2013,Sony itself tried to make it more tasty for you not only to play with their newest Home Console, but also with the previous released PS Vita as well, especially when using the official "Remote Play" Feature. While this didn't worked quite well for Sony to be honest -although even the newest PS4 Games today still supports "Remote Play"- this Developer took a similar approachto understand the "connectivity" between both consoles but in terms of hacking them and to create useful Homebrew for it. And his results are impressive as well. So without further ado,our Guest Today is well-known multiconsole Developer@CelesteBlue.​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-29T14:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Max Payne Mobile Ported to PS Vita / PS TV</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Max_Payne_Mobile_Ported_to_PS_Vita__PS_TV.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/max-payne-mobile-ported-to-ps-vita-ps-tv.32752/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Max_Payne_Mobile_Ported_to_PS_Vita__PS_TV.jpg">While the Vita scene patiently awaits the arrival of the nextGrand Theft Autoports rumored to be released soon, we have a surprise release coming fromfgsfdsandTheFloW. Today, the mobile version ofMax Paynehas been ported to the PS Vita / PS TV. Thanks to the recent release of TheFloW'skubridge, developers are able to bypass dynamic recompilation limits that had been previously set in place. You can take a look at the full list of credits in our dedicated resource thread (linked below) to see all the developers who helped in bringing this game to the PS Vita / PS TV.Similar to other ports,in order to enjoy Max Payne Mobile on your PS Vita / PS TV, you will need to obtain the legitimate assets from your own copy of the game. You will find detailed instructions on how​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-23T10:50:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>The Power Supply (Vol. 07) - Our Guest Today: "well known multi-console Developer @mathieulh"</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._07)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well_known_multi-console_Developer_@mathieulh.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/the-power-supply-vol-07-our-guest-today-well-known-multi-console-developer-mathieulh.28915/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/The_Power_Supply_(Vol._07)_-_Our_Guest_Today_well_known_multi-console_Developer_@mathieulh.jpg">OurInterview Seriesconducted various Interviews with Developers, who worked either mainly for the PlayStation 3 or for the PlayStation 4 (andone time for the PlayStation Vita). But sometimes, there are well-known Developers who say to themselves thatworking on one console isn't enough for me. In fact the older readers will probably remember back when the magical 3.55 Firmware got hacked for the PS3 how many useful stuff we saw from the PSP Development for instance,which led into daily new releases and achievements for both consoles. As you can see, working on several consoles within the same "family" can be an advantage. So when we thought about new candidates for this series of interviews, we quickly recognized that if you want to interview a"multi-console" Developer, then there is someone, where his name will come immediately in every mind. In fact ournext candidate worked with so many both home and portable consoles in the past and still in present days, we would probaly need a complete new sub-section inside the forum to list all of his releases and achievements he did for the community.And you can't imagine how difficult it was for us "questioners" how to begin this interview with such a great person or how to find the right words for him. :P But somehow we think we managed it quite good and this time we have even aspecial question for our female readersout there. ^^ This man needs no more introduction.Here is our guest today, Developer@mathieulh!​</description>
			<creators>Roxanne</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-7T13:56:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>Dreamcast Emulation Comes to PS Vita and PS TV with flycast-vita</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dreamcast_Emulation_Comes_to_PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_with_flycast-vita.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/dreamcast-emulation-comes-to-ps-vita-and-ps-tv-with-flycast-vita.32450/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/Dreamcast_Emulation_Comes_to_PS_Vita_and_PS_TV_with_flycast-vita.jpg">Earlier this year, there were plans put into motion by@Rinnegatamanteto bringDreamcast emulation to the PlayStation Vita and PlayStation TV. Nowadays, the nameRinnegatamanteshould synonymous with Vita ports, as he is responsible for multiple major ports, all which come with a high level of polish. You will have to look no further than the work he andThe FlOwhave performed in bringingGrand Theft Auto IIInatively to the scene, and all the advancements that have been made since the initial release. Or, watch as the continually evolvingDaedalus X64(Nintendo 64 emulator) make leaps and bounds in allowing us to enjoy all of our favorite N64 games once again. Simply put, take a look at ourVita Homebrewsection of the forum to see all the hard work and amazing releasesRinnegatamantehas been providing for us.​</description>
			<creators>tthousand</creators>
		</mtrl>
		<mtrl id="0" lastm="2021-1-6T19:46:00.000Z" until="2100-12-31T23:59:00.000Z">
			<desc>OPL (Open PS2 Loader) version 1.0 Released !!!</desc>
			<url type="2">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OPL_(Open_PS2_Loader)_version_1.0_Released_!!!.jpg</url>
			<target type="u">https://www.psx-place.com/threads/opl-open-ps2-loader-version-1-0-released.32442/</target>
			<cntry agelmt="0">all</cntry>			<lang>all</lang>
			<description><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PS3-Pro/PSX-Place/master/resources/images/uncompressed/OPL_(Open_PS2_Loader)_version_1.0_Released_!!!.jpg">It is here! Open PS2 Loader ("OPL") 1.0.0!After more than a decade (November 2008) of continuous development and a bit more than5 years since the last official stable release-build(0.9.3 in December 2015),OPL 1.0.0 has been officially released!​</description>
			<creators>TnA</creators>
		</mtrl>
	</spc>
</nsx>